<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advent-of-Code on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/advent-of-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advent-of-Code on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:15:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/advent-of-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some more fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Scala3 is here.&#xA;In my earlier post I saw some weird performance differences between Scala2 and Scala3 (RC3) and felt (obviously) compelled to run the benchmark again against 3.0.0.&#xA;And &amp;hellip; big surprise: Everything is back to normal. Scala3 is as fast as Scala2.&#xA;The big differences come from very small numbers (e.g. Day13). The biggest (reproducible) differences is on Day3(part1): 112 msecs vs. 255 msecs. If I am getting really bored one day I might take a look at it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Note: Look here for 3.0 benchmark numbers&#xA;The release of Scala3 is imminent.&#xA;In April I ported/migrated nmesos from Scala2 to Scala3 and I just did a quick benchmark to see what Scala3 is doing to my Advent-of-Code implementation from 2017.&#xA;Initially I was wondering (and maybe a little bit afraid) how difficult migrating to Scala3 will be (and what problems I will be running into).&#xA;The good news is that migrating to Scala3 is not difficult at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &#43; Beam = Hamler (III)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/01/haskell--beam-hamler-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/01/haskell--beam-hamler-iii/</guid>
      <description>Here comes part III of the Hamler blog post series &amp;hellip;&#xA;One of the observations was that for/on Day21 hamler ~6000 times slower than haskell, where in general we where able to see that it was 5-20 times slower.&#xA;Just looked into this a little bit and there is good news and bad news. The good news is I found something.&#xA;I can make the hamer solution run 10 times faster by changing the implementation of part1 from &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &#43; Beam = Hamler (II)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/01/18/haskell--beam-hamler-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/01/18/haskell--beam-hamler-ii/</guid>
      <description>Here comes part II of the Hamler blog post series &amp;hellip;&#xA;For this year&amp;rsquo;s Advent-of-Code I wanted to take a look at Hamler.&#xA;I just finished implementing all of the part-1 solutions in Hamler.&#xA;I had to skip Day 20 (the seamonster), because Hamler only supports a very small/limited number of packages, which means I would have needed to write a lot of code before I would have been able to tackle the actual problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &#43; Beam = Hamler (I)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/12/15/haskell--beam-hamler-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/12/15/haskell--beam-hamler-i/</guid>
      <description>Hamler Blog Post Series &amp;hellip;&#xA;Hamler (I) - First week (this post) Hamler (II) - All solutions for part 1 (in Hamler and Haskell) Hamler (III) - Making Day21 10 times faster What&amp;rsquo;s at the intersection of Haskell, the Erlang Beam/OTP and the Advent-of-Code?&#xA;Yes, right: Hamler!&#xA;Hamler is a Haskell-like language that runs on the Erlang Beam/OTP.&#xA;At Community we are big Beam/OTP fans (because we like highly-scalable and highly-available shared nothing micro-services systems).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code ... Final cut (... and First cut :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/11/30/advent-of-code-...-final-cut-...-and-first-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/11/30/advent-of-code-...-final-cut-...-and-first-cut/</guid>
      <description>Today Advent of Code 2018 started again (at 05:00am (GMT))!!!&#xA;And &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; just in time &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; today I am also wrapping up Advent of Code 2017!!!&#xA;My first implementation was (obviously) in Scala.&#xA;And that one alone was interesting, because I also used ScalaCheck for property-based testing and ScalaMeter to implement performance tests for all solutions.&#xA;I then made the Scala code cross-compile with ScalaNative.&#xA;At the time I was also learning Kotlin and spend some cycles to port the code to Kotlin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2017 ... Revolutions!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/advent-of-code-2017-...-revolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/advent-of-code-2017-...-revolutions/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the Advent of Code &amp;hellip; again!!!&#xA;Last time we talked about a/the Scala implementation.&#xA;This time around I figured that I need to understand what the hype about Kotlin is all about and decided to port my Scala solutions to Kotlin.&#xA;There is a separate blog post on what I think about Kotlin, but overall it was a positive experience. I like Kotlin (but would not suggest/recommend it as a replacement for Scala).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2017 ... Reloaded!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/05/24/advent-of-code-2017-...-reloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/05/24/advent-of-code-2017-...-reloaded/</guid>
      <description>OK &amp;hellip; it took me a while, but &amp;hellip; hopefully it was worth it!!!&#xA;Last year at christmas I did the Advent of Code and &amp;hellip; really liked it!!!&#xA;If you do not know it, it is a series (25 of them) of code puzzles that need to be solved to unlock a/the christmas tree (every day (between Dec. 1st and Dec. 25th) a new/the next puzzle becomes available).&#xA;The puzzles do a lot of different things and will test your ability to come up with good/clever datastructures/algorithms.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
