<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 16:11:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Using TimeMachine Part II or Why Restore was greyed out?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/09/12/effective-mac-using-timemachine-part-ii-or-why-restore-was-greyed-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/09/12/effective-mac-using-timemachine-part-ii-or-why-restore-was-greyed-out/</guid>
      <description>It happened again!!! Another HD crash. A year ago I lost my original 160GB drive and replaced it with a 250GB drive. Now this one failed only 12 month later. I am not sure what is happening here, but I do not feel that I &#34;mishandle&#34; my MacBook in a way that would explain this rate of failure. Let me know, what your experience is. Are MacBooks DiskEaters?&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Anyway ... in any case I had a chance to see, if my new backup strategy is better than my old one. You might remember (or not :)) that last year I found out that you have to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/Blog/2008/09/effective-mac-using-time-maschine.html&#34;&gt;use TimeMachine the &#34;right way&#34;&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to have a pleasant restore experience.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This time around I booted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?path=Mac/10.5/en/15638.html&#34;&gt;the Installation CD, went to Utilities and selected &#34;Restore System from Backup ...&#34;&lt;/a&gt;. Imagine my surprise when I was confronted with a selection of snapshots until 2 month ago (and I was sure that the last backup was from Sep., 03rd), but I figured &#34;Hey, better *something* from mid of May than nothing and maybe I can restore more files using the TimeMachine application after the initial restore&#34; and of we go ...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;6 hours later my system is restored and I start the TimeMachine application and surprise (again :)) I can see all me backups until Sep., 03rd, but all backups between mid of May and Sep., 03rd are greyed out (including the Restore button). Weird and frustrating. What the hell did I do to make all of these backups &#34;un-restoreable&#34;?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;After an hour of investigation I found the problem: Mid of may I renamed the disk in the MacBook from &#34;Macintosh HD&#34; to &#34;Roland&#39;s HD&#34;. Trivial, simple change, nothing to think about, nothing to worry about and TimeMachine continues to back up as normal, but will create a new backup set with the new volume name.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What is not really immediately obvious is that you can restore from various backup sets, when you run &#34;Restore System from Backup ...&#34;. After you have selected the disk to restore from, there is a drop-down box at the top of the screen, that will allow you to select a backup set (in case you have more than one on the disk) and the next screen will then display all snapshots in that set, means the solution to my problem was to select the &#34;Roland&#39;s HD&#34; set and voila ... suddenly the snapshots between mid of May and Sep., 03rd are displayed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;After another 6 hours I was in pretty good shape and I now like TimeMachine even more than before.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;BTW, ... if you are in Dublin and need help with your Mac I recommend the guys from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themacshop.ie/&#34;&gt;MacShop&lt;/a&gt; at Merrion Square. Good, competent, fast. This is how it should be.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Make the Mac listen ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/05/18/effective-mac-make-the-mac-listen-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/05/18/effective-mac-make-the-mac-listen-.../</guid>
      <description>This morning I was using my new &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2007/biz2/0709/gallery.favorites_tools.biz2/index.html&#34;&gt;JawBone&lt;/a&gt; Bluetooth headset to make a Skype call. The quality was bad and therefore I decided to switch to my headset. The result was better, but still not what I was looking for. At the end I took the time to really understand, where the sound is coming from and to my big surprise I found out that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.macrumors.com/showthread.php?t=342539&#34;&gt;line-in jack is not working with normal headsets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;On the Mac you need a mic (or a headset) with &#34;power&#34; (e.g. a USB mic or a pre-amp mic). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Conclusion: I have stored away my headset and will use the built-in speaker/built-in mic to make calls. In case I need privacy I will just plug in my iPhone earbuds. That sounds like a/the winning configuration. But that also means that I do not have a solution for environments with a lot of background noise. Maybe I need to go back and need to find out why the quality with the JawBone was bad in the first place.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Sleeping on the plane</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/10/effective-mac-sleeping-on-the-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/10/effective-mac-sleeping-on-the-plane/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, I &#34;borrowed&#34; the battery from Christina&#39;s MacBook to extend my &#34;life&#34;, while I am on the plane. The Mac (being the Mac) has a nice feature, which will hibernate the machine when the battery gets low. This allows you to change the battery without rebooting.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was looking for a way to hibernate the machine on demand. This is also useful if you want to conserve battery power (e.g. while one a plane). The sleep mode is a drain on the battery, because the RAM needs to be kept alive/refreshed. This is especially a problem, if you have a lot of RAM.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Found the following &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kaputtendorf.de/2007/08/17/hibernation-tool-for-mac-os/&#34;&gt;applescript&lt;/a&gt;. Seems useful.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Using OpenOffice, NeoOffice and/or iWorks08</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/04/effective-mac-using-openoffice-neooffice-and/or-iworks08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/04/effective-mac-using-openoffice-neooffice-and/or-iworks08/</guid>
      <description>Finally! OpenOffice is now available for the Mac. In the last two month I used OpenOffice 3.0, NeoOffice 2.2.5 and iWorks08 in parallel (with a special focus on the presentation functionality).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The result is surprising (and maybe not :)). If you use the &#34;native&#34; formats (e.g. ODF, .key/.page) everything works fine. Obviously things get more interesting, if you want to use these tools to read and write MS-Office files (.ppt/.doc/.xls) or even MS-Office 2007 files (.pptx, etc.).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In this case it is my experience that you (still) have to limit yourself to a (non-obvious) subset of the functionality to make sure you can import/export your files to/from MS-Office. Especially for Powerpoint 2007 files I currently have to use all three tools and see, which tool will give me the best result, when I import .pptx files. In some cases entire slides show up blank. In other cases they are &#34;reformated&#34; in a way that makes them unreadable.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Buttom line: It seems that for the time being, neither OpenOffice nor NeoOffice is a solution on its own, when it comes to importing/exporting to/from MS-Office. But that may change in the future.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Using Time Maschine</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/30/effective-mac-using-time-maschine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/30/effective-mac-using-time-maschine/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday at 08:00am it happend to me. I move/dragged an email into a folder on my Mac and the machine froze. Diagnosis: Catastrophic harddisk failure. &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But hey ... look at the bright side: I got to replace my 160GB disk with a bigger 250GB disk and got to test, if my Time Machine backup really works.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And there is where the problem starts. In an ill-conceived effort to minimize the disk space and the time I need for my backup, I excluded all directories besides my &#34;User&#34; directory. This will allow you to recover single files (and/or mails, photos, etc.), but will make it very hard to recover a machine, since Time Machine (when you run the app) cannot restore all data from a given date.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The better/only way to do it, is to backup everything (including all apps, system folders, libraries) and just exclude a folder (e.g. the download folder), which has recoverable (fast changing, big, volatile) data in it (e.g. my iTunes Library). Basically reverse my backup strategy. This will create Time Machine backups, which include a snapshot of the entire system (including the operating system).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These backups can then be used with the &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://newsgroups.derkeiler.com/Archive/Uk/uk.comp.sys.mac/2008-01/msg02463.html&#34;&gt;migration assistant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to restore the machine with the last backup or even better you boot from the install DVD and use the &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macobserver.com/article/2008/01/28.15.shtml&#34;&gt;restore from Time Machine utility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to restore to a backup of your choice.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I can tell you, restoring a system file by file is tedious :).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Open-Source Mac</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/10/effective-mac-open-source-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/10/effective-mac-open-source-mac/</guid>
      <description>Was looking for an opensource search engine for the Mac and found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensourcemac.org/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; interesting website. I am already using half of the apps, but will take a look at the other half too :).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Growl back to work</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/07/effective-mac-growl-back-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/07/effective-mac-growl-back-to-work/</guid>
      <description>Stumbled over James&#39;s blog entry about &lt;a href=&#34;http://macstrac.blogspot.com/2007/07/my-favourite-os-x-software.html&#34;&gt;useful software for the Mac &lt;/a&gt;and added &lt;a href=&#34;http://growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; to my list of software that you need have/use to be effective, but was not able to make it work with X-Chat (AquaChat). Confronted with the option to figure out what is wrong or to try something new, I took the easy way out: I tried Colloquy. This worked out of the box. I know need to find out how to make my Twitter tweeds show up in Growl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - call me slow</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/12/effective-mac-call-me-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/12/effective-mac-call-me-slow/</guid>
      <description>You can call me slow, but it took me only a year to find the RSS reader that everybody else is using. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davidgreco.it&#34;&gt;David Greco&lt;/a&gt; finally pointed me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsgator.com/Individuals/NetNewsWire/&#34;&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt;. This seems to be it :).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - the beginning of a journey</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/effective-mac-the-beginning-of-a-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/effective-mac-the-beginning-of-a-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;yesterday i finally finished my upgrade to Mac OS X 10.5 (Leopard).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;overall it went well. i did an erase and install (as a 20 year windows user i feel much more comfortable with clean installs. maybe next time if will try it the mac-way :)) and also used the exercise to clean up my disk and the way i work. the biggest problem was that leopard does not come with iLife, means you need to find your old tiger CDs and reinstall iLife from there (or buy (!?!?) iLife 08, no comment).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;using a mac is like using any other tool. just using it is not going to give you the maximum ROI. using it effectively is going to make the difference.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;therefore i decided to start a little series of blogs and i am going to call it &#34;Effective Mac&#34;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;this is the first one and i just want to give a summary of tools that i am using on my mac. please feel free to comment and add to this list.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;mail - looked at a couple of options, but for the time being will stick with mail.app. using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/downloads/macosx/email_chat/yai.html&#34;&gt;YAI&lt;/a&gt; to deal with exchange invitations and will probably checkout &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indev.ca/MailTags.html&#34;&gt;MailTags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;calendar and contacts - have not looked around and will stick with iCal and AdressBook.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;todos - did look at the functionality in iCal and did not really like it. did a little bit of research and finally settled for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igtd.pl/&#34;&gt;iGTD&lt;/a&gt; (get things done).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;browser - currently using safari and occasionally firefox (especially, if i am in london heathrow airport. the safari browser cannot get me onto the bingo wifi network there). also looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flock.com&#34;&gt;Flock&lt;/a&gt; to get a grip on my social networking (xing, linked-in, pulse, facebook - it is madness).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;RSS reader - looked at safari (and a couple of other browsers) and the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acrylicapps.com/&#34;&gt;TimesReader&lt;/a&gt; (looks very good. almost like a newspaper), but settled for the new RSS reader in mail.app.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;communication - using iChat (AIM), Skype, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/xchataqua/&#34;&gt;Aqua X-Chat&lt;/a&gt; (IRC) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific&#34;&gt;Twitterific&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://macstrac.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; also pointed me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtwit.com/&#34;&gt;GTwit&lt;/a&gt;, but i still need to makeup mind, if and how i am going to use it). tried to find a universal &#34;chat&#34; client. stumbled over &lt;a href=&#34;http://fire.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Fire&lt;/a&gt;, but it does not support SSL enabled IRC server (and keeps on crashing on me).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;programming - still like my emacs :). using &lt;a href=&#34;http://aquamacs.org/&#34;&gt;Aqua-Emacs&lt;/a&gt;, but have also started to use Dashcode for my web developement.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;brainstorming - using &lt;a href=&#34;http://freemind.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Freemind&lt;/a&gt; for my mindmaps and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnioutliner/&#34;&gt;OmniOutliner&lt;/a&gt; for structured bullet list type brainstorming.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;let me know, what you think about the toolset. anything missing? anything that could/should be replaced by a better tool?&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
