<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TEDN on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/tedn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TEDN on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/tedn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDN.LIFE Podcast - Trutzbox</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/08/23/tedn.life-podcast-trutzbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/08/23/tedn.life-podcast-trutzbox/</guid>
      <description>WARNING: This content is in German :) &amp;hellip;
 Willkommen zum TEDN.LIFE Podcast.
Ich wollte schon immer mal ausprobieren wie man so was macht/produziert.
Da trifft es sich gut das ich ueber die letzten Wochen und Monate ein paar super-interessante Gesprache mit meinem Freund Hermann (Sauer) hatte.
Er ist Geschäftsführer und Gründer bei Comidio und Erfinder der Trutzbox.
Hermann und ich kennen uns jetzt seit mehr als 30 Jahren und haben eine Podcast-Serie produziert um zu diskutieren wie man sich heutzutage zeitgemaess davor schuetzen kann das die eigenen Daten ungefiltert dem Internet zur Verfuegung gestellt werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The TEDN Van</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/14/the-tedn-van/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/14/the-tedn-van/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again: There is good news and bad news!!!
The good news is that the TEDN Mobile Office project is making good progress!
By now we (means mainly my dad :)) have &amp;hellip;
 put in a screen installed an external 230V power plug (so that I can get power on/from a camp-ground) installed a fridge and a sink and a cooker (basically a kitchen) tested the tent (see below) installed a roof box (to store the tent) got ourselves a foldable e-bike  &amp;hellip; means: we are ready to rock and roll!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the WLAN ... the dark arts of extreme digital nomading</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/10/assessing-the-wlan-...-the-dark-arts-of-extreme-digital-nomading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/10/assessing-the-wlan-...-the-dark-arts-of-extreme-digital-nomading/</guid>
      <description>When you work from anywhere (or even from home) it is YOUR(!!!) responsibility to ensure that you are connected!!!
Statements like &amp;hellip;
 &amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;hellip; I cannot join the standup, because I was not able to find a WLAN hotspot.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Can you hear me? Sorry &amp;hellip; I am on a shitty/weak WLAN.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;hellip; can we switch off the video. There is too much lag.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip; are just not good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing Remote ... the book!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/07/discussing-remote-...-the-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/07/discussing-remote-...-the-book/</guid>
      <description>These days people look for advice and insight into how to build and run a remote-first engineering organization. And want/need to learn fast!!!
One good resource is (obviously) Remote (kind of the bible on working remote).
The book was published in 2013 (and was probably written in the 12 month before that).
Obviously the key messages/statements from the book are still true (or truer than ever), but I think that since then things have also changed and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDN - The most important tool ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; is the laptop? No (but more on this later)!
&amp;hellip; is the mobile phone (with good 4G coverage)? No (and again &amp;hellip; more on this later)!
&amp;hellip; is a foldable coffee mug!!!
 When you start to work remote (from home, from any place, &amp;hellip;) you will discover that you will end up in coffee shops (either because you want to (because you want/need to fight the cabin fever) or because you have to (because you want/need to find/have a WLAN connection)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extreme Digital Nomad (TEDN)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/03/31/the-extreme-digital-nomad-tedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/03/31/the-extreme-digital-nomad-tedn/</guid>
      <description>In the last 25 years I have build and run multiple distributed software engineering organisations.
My management style/philosophy is based on a couple of core believes &amp;hellip;
 The Power of Why - I like to lead with Why (to make sure Talent and Passion can meet a Purpose) People first - I always think and feel that people are the solution (not the problem) Heterogenerity for the win - You have to be different to complement each other (and to create innovation) No surprises - Everybody (at all times) should be clear on what is happening and why it is happening, which leads to &amp;hellip; Building and maintain trust (and respect) (between the people) at all cost!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 4th of July!!! Or ... how to take advantage of an opportuunity!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/07/10/happy-4th-of-july-or-...-how-to-take-advantage-of-an-opportuunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/07/10/happy-4th-of-july-or-...-how-to-take-advantage-of-an-opportuunity/</guid>
      <description>A long weekend in San Francisco (Jul., 4th - Independence Day), great weather and nothing to do?
I smell opportunity! Opportunity to do something that I always wanted to do: Explore the bay area on a motor bike.
The Nitro CEO was kind enough to introduce me to Wolfgang and Wolfgang and his team helped me to get my hands on a BMW R1200 RT and off we go.
Motorcycling in San Francisco (SF) can be tricky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>