<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 12:10:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Huffman Trees/Codes - Why are they different?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/11/19/huffman-trees/codes-why-are-they-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/11/19/huffman-trees/codes-why-are-they-different/</guid>
      <description>Right now I am solving the 99-scala-problems. Again!!!&#xA;This time around I am using them to learn more about what it means to be an Augmented Software Engineer (ASE). Just subscribe to the podcast to follow along.&#xA;P50 is to build a Huffman tree and to return the set of Huffman codes for the given string.&#xA;codeium found a good implementation, but struggled to find tests that worked.&#xA;I then tried various websites ([1], [2], [3], [4]) to test various strings and noticed that the trees and the resulting set of codes are different between the implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Augmented Software Engineer - What is it?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>Updated &amp;hellip;&#xA;2024-11-08: Added section at the end on published and planned episodes 2024-11-19: Added episode 3-5&#xA;I can hear you loud and clear &amp;hellip;&#xA;Ooohhh my god: Not another blog post about AI!!!&#xA;Bear with me. I will try to make reading it (or watching it) worth while your time. I promise.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s set the stage. My opinion is &amp;hellip;&#xA;The planet has problems (over-population, climate-change, poverty and economic inequality, cancer and alzheimer, &amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon and Emacs - The Restart</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/07/05/mastodon-and-emacs-the-restart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/07/05/mastodon-and-emacs-the-restart/</guid>
      <description>Ok &amp;hellip; I admit it! I am using emacs! A lot!&#xA;I am also using emacs to do my tooting.&#xA;Means I am using mastodon.el.&#xA;The other day I had to reset/reinstall my emacs configuration and had to re-authenticate my mastodon server.&#xA;That proofed to be more challenging than I thought, because there is a screen missing. Let me explain &amp;hellip; or even better: Let me walk you through how you can reset the authentication, if/when you have to &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Note to myself - How to make ManxTelecom work</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/07/04/note-to-myself-how-to-make-manxtelecom-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/07/04/note-to-myself-how-to-make-manxtelecom-work/</guid>
      <description>Ok &amp;hellip; it is not a secret: I have been to the Isle of Man (IOM) once or twice (for the the TT and the Manx Grand-Prix).&#xA;And every 12 month I find myself in the same situation &amp;hellip;&#xA;I get myself a (free) pay-as-you-go ManxTelecom SIM card I get myself a 10 pound voucher and top-up the card with it (this gives me 10GB of data, which is plenty for 2 weeks) I cannot get the data connection to work The THING to remember (and the secret to success) is that you ALSO have to (manually) adjust your internet settings on your (Android) phone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IOM TT 2024 - History was made</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/06/01/iom-tt-2024-history-was-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/06/01/iom-tt-2024-history-was-made/</guid>
      <description>Ok, here comes an odd one &amp;hellip;&#xA;This one is not about software-technologies or software-engineering or software-craftmanship or management or leadership.&#xA;This is about another passion of mine: Motorbikes and motorbike racing. Specifically road-racing.&#xA;For those of you who know nothing about road-racing and want to learn and understand more I recommend to watch Road.&#xA;The exec summary is that all racing started on open, public roads. Later purpose build tracks started to emerge and are obviously the much safer option to conduct a race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Software Gardening Manifesto - A copy</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/07/01/the-software-gardening-manifesto-a-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/07/01/the-software-gardening-manifesto-a-copy/</guid>
      <description>In case the Software Gardening Manifesto is down or otherwise not available, here is a copy of it &amp;hellip;&#xA;SOFTWARE GARDENING MANIFESTO Software Gardeners are professionals who perceive software development in a different way. Our goal is to spread the word of our core values, be mentors for the new developers and create software that it is developed at the highest quality bar.&#xA;Every software gardener believes and embraces the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Blogging - The Art of Prompting</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/augmented-blogging-the-art-of-prompting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/augmented-blogging-the-art-of-prompting/</guid>
      <description>This is a landmark blog post. I just introduced a tag called Augmented-by-AI. And this post is tagged with it.&#xA;This is going to be the new normal. Let me explain &amp;hellip;&#xA;First things first: This blog post is not written by chatGPT.&#xA;It is Sunday morning, 6am and I am sitting here in my living room in my PJ with a cup of coffee and I am typing this. Believe me &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renault Zoe - STOP Electric Motor Failure</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/renault-zoe-stop-electric-motor-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/renault-zoe-stop-electric-motor-failure/</guid>
      <description>I used to have a Nissan Leaf (for 6 years) and now I have a Renault Zoe (for 2 years).&#xA;I was and I am very happy with these cars. I am very happy to drive electric cars. Point. Period.&#xA;What I like is to learn what it takes to drive an electric car. You need to learn a lot. About the car. About electricity. About batteries. About the (charging) infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pillars of a sustainable energy future - A fireside chat</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is interesting in more than one way, because &amp;hellip;&#xA;I am going to discuss a topic that is deer to my heart: What do we need to do to get to a better place with respect to a sustainable energy future? And I am going to use a new approach: Where I am first going to articulate my thoughts and then I am going to complement it with a fireside chat that I had with chatGPT about the topics at hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal Team Player - HHS vs. DAC</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/02/10/the-ideal-team-player-hhs-vs.-dac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/02/10/the-ideal-team-player-hhs-vs.-dac/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Lencioni (obviously) wrote The Five Dysfunctions of a Team.&#xA;In that book we learn that the five dysfunctions you need to avoid are &amp;hellip;&#xA;Absence of trust — unwilling to be vulnerable within the group Fear of conflict — seeking artificial harmony over constructive passionate debate Lack of commitment — feigning buy-in for group decisions creates ambiguity throughout the organization Avoidance of accountability — ducking the responsibility to call peers, superiors on counterproductive behavior which sets low standards Inattention to team results — focusing on personal success, status and ego before team success I always try to frame these in positive/actionable terms by asking people to help me to build teams that show/exhibit the following characteristics &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can we afford to be surprised? - &#34;Hot, hot, hot&#34;</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/01/14/can-we-afford-to-be-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/01/14/can-we-afford-to-be-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</guid>
      <description>6 years ago I wrote a blog post to express that my wife loves me for a lot of different reasons and that there is no reason to be surprised about the climate change that we are experiencing.&#xA;Note: If you do not know, why there is a picture of a microwave here, you need to read the first blog post.&#xA;I am compelled to write about it again.&#xA;Mainly because it did not get better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy new year - I am tooting now ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/01/01/happy-new-year-i-am-tooting-now-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/01/01/happy-new-year-i-am-tooting-now-.../</guid>
      <description>Happy new year to ya all!!!&#xA;What a year it has been. Some of the highlights are &amp;hellip;&#xA;In February I spend a week with the European Community Engineers in Lisbon/Portugal for the first (actually the second) EMEA tribe meeting after the pandemic In June I spend a week with Christina in London to deliver a talk on Micros-Services &amp;amp; Event-Based Systems In August I spend 3 weeks on the Isle Of Man to attend the Manx GP and (finally) got my TT Race Course Marshall certification In May I Went do the US for 3 weeks to attend the US east/west coast tribe meetings &amp;hellip; and had to isolate for 10 days because I got Covid (but got a good sunrise out of it) We continue to do Innovation-Weeks at Community :) &amp;hellip; I really enjoyed working as a Staff-Director here at Community (I get to do all (or at least a lot of) the good/interesting stuff) Installed a stove at home and bought one(solo) for the mobile office Spend a week in county Donegal (working remote) Spend a week in county Clare (working remote) using the most remote co-working space in Ireland Had two weeks of outstanding boating again (no remote working; just vacation :)) Doing (another) 100 day walking challenge Got a full-body check-up done (first after 6 years).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Pair Programming - Innovation-Week Q2/2022</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2022/05/01/emacs-pair-programming-innovation-week-q2/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2022/05/01/emacs-pair-programming-innovation-week-q2/2022/</guid>
      <description>We (at Community) just had another Innovation-Week. I was actually working on generating pact-files from frontend code and then generating openapi spec files from elxir backend code and then automatically check that the frontend pact is compatible with the backend openapi spec while running the build pipeline for the frontend(s)/backend.&#xA;But this is not what this blog post is all about :).&#xA;While working on this Geoff and myself also decided that it is a good opportunity to sharpen the tools and take remote-first pair-programming to the next level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/about/</guid>
      <description>Builder and runner of functional teams and functional systems&#xA;Explorer of extreme digital nomading and remote-first cultures&#xA;My name is Roland Tritsch. I am The Extreme Digital Nomad (TEDN). I am a Software Craftsman and I am applying my craft to building and maintaining beautiful Software Gardens. I am also a Manager. And a Husband and a Father. I like to make engineers grow and users smile. I like computer science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/social/</guid>
      <description>Find out &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; where I am working right now &amp;hellip; what I am tooting about &amp;hellip; what I am working on &amp;hellip; what I am looking at &amp;hellip; where I am working today </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting to RabbitMQ with AMQP in Elixir</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/10/26/reconnecting-to-rabbitmq-with-amqp-in-elixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/10/26/reconnecting-to-rabbitmq-with-amqp-in-elixir/</guid>
      <description>Updated (2022-01-01): Added stage.&#xA;At Community we are building a platform that will allow you to have meaningful conversations with large audiences &amp;hellip; at scale!!!&#xA;The architectural backbone is a shared-nothing micro-services architecture, that uses an event-bus for state propagation.&#xA;To avoid any kind of 2-phase-commit shenanigans we are publishing events at-least-once (not exactly-once). That means our services need to be able to and are able to deal with dublicated events gracefully (by ignoring them).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good WiFi - More TEDN dark arts</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/07/25/good-wifi-more-tedn-dark-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/07/25/good-wifi-more-tedn-dark-arts/</guid>
      <description>Updated (2021-08-14): Added some test data (at the end; see below)&#xA;As I said before &amp;hellip;&#xA;When you work from anywhere (or even from home) it is YOUR(!!!) responsibility to ensure that you are connected!!!&#xA;Statements like &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;hellip; I cannot join the standup, because I was not able to find a WLAN hotspot.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Can you hear me? Sorry &amp;hellip; I am on a shitty/weak WLAN.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;hellip; can we switch off the video.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is better than Remote-First 1.0? Remote-First 2.0!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/07/04/what-is-better-than-remote-first-1.0-remote-first-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/07/04/what-is-better-than-remote-first-1.0-remote-first-2.0/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I got my second jab. I am fully vaccinated now. I am now in Germany to see my parents for the first time in 12 month.&#xA;Yes: It is finally happening! The pandemic (slowly, but surely) comes to an end.&#xA;Which creates (for some of us and for some companies) a big question: What&amp;rsquo;s the next step? What&amp;rsquo;s the path forward (e.g. from a organisational structure/development point of view)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of the pandemic - Social Media Edition</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/10/the-end-of-the-pandemic-social-media-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/10/the-end-of-the-pandemic-social-media-edition/</guid>
      <description>Now it is (almost) official: The pandemic is over (or is coming to an end fast/soon). In the next couple of days I am going to get my second shoot. Last week I was staying for 5 days in River Valley Holiday Park (first time in 12 month that I was able to do a multi-day_trip with the TEDN van). And next week I am going to Germany (and I am going to stay there for a month).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programming with Scala(3)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/02/effective-programming-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/02/effective-programming-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Just finished the brand new Effective Programming with Scala course on Coursera.&#xA;It is a beginners course and it is excellent for beginners. Good introduction to Scala and also into the basics of functional programming.&#xA;But &amp;hellip; for me the main attraction was that the course is based on (and is using) Scala3, means even if you are a seasoned Scala2 software engineer (and/or have not written Scala code in a while), this course is an excellent refresher that will allow you to grasp the essence of why/how Scala3 is different from Scala2 in the shortest possible time (I was playing the videos on 2x and was able to do all 6 weeks in 6x3=18 hours; and used the exercices to make my IDE (emacs/metals) work with Scala3).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distances - Know them. Manage them.</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</guid>
      <description>Building and managing remote-first organizations means that you also need to understand (and manage) distances!&#xA;To develop your ability to understand and manage distances is very important because human beings naturally need closeness (to other people and/or the purpose of the endeavor) to feel a sense of belonging.&#xA;But &amp;hellip; wait a sec: What do you mean by distances (plural)? Is there more than one?&#xA;Big surprise: Yes! When I build and run remote-first organizations I worry about and manage at least the following distances &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(The Extreme) 100 Day Walking Challenge</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/the-extreme-100-day-walking-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/the-extreme-100-day-walking-challenge/</guid>
      <description>In January I had a good call with my friend Braggy in Sydney. The insight was, that 2020 was different to what I/we expected, but with 20/20 hint-sight it was not necessarily a bad a year (at least not for me).&#xA;The pandemic forced me to question what I am doing and why I am doing it and how I am doing it in a lot of interesting ways. I will always remember 2020 as a year where I grew a lot, albeit in unexpected ways/directions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some more fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Scala3 is here.&#xA;In my earlier post I saw some weird performance differences between Scala2 and Scala3 (RC3) and felt (obviously) compelled to run the benchmark again against 3.0.0.&#xA;And &amp;hellip; big surprise: Everything is back to normal. Scala3 is as fast as Scala2.&#xA;The big differences come from very small numbers (e.g. Day13). The biggest (reproducible) differences is on Day3(part1): 112 msecs vs. 255 msecs. If I am getting really bored one day I might take a look at it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Note: Look here for 3.0 benchmark numbers&#xA;The release of Scala3 is imminent.&#xA;In April I ported/migrated nmesos from Scala2 to Scala3 and I just did a quick benchmark to see what Scala3 is doing to my Advent-of-Code implementation from 2017.&#xA;Initially I was wondering (and maybe a little bit afraid) how difficult migrating to Scala3 will be (and what problems I will be running into).&#xA;The good news is that migrating to Scala3 is not difficult at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala 3 is ... gluten-free!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/21/scala-3-is-...-gluten-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/21/scala-3-is-...-gluten-free/</guid>
      <description>A couple of month ago I started to have stomach cramps. First it was only once week, but then it was more or less constant.&#xA;Funny enough I had to find out that (even) late(r) in life you can &amp;ldquo;become&amp;rdquo; gluten-sensitive/-intolerant. Means &amp;hellip; a couple of weeks ago I got myself tested and changed my diet (to (mostly) gluten-free) and (big surprise !!!) &amp;hellip; after 3 days I was pain free!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The first Summit/Hack-a-thon @ Community</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/12/the-first-summit/hack-a-thon-@-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/12/the-first-summit/hack-a-thon-@-community/</guid>
      <description>As people know &amp;hellip; I am big fan of building and maintain this balance between Product and Engineering where &amp;hellip;&#xA;Product makes sure we build the right thing and Engineering makes sure we built it right (and we help each other to do so :)) But that is only the start. The real magic happens when we get to a point where we are not building faster horses. If the conversation goes wrong it goes like this &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &#43; Beam = Hamler (III)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/01/haskell--beam-hamler-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/01/haskell--beam-hamler-iii/</guid>
      <description>Here comes part III of the Hamler blog post series &amp;hellip;&#xA;One of the observations was that for/on Day21 hamler ~6000 times slower than haskell, where in general we where able to see that it was 5-20 times slower.&#xA;Just looked into this a little bit and there is good news and bad news. The good news is I found something.&#xA;I can make the hamer solution run 10 times faster by changing the implementation of part1 from &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &#43; Beam = Hamler (II)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/01/18/haskell--beam-hamler-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/01/18/haskell--beam-hamler-ii/</guid>
      <description>Here comes part II of the Hamler blog post series &amp;hellip;&#xA;For this year&amp;rsquo;s Advent-of-Code I wanted to take a look at Hamler.&#xA;I just finished implementing all of the part-1 solutions in Hamler.&#xA;I had to skip Day 20 (the seamonster), because Hamler only supports a very small/limited number of packages, which means I would have needed to write a lot of code before I would have been able to tackle the actual problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &#43; Beam = Hamler (I)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/12/15/haskell--beam-hamler-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/12/15/haskell--beam-hamler-i/</guid>
      <description>Hamler Blog Post Series &amp;hellip;&#xA;Hamler (I) - First week (this post) Hamler (II) - All solutions for part 1 (in Hamler and Haskell) Hamler (III) - Making Day21 10 times faster What&amp;rsquo;s at the intersection of Haskell, the Erlang Beam/OTP and the Advent-of-Code?&#xA;Yes, right: Hamler!&#xA;Hamler is a Haskell-like language that runs on the Erlang Beam/OTP.&#xA;At Community we are big Beam/OTP fans (because we like highly-scalable and highly-available shared nothing micro-services systems).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet connections ... the life blood of The Extreme Digital Nomad</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/09/11/internet-connections-...-the-life-blood-of-the-extreme-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/09/11/internet-connections-...-the-life-blood-of-the-extreme-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>I am in Hidden Valley Holiday Park. Working on the career progression framework for Community. It is 5am and &amp;hellip; I realized something. Don&amp;rsquo;t hold your breath: It is something obvious (but I thought I share it anyway).&#xA;If you want to be successful as an Extreme Digital Nomad, having a good internet connection is absolutely essential (this is more true now then ever before, because of Covid-19 an even bigger part of the job relies on videoconverencing).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s a Staff Director?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</guid>
      <description>Community is growing fast.&#xA;More business. More customers. More people. More money. More (necessary) complexity (software and people).&#xA;The demand for this kind of growth can create a lot of interesting strains, problems and challenges.&#xA;In situations like this it is easy to end up between a rock and a hard place: Grow fast and run a/the risk that the growing pains will kill you or end up being too slow to fully capitalize on the magnitude of the opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEDN.LIFE Podcast - Trutzbox</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/08/23/tedn.life-podcast-trutzbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/08/23/tedn.life-podcast-trutzbox/</guid>
      <description>WARNING: This content is in German :) &amp;hellip;&#xA;Willkommen zum TEDN.LIFE Podcast.&#xA;Ich wollte schon immer mal ausprobieren wie man so was macht/produziert.&#xA;Da trifft es sich gut das ich ueber die letzten Wochen und Monate ein paar super-interessante Gesprache mit meinem Freund Hermann (Sauer) hatte.&#xA;Er ist Geschäftsführer und Gründer bei Comidio und Erfinder der Trutzbox.&#xA;Hermann und ich kennen uns jetzt seit mehr als 30 Jahren und haben eine Podcast-Serie produziert um zu diskutieren wie man sich heutzutage zeitgemaess davor schuetzen kann das die eigenen Daten ungefiltert dem Internet zur Verfuegung gestellt werden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The TEDN Van</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/14/the-tedn-van/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/14/the-tedn-van/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again: There is good news and bad news!!!&#xA;The good news is that the TEDN Mobile Office project is making good progress!&#xA;By now we (means mainly my dad :)) have &amp;hellip;&#xA;put in a screen installed an external 230V power plug (so that I can get power on/from a camp-ground) installed a fridge and a sink and a cooker (basically a kitchen) tested the tent (see below) installed a roof box (to store the tent) got ourselves a foldable e-bike &amp;hellip; means: we are ready to rock and roll!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland ... what&#39;s in a name</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/13/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/13/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>Updated: On Oct., 11th, 2020 Updated: On Apr., 12th, 2020 Updated: On Oct., 29th, 2016&#xA;A couple of years ago a colleague of mine pointed me to the new website/book from Jim Carrey &amp;ldquo;How Roland rolls&amp;rdquo; and while looking at it I started to think about my name: What does it mean? What is the origin? What are other well-known usages?&#xA;Here is what I found out &amp;hellip; Roland was a knight who fought for Charles the Great (also called the father of Europe).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs &amp; Lisp ... a match made in heaven</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/12/emacs-lisp-...-a-match-made-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/12/emacs-lisp-...-a-match-made-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>At community (as everywhere these days) we are not using one programming language, we are using a set of programming languages, means for one week I find myself writing a lot of elixir, the next week I write go, the week afterwards I need to fix some of our terraform configurations and on the weekend I am fixing a bug in a scala project.&#xA;What you need to survive (and stay sane) in such polyglot software engineering environment is a an IDE that is highly configurable and highly extensible (so that you get all the good stuff (auto-complete, code-navigation, on-the-fly syntax checking, &amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the WLAN ... the dark arts of extreme digital nomading</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/10/assessing-the-wlan-...-the-dark-arts-of-extreme-digital-nomading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/10/assessing-the-wlan-...-the-dark-arts-of-extreme-digital-nomading/</guid>
      <description>When you work from anywhere (or even from home) it is YOUR(!!!) responsibility to ensure that you are connected!!!&#xA;Statements like &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;hellip; I cannot join the standup, because I was not able to find a WLAN hotspot.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Can you hear me? Sorry &amp;hellip; I am on a shitty/weak WLAN.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Sorry &amp;hellip; can we switch off the video. There is too much lag.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; are just not good enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discussing Remote ... the book!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/07/discussing-remote-...-the-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/07/discussing-remote-...-the-book/</guid>
      <description>These days people look for advice and insight into how to build and run a remote-first engineering organization. And want/need to learn fast!!!&#xA;One good resource is (obviously) Remote (kind of the bible on working remote).&#xA;The book was published in 2013 (and was probably written in the 12 month before that).&#xA;Obviously the key messages/statements from the book are still true (or truer than ever), but I think that since then things have also changed and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEDN - The most important tool ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; is the laptop? No (but more on this later)!&#xA;&amp;hellip; is the mobile phone (with good 4G coverage)? No (and again &amp;hellip; more on this later)!&#xA;&amp;hellip; is a foldable coffee mug!!!&#xA;When you start to work remote (from home, from any place, &amp;hellip;) you will discover that you will end up in coffee shops (either because you want to (because you want/need to fight the cabin fever) or because you have to (because you want/need to find/have a WLAN connection)).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Extreme Digital Nomad (TEDN)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/03/31/the-extreme-digital-nomad-tedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/03/31/the-extreme-digital-nomad-tedn/</guid>
      <description>In the last 25 years I have build and run multiple distributed software engineering organisations.&#xA;My management style/philosophy is based on a couple of core believes &amp;hellip;&#xA;The Power of Why - I like to lead with Why (to make sure Talent and Passion can meet a Purpose) People first - I always think and feel that people are the solution (not the problem) Heterogenerity for the win - You have to be different to complement each other (and to create innovation) No surprises - Everybody (at all times) should be clear on what is happening and why it is happening, which leads to &amp;hellip; Building and maintain trust (and respect) (between the people) at all cost!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The corona virus ... and it&#39;s consequences</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/03/30/the-corona-virus-...-and-its-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 21:36:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/03/30/the-corona-virus-...-and-its-consequences/</guid>
      <description>The corona virus has a lot of weird side effects.&#xA;You suddenly find time to do things that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t do (or wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do) for month!!!&#xA;In my case I just updated/refreshed my blogging infrastructure &amp;hellip;&#xA;switching from jekyll to hugo (more capable framework; good support for Emacs org-mode) adding support for tags and categories retiring www.tritsch.org and www.innolocity.org (replacing it with tedn.life (more on that in due course)) The result is aesthetically pleasing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Elixir LDN 2019 - 3 languages in 3 minutes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2019/08/01/code-elixir-ldn-2019-3-languages-in-3-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2019/08/01/code-elixir-ldn-2019-3-languages-in-3-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was in London attending Code Elixir LDN 2019 delivering a lightening talk on 3 languages in 3 minutes &amp;hellip;&#xA;This was my first Elixir conference. We had about 100 people there. The conference was very well organized. From what I can see London is one the Elixir hotspots in Europe.&#xA;All of the talks where good, but a couple of them where of even better value to me personally (because I am the newbie) &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I love Haskell</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2019/04/06/i-love-haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2019/04/06/i-love-haskell/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 2 years I did a fair bit of Haskell (after doing a fairer bit of Scala for 8 years).&#xA;And I love Haskell.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: If you are tied to the JVM eco-system (and who is not these days), my opinion is that Scala is your best option to do functional programming on the JVM.&#xA;At the same time writting code in Haskell feels very natural to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hub-First vs. Remote-First vs. Pod-First ... Skating to where the puck is going to be</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2019/03/01/hub-first-vs.-remote-first-vs.-pod-first-...-skating-to-where-the-puck-is-going-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2019/03/01/hub-first-vs.-remote-first-vs.-pod-first-...-skating-to-where-the-puck-is-going-to-be/</guid>
      <description>Fig 1: Skating to where the puck ... Finding good and the right talent for an engineering organisation is as challenging as ever.&#xA;And then you need to keep engagement high and attrition low and you need to build/deliver something (with good/high velocity/efficiency/quality).&#xA;One key component to get this right is a good/the right structure for your engineering organisation.&#xA;And you probably want to structure it in a way so that it not only works today, but also in 2-3 years from now, because otherwise by the time you are done building the org it will not work (anymore)).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code ... Final cut (... and First cut :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/11/30/advent-of-code-...-final-cut-...-and-first-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/11/30/advent-of-code-...-final-cut-...-and-first-cut/</guid>
      <description>Today Advent of Code 2018 started again (at 05:00am (GMT))!!!&#xA;And &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; just in time &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; today I am also wrapping up Advent of Code 2017!!!&#xA;My first implementation was (obviously) in Scala.&#xA;And that one alone was interesting, because I also used ScalaCheck for property-based testing and ScalaMeter to implement performance tests for all solutions.&#xA;I then made the Scala code cross-compile with ScalaNative.&#xA;At the time I was also learning Kotlin and spend some cycles to port the code to Kotlin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The vertical bar screen of death ... the story of an unexpected win-win</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/09/21/the-vertical-bar-screen-of-death-...-the-story-of-an-unexpected-win-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/09/21/the-vertical-bar-screen-of-death-...-the-story-of-an-unexpected-win-win/</guid>
      <description>Last year I spend some time and money to &amp;ldquo;renovate&amp;rdquo; my old 17-inch Macbook Pro (remember the good old times &amp;hellip; when Apple was building good laptops with great keyboards and no touchbar :)).&#xA;For the last 6 month I was running VirtualBox on it hosting an Ubuntu image.&#xA;That kind of worked (a little bit slow at times and managing the ports was (sometimes) challenging, but otherwise &amp;hellip; ok).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Google Chrome show the Wifi login screen (best trick ever :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/09/20/make-google-chrome-show-the-wifi-login-screen-best-trick-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/09/20/make-google-chrome-show-the-wifi-login-screen-best-trick-ever/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if this has ever happen to you, &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; but once a month I am sitting in a hotel lobby or a coffee shop and I cannot (for the life of it) make Chrome show me the login screen to the Wifi portal and then you start to fiddle around with stop/start the Wifi and/or disconnect/connect to the Wifi and/or start a different browser (e.g. Firefox or Safari) and/or try a private browser window and/or clear the DNS cache and/or &amp;hellip; reboot!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2017 ... Revolutions!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/advent-of-code-2017-...-revolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/advent-of-code-2017-...-revolutions/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the Advent of Code &amp;hellip; again!!!&#xA;Last time we talked about a/the Scala implementation.&#xA;This time around I figured that I need to understand what the hype about Kotlin is all about and decided to port my Scala solutions to Kotlin.&#xA;There is a separate blog post on what I think about Kotlin, but overall it was a positive experience. I like Kotlin (but would not suggest/recommend it as a replacement for Scala).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin ... the better Java?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/kotlin-...-the-better-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/kotlin-...-the-better-java/</guid>
      <description>Everybody is talking about Kotlin. Me too!!!&#xA;Obviously the question is: Is Kotlin the next better thing?&#xA;Is Kotlin going to replace Java? Is Kotlin going to replace Scala? Is Kotlin the next better language that will make Software Engineers (much) more productive?&#xA;To find out I ported my Scala Advent of Code solutions to Kotlin.&#xA;My main take aways are &amp;hellip;&#xA;if you know Java, learning Kotlin will be easier and faster than learning Scala Kotlin is without a doubt &amp;ldquo;the better Java&amp;rdquo; it compiles fast it runs fast it has very good tooling/IDE support (namely (obviously) the support in Intellij is first-class) it runs on Android hell &amp;hellip; it even runs on Raspberry Pi with Arrows it has a very nice (pure) functional programming library if you know Scala, learning Kotlin will be even easier, but you will also feel that you are not gaining anything or even that you are loosing some capabilities that are valuable Sooooo &amp;hellip; my exec summary is &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn you a ... Haskell!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/learn-you-a-...-haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/learn-you-a-...-haskell/</guid>
      <description>In the last 6 month I have started to wonder.&#xA;First of all &amp;hellip; I am convinced that using the concepts of functional programming will give you better results (more maintainable/changeable/extendable code). Not embracing functional programming will (sooner or later) put you (and the organisation you are leading) at a competitive disadvantage (compared to those who do).&#xA;In that context I have put some time into learning more Scala (the learning never stops :)) and have also looked at Kotlin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The cost of building a skateboard ... and a lot of PSs</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/05/26/the-cost-of-building-a-skateboard-...-and-a-lot-of-pss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/05/26/the-cost-of-building-a-skateboard-...-and-a-lot-of-pss/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was explaining again how to build an MVP and I was using the skateboard picture (again :)).&#xA;In the middle of the discussion I realized that we only had half of the discussion, because we only talked about the direct benefits of the approach: Fast feedback, less risk to build the wrong thing, &amp;hellip;&#xA;We did not really talk about the cost of getting these benefits. The meeting got interesting when I started to point out that this is not about building the solution the fastest way or the cheapest way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2017 ... Reloaded!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/05/24/advent-of-code-2017-...-reloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/05/24/advent-of-code-2017-...-reloaded/</guid>
      <description>OK &amp;hellip; it took me a while, but &amp;hellip; hopefully it was worth it!!!&#xA;Last year at christmas I did the Advent of Code and &amp;hellip; really liked it!!!&#xA;If you do not know it, it is a series (25 of them) of code puzzles that need to be solved to unlock a/the christmas tree (every day (between Dec. 1st and Dec. 25th) a new/the next puzzle becomes available).&#xA;The puzzles do a lot of different things and will test your ability to come up with good/clever datastructures/algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable new hire training ... and integrating sbt-release with sbt-github-release</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/05/04/tenable-new-hire-training-...-and-integrating-sbt-release-with-sbt-github-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/05/04/tenable-new-hire-training-...-and-integrating-sbt-release-with-sbt-github-release/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was flying to the Tenable new hire training in Columbia/MD and that means &amp;hellip; 8 hours of uninterrupted coding time!!!&#xA;At the same time, I saw/found the sbt-guthub-release plugin and started to wonder, if it would be possible to combine it with the sbt-release plugin.&#xA;And while I was thinking about this I figured &amp;ldquo;what the hell&amp;rdquo;, why not creating another opinionated giter8 template to bootstrap my scala projects, means at the end I decided to spend the 8 hours on bringing a couple of things together &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Category Theory for Programmers ... Reviewing THE course!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/04/03/category-theory-for-programmers-...-reviewing-the-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/04/03/category-theory-for-programmers-...-reviewing-the-course/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago Angel pointed me to a very nice lecture: Category Theory for Programmers (from/by Bartosz Milewski).&#xA;Bartosz Milewski is a physisist, a philosopher (on computer science and life in general :)) and runs his own company to make the world a better place by means of Category Theory and Haskell :).&#xA;The course is long &amp;hellip;&#xA;Category Theory 1.1: Motivation and Philosophy Category Theory 1.2: What is a category?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assembling a Gatling (gun) ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/03/07/assembling-a-gatling-gun-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/03/07/assembling-a-gatling-gun-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>Back to the roots!!!&#xA;I am writing Gatling tests (again :)). (Obviously) I used to do this (a lot :)), when I was with Gilt (for an obvious reason :)).&#xA;To get going again, I had to make the basics work &amp;hellip; again.&#xA;The basics are: Make the sbt-gatling plugin work to build (end-to-end integration) tests/simulations and then create a &amp;ldquo;deployable&amp;rdquo; (fat) jar (using sbt-assembly).&#xA;This proved to be more difficult than I thought (because this used to work).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Cookbook ... Insights into Digital Transformation and how to go about it!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/25/the-digital-cookbook-...-insights-into-digital-transformation-and-how-to-go-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/25/the-digital-cookbook-...-insights-into-digital-transformation-and-how-to-go-about-it/</guid>
      <description>Nitro&amp;rsquo;s mission statement is &amp;hellip;&#xA;And right now &amp;hellip; Digital Transformation is a very hot topic. For most of the Fortune 500 companies! And it is also a very complex topic (e.g. How to make sure that (PDF) documents can become a first class citizen in the Digital Transformation initiative).&#xA;Companies obviously want it. Either to gain a competitive advantage or at least to not put themselves at a competitive disadvantage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDSE @ edx.org (with TU Delft)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/24/gdse-@-edx.org-with-tu-delft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/24/gdse-@-edx.org-with-tu-delft/</guid>
      <description>MOOCs (Massive Open Online Courses) are massive!!!&#xA;I did my first one 7 years ago (on Cousera; Martin Odersky&amp;rsquo;s course on Functional Programming with Scala).&#xA;Since then there has been an explosion of sites and offerings. By now it is clear that, if you do not know, how to use these sites to your own advantage you are putting yourself at a competitive disadvantage (from a skills development point of view).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The American election ... 1 year after</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</guid>
      <description>The dust has settled. All opinions have been voiced. All articles have been written. Not quite &amp;hellip; here is another one :).&#xA;I am struggling with Donald Trump and his character and his personality and his opinions. A lot!&#xA;And what do to next depend first of all on, if you believe that there is a problem or not and what that problem is. It then comes down to what to do to fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About being a (software development) manager ... and managing energy!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/20/about-being-a-software-development-manager-...-and-managing-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/20/about-being-a-software-development-manager-...-and-managing-energy/</guid>
      <description>A lot has been written and said about what you need to do as a manager or more specifically as a manager of a software development team/group/organisation.&#xA;You need to understand people and the business and technology (software engineering processes and practices, tools and frameworks, programming languages, &amp;hellip;).&#xA;You need to be a manager and a leader. You need to be a friend and a dad (or mother) and a boss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackweeks @ Nitro ... The Why, The What, The How</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/07/29/hackweeks-@-nitro-...-the-why-the-what-the-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/07/29/hackweeks-@-nitro-...-the-why-the-what-the-how/</guid>
      <description>As already discussed: I am obsessed with building cars!!!&#xA;Not in the sense that I want/need to build cars, but in the sense that Henry Ford famously once upon a time (apparently not) said, that if he would have build what customers wanted, he would have build faster horses.&#xA;Luckily he was able to complement the input from the customers (we want faster horses) with a view of what is possible (cars).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make your options in the future suck less!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/26/how-to-make-your-options-in-the-future-suck-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/26/how-to-make-your-options-in-the-future-suck-less/</guid>
      <description>If you are here for some advise on how to invest your money (using options), you are in the wrong place.&#xA;This is about how to use Scala Options in Scala Futures!!!&#xA;Erik Bakker delivered an excellent talk on this topic in 2015 at the ScalaDays in Amsterdam.&#xA;On Sunday morning I was on Dad-duty driving Alexandros to a paint-ball battle and ended up in coffee shop with three hours of zone time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leadership at Amazon ... Productive Friction 2.0</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/leadership-at-amazon-...-productive-friction-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/leadership-at-amazon-...-productive-friction-2.0/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was reading the letter that Jeff Bezo&amp;rsquo;s is writing to shareholders every year.&#xA;The obsession with fast, good decision making was and is resonating with me.&#xA;I like fast decision making processes that produce good decisions. And I like cultures and behaviors that foster environments that produce these fast, good decisions.&#xA;In the case of Amazon they have developed a set of leadership principles and behaviors (like the famous 2 pizza rule) to protect their agility and velocity, while they are scaling (and to make sure they stay a Day 1 company).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productive Friction and Diversity ... the pillars of innovation ... or: How to NOT build faster horses!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/productive-friction-and-diversity-...-the-pillars-of-innovation-...-or-how-to-not-build-faster-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/productive-friction-and-diversity-...-the-pillars-of-innovation-...-or-how-to-not-build-faster-horses/</guid>
      <description>In the week of Jul., 10th we are going to do our next Hackweek.&#xA;The concept is not new. A lot of companies do it.&#xA;The question is: Why is it valuable?&#xA;For me the answer is: Because you want to make sure you are not building faster horses!&#xA;Henry Ford once famously said (or not said :)): &amp;ldquo;If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The myth of ... getting it right the first time</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/06/the-myth-of-...-getting-it-right-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/06/the-myth-of-...-getting-it-right-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>I am reading it again: Clean Code.&#xA;This time I am reading it differently. The first time around (6 years ago), I was reading it and learned a lot (about how to write clean code) and was using it (a lot) to get other people on board and convince them that this is the way (the only way) to write code.&#xA;I still think that the book can serve that purpose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Operational Excellence</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/04/30/thoughts-on-operational-excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/04/30/thoughts-on-operational-excellence/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes for me discussions about Operational Excellence sound like discussions about teenager sex: Everybody is talking about it, nobody &amp;hellip;&#xA;The other day I was wondering again: What is Operational Excellence and why should you have it?&#xA;For me Operational Excellence is the ability of an organization to make (initially small and then over time bigger and bigger) promises and keep them consistently and reliably within budget (time and money).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do the right thing ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/03/19/do-the-right-thing-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/03/19/do-the-right-thing-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>I am driving an electric car. It is a great experience. Not to a small part, because the Irish government is trying very hard to make it a good experience. Government grants, good infrastructure, friendly people.&#xA;The other day, I noticed something that leaves room for improvement. On a Sunday afternoon, I was charging my car at the quick charger at the LUAS station in Stillorgan. The parking lot is operated by NCPS and has signs on the ground and on sign-posts to indicate that the spaces are reserved for electric vehicle (EV) charging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Micro-Services Systems be simple?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/20/can-micro-services-systems-be-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/20/can-micro-services-systems-be-simple/</guid>
      <description>Architecting and designing large (distributed) systems makes you think about complexity. A lot!!!&#xA;The first question that you want to ask yourself is probably &amp;ldquo;What is complexity?&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;For that I recommend to watch Rich Hickey&amp;rsquo;s talk on complexity (Simple Made Easy). In this talk he raises awareness for the difference between something being complex or complicated. And he also (rightfully) points out that simple is actually very hard (every idiot can build a complicated solution) and that simple is a relative term (something that is simple for you can look complex and/or complicated to others).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LOL ... printers suck!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/19/lol-...-printers-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/19/lol-...-printers-suck/</guid>
      <description>Last year we visited some of our customers in EMEA to get some video footage about their Nitro Experience.&#xA;While we had our Creative Director in town (in Dublin), we also decided to shoot some material for some internal videos. Ooohhh &amp;hellip; the fun we had &amp;hellip;&#xA;Life at Nitro: The Nitro Family Life Nitro: Our Dedication to Development Life at Nitro: Our Diversity Nitro: Our Vision for PDF Life at Nitro: Our Leaders Nitro: Our Thoughts on Printers My favorite quote is &amp;hellip; obviously &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;Printers suck!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am a lucky guy :) ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it takes a while to get to it &amp;hellip;&#xA;Last year I was opening Data-by-the-Bay and was welcoming/addressing the attendees. Wanted to turn it into a blog post and never got around to do it. Finally &amp;hellip; here we go &amp;hellip;&#xA;Good morning everybody. On behalf of Nitro: Welcome to Data by the Bay.&#xA;My name is Roland Tritsch and I am German and I am the VP Engineering at Nitro.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Light ... Nitro Engineering 2017</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/12/09/spotify-light-...-nitro-engineering-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/12/09/spotify-light-...-nitro-engineering-2017/</guid>
      <description>Finding a good and maybe even the right org structure for an engineering organization is something of a dark art.&#xA;Initially everything is so easy. 5-10 engineers are in one location, have one boss, work on the one thing and have one common skill.&#xA;But then you are successful. And you hire more engineers and then you realize that to derisk the hiring and the growth you probably want to hire in more than one location and then a couple of engineers will leave, because the people management aspect of the being an engineering manager is not something that comes naturally to most of us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do I work for Nitro ... connecting the dots!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/11/11/why-do-i-work-for-nitro-...-connecting-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/11/11/why-do-i-work-for-nitro-...-connecting-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>We are redoing our engineering website and our blog (stay tuned).&#xA;In parallel we have worked on the Nitro Mission Statement (for 2017 and beyond) and have condensed it down to &amp;hellip;&#xA;Our VP Product has also articulated a comprehensive, 2-step, &amp;ldquo;Elon Musk&amp;rdquo;-style master plan how to get there &amp;hellip;&#xA;Make edit, collaborate, share, sign &amp;hellip; work!!! - for everybody (personal and business (wall-to-wall)), everywhere (desktop, browser, mobile) and anytime (always-on).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ooohhh boy ... twitterfeed is no more</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/31/ooohhh-boy-...-twitterfeed-is-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/31/ooohhh-boy-...-twitterfeed-is-no-more/</guid>
      <description>The other day I got and email that twitterfeed is no more (they recommend to use buffer or dlvr.it instead).&#xA;My social media setup was to post to Google+ and then use twitterfeed to cross-post to twitter and facebook.&#xA;With twitterfeed going out of business I am &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; going to retire my Google+ account &amp;hellip; going to use HootSuite to selectively post to twitter (business, technical, work) and facebook (private, personal) &amp;hellip; going to continue to use Flickr to publish pictures &amp;hellip; going to continue to use GitHub to host my blog (and will cross-post on medium and linked-in for visibility).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit the Powerscourt Gardens ... the Home of Software Gardening</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/28/visit-the-powerscourt-gardens-...-the-home-of-software-gardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/28/visit-the-powerscourt-gardens-...-the-home-of-software-gardening/</guid>
      <description>Clearly &amp;hellip; and obviously &amp;hellip; the idea of Software Gardening is not mine. But as I have already mentioned once or twice &amp;hellip; I like it a lot.&#xA;And it is also something that we have adopted here at Nitro Engineering as a guiding principle for our daily actions and daily habits.&#xA;In general software architecture is something that you cannot see or touch, but in October I had the engineering managers in Dublin and that chance was just too good to not use it, means we all hoped on a bus and went to see the real thing!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-to-Hero ... in a day</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/22/zero-to-hero-...-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/22/zero-to-hero-...-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had a good day in the office!&#xA;Nitro (like a lot of other startups) is going through growing pains. In the last 2 years we have hired a lot of people (and have not been able to retain all of them). We have build a lot of systems, platforms, features and products (and some of it turned into technical debt faster than we wanted). We implemented processes and practices (and not all of them made us more productive or faster).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Penny ... everything is better with ... blockchain :)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/17/penny-...-everything-is-better-with-...-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/17/penny-...-everything-is-better-with-...-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>In terms of technologies right now I am very much focused on Functional Programming and Machine Learning and Software Engineering for Mobile Devices and &amp;hellip; a couple of other things (Rust, Go, &amp;hellip;), but wanted to dedicate a blog post to a technology that will (IMHO) have a significant impact on our future: Blockchains (or more specfically the Ethereum project).&#xA;Why are we talking about this &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; because everything is better with blockchain :).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning ... and beyond - RRRs from the Deep Learning Summit 2016 in London</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/09/23/deep-learning-...-and-beyond-rrrs-from-the-deep-learning-summit-2016-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/09/23/deep-learning-...-and-beyond-rrrs-from-the-deep-learning-summit-2016-in-london/</guid>
      <description>I am just back from the Deep Learning (DL) Summit in London, where I had very interesting 2 days with a lot of good presentations and a lot of time to think about the future.&#xA;I am working with Nitro for a year now and have learned a lot about Machine Learning (ML) and Natural Language Processing (NLP), but as always: the more you learn, the more you understand that you know nothing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy 4th of July!!! Or ... how to take advantage of an opportunity!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/07/10/happy-4th-of-july-or-...-how-to-take-advantage-of-an-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/07/10/happy-4th-of-july-or-...-how-to-take-advantage-of-an-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>A long weekend in San Francisco (Jul., 4th - Independence Day), great weather and nothing to do?&#xA;I smell an opportunity! An opportunity to do something that I always wanted to do: Explore the bay area on a motor bike.&#xA;The Nitro CEO was kind enough to introduce me to Wolfgang and Wolfgang and his team helped me to get my hands on a BMW R1200 RT and off we go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are we surprised? - &#34;Hot, hot, hot&#34;</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/02/08/why-are-we-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/02/08/why-are-we-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</guid>
      <description>Christina loves me. For a lot of reasons. One of them is that I have this habit of putting stuff into the microwave, heat it for 10 mins (I am exhaturating) and then try to take it out with my bare hands, while shouting (with this expression of total surprise on my face) &amp;ldquo;hot, hot, hot&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Why am I surprised? If you put stuff into the microwave (longer than 30 secs) it is probably going to be (very) hot, right?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Job, New Site, ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/08/14/new-job-new-site-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/08/14/new-job-new-site-.../</guid>
      <description>Yep &amp;hellip; I got a new job and yep &amp;hellip; I got a new website.&#xA;In reverse order, first: (Given that I am a VP Infrastructure Engineering) I am currently in the process to refactor my personal infrastructure and I am consolidate most of it on GitHub and Amazon. The result is the wonderful new website you are looking at. The pages are on GitHub (pages based on Jekyll) and the domains and the DNS are hosted on Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>According to the Sunday Independent ... 50 years ago ... the outlook was ... mainly dry</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/07/11/according-to-the-sunday-independent-...-50-years-ago-...-the-outlook-was-...-mainly-dry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/07/11/according-to-the-sunday-independent-...-50-years-ago-...-the-outlook-was-...-mainly-dry/</guid>
      <description>Nuclear power plant offered to usReports are current in political circles that the Government has received an offer from a German industrialist to build a nuclear reactor in Ireland as part of his plan to provide power for industrial development. Ballad group singers are engagedFolk singer Ann Byrne, of Blackrock, and Paddy Roche, Templeogue, a member of the Ludlow Trio, who have announced their engagement. Both are regular singers at the Abbey Tavern in Howth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Range anxiety? What range anxiety! (My first road trip with the BADMobile :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/05/20/range-anxiety-what-range-anxiety-my-first-road-trip-with-the-badmobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/05/20/range-anxiety-what-range-anxiety-my-first-road-trip-with-the-badmobile/</guid>
      <description>In case you are wondering ... this is the BADMobile ... (ask me, if you want :)) ...&#xA;My friend Klaus and myself have spend more time and more miles (on motorbike(s)) together than we care to count. And the pattern is that once in a while we need to do something crazy. This time around we decided that in the next 5 years we will visit all of the major road races in the UK &amp;amp; Ireland (at least) once.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming on iOS and Android - Making the impossible ... possible?!?!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/04/25/functional-programming-on-ios-and-android-making-the-impossible-...-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/04/25/functional-programming-on-ios-and-android-making-the-impossible-...-possible/</guid>
      <description>Beginning of the year we had one of our Microsoft Senior Architects from the GDC (Global Delivery Center) in India with us. Over a couple of pints the obvious happened: I sparked his interest in functional programming and he sparked my interest in F#.&#xA;First I made Mono&amp;nbsp;and Emacs work, but then I started to use Xamarin.&#xA;Not so much, because I needed a better IDE (Emacs rules :)), but because I got interested in the claim that you can use Xamarin to do Android and iOS cross-platform development with #F.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on Android - Gradle, Ensime and the Android UI samples</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/01/27/scala-on-android-gradle-ensime-and-the-android-ui-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/01/27/scala-on-android-gradle-ensime-and-the-android-ui-samples/</guid>
      <description>Besides getting my first companion app done for my Pebble, I also spend some time on X-Mas to start porting the Android UI samples to Scala. The samples obviously use gradle. I normally use sbt to build my apps, but this time I decided to stick with gradle, because I wanted to make it easy for people to consume the code (and embracing a new build system might be too big of a step as a first step).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Mas Project 3: Install Source Code Pro (again) - And make Emacs use it (again)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-3-install-source-code-pro-again-and-make-emacs-use-it-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-3-install-source-code-pro-again-and-make-emacs-use-it-again/</guid>
      <description>It is not a secret ... I like Source Code Pro!&#xA;A couple of weeks ago I got myself a new MacBook Air (and resisted the temptation to get the 13-inch and like the 11-inch a lot) and installed Source Code Pro again. Getting it installed using FontBook was no problem, but then I could not remember how make it the default font for Emacs and all the tips and tricks that I was able to find did not work for me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Mas Project 1: Pebble Hello World 2.0 - The companion edition (with Android, Scala, Macroid)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-1-pebble-hello-world-2.0-the-companion-edition-with-android-scala-macroid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-1-pebble-hello-world-2.0-the-companion-edition-with-android-scala-macroid/</guid>
      <description>I love Christmas!!!&#xA;My wife turns the house into the home of all homes, I get to see my all (or at least most of) my friends and ... I get to work on special projects :).&#xA;My first special project was to extend the standard Pebble Tutorial a little bit and show how to build a simple companion app that exchanges data with the watch.&#xA;As a first step I added some text to the standard Pebble Tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Mas Project 2: Building a &#34;FlieWaTuet&#34; - Using Mignon :)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-2-building-a-fliewatuet-using-mignon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-2-building-a-fliewatuet-using-mignon/</guid>
      <description>Warning!!! This has nothing to do with Scala or Software Engineering in general. Read at your own risk :).&#xA;Ok, I admit it: This post is a little bit off-topic, but we had too much fun not to talk about it.&#xA;It all started with an afternoon and nothing to do. At the end my dad, Alexandros and myself decided to get my dad&#39;s old Mignon box and just build &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala, Android and BLE, because ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/07/27/scala-android-and-ble-because-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/07/27/scala-android-and-ble-because-.../</guid>
      <description>... everything is better with bluetooth :).&#xA;Originally I was thinking to do a presentation, but Martin convinced me to turn my talk for the Scala Meetup in Dublin into a hands-on tutorial.&#xA;The main objective was to talk people through a couple of demos that can serve as starting points, so that they can start to do their own development.&#xA;We talked about, how to write, compile and run .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTC One Mini ... does it make Sense?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/04/01/htc-one-mini-...-does-it-make-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/04/01/htc-one-mini-...-does-it-make-sense/</guid>
      <description>Update 2004-04-02: The first nightlies for M4 got released on CyanogenMod. Testing now ...&#xA;---&#xA;The short answer is: NO!&#xA;At least not in my case (anymore). I just removed all (common) Sense from my phone. HTC Sense that is!&#xA;3 month ago I got myself a new phone and decided to go with the HTC One Mini. It is my kind of phone. It runs Android (means I can write Scala apps for it), it is sturdy, looks good and is not too big.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on the Pebble - Exploring SDK 2.0 ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/02/06/scala-on-the-pebble-exploring-sdk-2.0-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/02/06/scala-on-the-pebble-exploring-sdk-2.0-.../</guid>
      <description>... just kidding :).&#xA;Reality is ... triggered by the release of the Pebble SDK 2.0 on Feb., 3rd (iOS only, more on this later) and after more than 20 years of JVM based software development I willingful decided to write some C code again!!!&#xA;And I liked it. Mainly because of CloudPebble. As pointed out here, setting up a software development environment can be a daunting task. Not so with CloudPebble.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on Android - A start ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/01/28/scala-on-android-a-start-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/01/28/scala-on-android-a-start-.../</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t know what your experience is, but ...&#xA;... in my case, when I look at a new technology, one of the main (or first) hurdles is, that it takes some time to get the initial development environment up and running.&#xA;This is why I figured it probably makes sense to polish and publish something that I did a couple of month ago: Porting the basic Android tutorial to Scala.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on a Chromebook? Yes, we can!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/01/22/scala-on-a-chromebook-yes-we-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/01/22/scala-on-a-chromebook-yes-we-can/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I got myself an Acer Chromebook and so far I am very happy with it. I use it as a tablet with a keyboard and carry it around with me a lot, but ...&#xA;... sometimes I have an hour to kill in a coffee shop and would like to do some software development (in my case and these days mainly Scala) and started to wonder, if and how this is possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talking about the value of immutability ... for deployment platforms and innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/11/12/talking-about-the-value-of-immutability-...-for-deployment-platforms-and-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/11/12/talking-about-the-value-of-immutability-...-for-deployment-platforms-and-innovation/</guid>
      <description>I am just back from presenting a talk at FutureStack in SFO.&#xA;Very interesting trip. Got very positive feedback on what we are doing. Did meet a lot of people with very interesting ideas (e.g. my friend Klaus (see below)). Lew&#39;s keynote on Rubicon was insightful and inspiring. Kate was talking on the art of self-management and Peter talked about how to run hundreds of Postgres databases for Heroku. Checking out these (and all of the the other talks) is recommended.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To become or not to become ... a Sunday with Scala and Actors</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/10/07/to-become-or-not-to-become-...-a-sunday-with-scala-and-actors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/10/07/to-become-or-not-to-become-...-a-sunday-with-scala-and-actors/</guid>
      <description>It is Sunday, the sun is shining ... in Ireland!!! What do you do? Right: You get your laptop and finally start to get your head around the actor model in Scala.&#xA;In my case I tried to come up with a simulation for the Dining Philosophers Problem (DPP). There are implementations available, but I consolidated them and renamed the states and transitions to make it more obvious what is going on and used plantUML to come up with State Transition Diagrams (STDs) that show what is going on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlightFest @ Gilt ... Location, Location, Location ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/09/27/flightfest-@-gilt-...-location-location-location-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/09/27/flightfest-@-gilt-...-location-location-location-.../</guid>
      <description>Psssttt ... don&#39;t tell anybody, but ... at Gilt it is not always about work and writing great code.&#xA;Sometimes we like to party. Especially when something like FlightFest comes along and the office is located right down by the Liffey overlooking the river and the Samuel Beckett Bridge.&#xA;Sometimes it is too good not to do it. What a great day. For the kids. For the girls and the boys.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gilt CIO talks ... about innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</guid>
      <description>From an interview with Steve. Too good not to turn it into a blog post ...&#xA;&#34;When people talk about innovation they are often talking about the solution to some problem. But the real source of innovation is figuring out what the right problem is to solve. Take Gilt for example: Gilt took the invite only friends &amp;amp; family sample sale invite that existed for coveted brands in cities like New York and moved that model online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting GTD done - Thoughts and Tools</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>We all have a lot to do. Effective time/task management is essential. I’ve been using GTD (Getting Things Done) for a while now (a long while :)) and for me it comes down to the question, “How do you pick the next, best, most valuable thing to work on?”—basically answering the question of how to make the best use of the time you have.&#xA;Picking something from your list of urgent things to do is kind of easy, but how can you make sure you are not missing the opportunity/chance to work on something important, if you get the chance to do so?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting some KPIs ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/05/10/charting-some-kpis-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/05/10/charting-some-kpis-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of weeks I was working on an initiative to make all the Gilt Tech KPIs available in one place. There are lots of dashboard solutions available, but nothing really did what we wanted it to do or it was clumsy to use. At the end we decided to build a small Scala Play app to get what we want.&#xA;As part of that exercise we had to find a way to visualise the history of the KPI values (timestamp, value pairs) and I started to play around with charting frameworks and figured it makes sense to write up what I have found out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About broken windows and software gardening ... - Thoughts from The Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/02/16/about-broken-windows-and-software-gardening-...-thoughts-from-the-pragmatic-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/02/16/about-broken-windows-and-software-gardening-...-thoughts-from-the-pragmatic-programmer/</guid>
      <description>These days I am writing more source code again (mostly Scala) and decided to (re)read a couple of books to refresh some thoughts and ideas and believes that I always had when it comes to writing source code.&#xA;One of the books I was (re)reading was Clean Code and there are lots of good ideas in it, e.g. after reading the book 15 years ago I got into the habit of refactoring, whenever I feel the urge to put a comment in the code, which is an indication that the code is not clear/self-documenting enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes small things make a big difference ... using Source Code Pro with Emacs</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2012/11/10/sometimes-small-things-make-a-big-difference-...-using-source-code-pro-with-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2012/11/10/sometimes-small-things-make-a-big-difference-...-using-source-code-pro-with-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;outing alarm&amp;gt;I love my emacs.&amp;lt;/outing alarm&amp;gt;&#xA;Sometimes small things can make a big difference. Like a dot. You can put it at the end of the sentence or in a number (1.001 vs. 100.1 - can make a &#34;small&#34; difference) or you put it into the zero to make it easily&amp;nbsp;distinguishable from capital O.&#xA;Now you might say, who cares, but if you read a lot of source code (like I do) Source Code Pro&amp;nbsp;is a real pleasure for your eyes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Scala @ TCD ... back to the roots</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2012/11/10/teaching-scala-@-tcd-...-back-to-the-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2012/11/10/teaching-scala-@-tcd-...-back-to-the-roots/</guid>
      <description>20 years ago I used to teach object-oriented programming (based on Eiffel) at my old university in Germany.&#xA;This week I got the chance to experience a deja-vu, because earlier this year I did run into Glenn Strong who is teaching Functional Programming in TCD in Dublin and we started to develop the idea that it would be useful to add a Scala module to his Haskell based lecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A starting point for ... Apache Felix, OSGi, Scala, Sbt</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2012/09/16/a-starting-point-for-...-apache-felix-osgi-scala-sbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2012/09/16/a-starting-point-for-...-apache-felix-osgi-scala-sbt/</guid>
      <description>It is not a secret ...&#xA;I like OSGi and Scala ... and therefore it was only a question of time until I started to wonder, if there is anything that would prevent me from using OSGi from/with Scala. The short answer and the good news is ... nothing.&#xA;I just checked in my port of the original Apache Felix Tutorial to Scala. As mentioned in the README I do not want to claim that this boilerplate code, but it is a working development environment that you can use as a starting point for your own experiments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning at Gilt - &#34;Maven-izing&#34; a/the Apache Mahout tutorial</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/12/11/machine-learning-at-gilt-maven-izing-a/the-apache-mahout-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/12/11/machine-learning-at-gilt-maven-izing-a/the-apache-mahout-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>If you work for Gilt Tech than you WILL (sooner or later ... somehow) get involved in our Machine Learning and Recommendation efforts. Our requirements are extremely complex and challenging. We have over 5 million members (fast growing) and a product catalog which features products that are selling out between 10 secs and 3 days, means we need to make recommendations for products that have (almost) no history to members that might not be with us for a long time (yet).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dublin Innovation Festival - Talking about Innovation, Gilt and Ireland ... and Evolution and Darwinism</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I had the chance to talk about three things I care about: Innovation, Gilt and Ireland. The occasion was the Dublin Chamber of Commerce Smart Series Event on Innovation (that was the day after Dundrum Shopping Center and half of Dublin got flooded). The objective was to share a couple of thoughts on what innovation is (or is not), what Gilt is doing to foster innovation and what Ireland has to offer to companies like Gilt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Small) change to my social networking ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/06/26/small-change-to-my-social-networking-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/06/26/small-change-to-my-social-networking-.../</guid>
      <description> First of all ... apologies!!! In the last 2 weeks my (private) tweeds (almost) completely died away. I was just madly busy with work :(. Going forward, I will (continue to) send my &#34;diary&#34; updates to @rolandtritsch, but will send my more work related tweeds (e.g. Blogging about ..., Reading about ..., Looking at ...) to @innolocity. @innolocity is a public feed. Just register here to follow. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing - A practical guide for the common user</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/05/01/cloud-computing-a-practical-guide-for-the-common-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/05/01/cloud-computing-a-practical-guide-for-the-common-user/</guid>
      <description>These days (and especially after the Amazon EC2 outage :)) everybody is talking about cloud computing. It seems you cannot be sexy, if you do not &#34;live&#34; in the cloud. But most of the more &#34;common&#34; users (and for the sake of the discussion, I am including myself in that group) probably think that cloud computing and using &#34;the cloud&#34; is something that enterprises use to (potentially) safe cost and also to (potentially) gain flexibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventure 2.0 - Building the Gilt Software Development Center in Dublin</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/04/19/adventure-2.0-building-the-gilt-software-development-center-in-dublin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/04/19/adventure-2.0-building-the-gilt-software-development-center-in-dublin/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I got a call from the Gilt Groupe in NYC and they asked, if I would be interested in joining Gilt Groupe to build a software development center in Dublin. I went to NY and met some of the brightest engineers in the industry and was totally blown away by the enthusiasm and the commitment to build and run the best e-commerce shopping experience on the web.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maven, Flex/Air and Android - Trinity or Bermuda Triangle</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/12/19/maven-flex/air-and-android-trinity-or-bermuda-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/12/19/maven-flex/air-and-android-trinity-or-bermuda-triangle/</guid>
      <description>Partially for professional reasons, partially out of plain, naked, old-fashioned curiosity (and also triggered by the Adobe announcement that Adobe Air now runs on Android) I am currently looking to find out how to use Maven to build a Flex/Air application for the Android phone. And ... it is not this easy. I am now working on this for a couple of weeks (elapse time that is - CPU time probably more 16 hours).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AquaEmacs and JDEE and Method Completion - Cannot find JDK&#39;s tools jar file (or equivalent)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/11/24/aquaemacs-and-jdee-and-method-completion-cannot-find-jdks-tools-jar-file-or-equivalent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/11/24/aquaemacs-and-jdee-and-method-completion-cannot-find-jdks-tools-jar-file-or-equivalent/</guid>
      <description>Hhhmmm ... nerd alert: If you do not like AquaEmacs, JDEE and Method Completion ... don&#39;t read this :).&#xA;Otherwise ... good news: Not sure, if you have stumbled over this, but if you try to make your method completion work you might get an error message along the lines of ... Cannot find JDK&#39;s tools jar file (or equivalent). Type M-x describe-function [RET] jde-get-jdk-dir for more info.&#xA;... when you hit C-c C-v .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cinema Screening in Aid of Haiti - Watching &#34;The Commitments&#34; (for a good cause)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/08/31/cinema-screening-in-aid-of-haiti-watching-the-commitments-for-a-good-cause/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/08/31/cinema-screening-in-aid-of-haiti-watching-the-commitments-for-a-good-cause/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it is possible to combine something that is fun with something that is useful.&#xA;I am happy to present such an opportunity, since my colleague Susan O&#39;Hara is organizing a charity event in the Sugar Club on Lower Leeson Street to watch &#34;The Commitments&#34; on Wednesday, 15 September 2010 at 7pm.&#xA;The cost is EUR 15,- pp. The feeling to have some fun and do something good is priceless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy, Mastery, Purpose - ... or ... how to unleash creativity.</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/06/08/autonomy-mastery-purpose-...-or-...-how-to-unleash-creativity./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/06/08/autonomy-mastery-purpose-...-or-...-how-to-unleash-creativity./</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a short blog post. A Facebook post by Brian Kelly made me revisit the stuff that Dan Pink did and is doing.&#xA;The main idea behind Drive (RSA, TED) is that Autonomy, Mastery and Purpose unleash the creative power of individuals and teams, not material/monetary incentives. Opensource and Wikipedia and ... are obviously the classic/legendary examples for this FACT (and yes, it is a fact :)).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing complexity with OSGi - In bundles and between bundles</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/22/managing-complexity-with-osgi-in-bundles-and-between-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/22/managing-complexity-with-osgi-in-bundles-and-between-bundles/</guid>
      <description>Right now the Brandvis SelectPortal system is based on Microsoft .NET and we constantly improve it and add features. While we do this we also constantly refactor the system to eliminate complexity to make it easier to maintain/extend.&#xA;Triggered by this work and triggered by a talk on reuse of OSGi bundles that I attended a couple of years ago, I started to think about complexity again. The main conclusion of that thought process is that there is probably an optimal (means minimal) complexity for any given system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Conference on Mass Customization and Personalization in Central Europe (MCP-CE 2010)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/07/international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe-mcp-ce-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/07/international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe-mcp-ce-2010/</guid>
      <description>Good news :). My talk on ...&#xA;About the importance of templates and platforms for &#34;managed customization&#34; in the garment industry&#xA;The garment industry is not only looking for a solution to address the increasing demand for customized product solutions for end-customers. As with other industries the solution/approach must take a more hollistic view to also cater for a wider variety of legal (certification) and manufacturing (small batches, short leadtime) requirements (&#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bierdeckel Economics vs. Armchair Economics - ... and what it got to do with Greece and Ireland</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</guid>
      <description>As most of you know, I am married to a greek woman and life in Ireland. Therefore the current economic crisis is omnipresent in my life.&#xA;A couple of weeks ago Chris Horn posted an interesting article about certain economical key indicators and what they mean for Ireland. I also saw a good article in the NYT about why and how the US and Ireland and Greece are different (from a financial crises/debt point of view).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greek Vacation - Food for thought</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/02/17/greek-vacation-food-for-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/02/17/greek-vacation-food-for-thought/</guid>
      <description>It is happening again :). I am in Greece ... on vacation. My wife has this unbelievable ability to find wonderful places for us to explore and experience the best of Greece. The (non-complete) list of breaks encompasses ... Visit the home of Zeus (Mount Olympus) (Mountain Resort Semeli)Find out how colosal the Colossus of Rhodes really was (Fashion Hotel Nikos)Take a 6 hour hike through Vikos Canyon Explore the beauty of PiliouFollow the footsteps of Leonard Cohen on Hydra (Four Seasons Hotel)Right now I am in the middle of nowhere in a place called Epohes and again .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link of the Month - The best Zoom feature ever</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/12/16/link-of-the-month-the-best-zoom-feature-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/12/16/link-of-the-month-the-best-zoom-feature-ever/</guid>
      <description>The frontend for many mass-customization, product-configurators is based on Adobe Flash/Flex, but as we all know, a fool with a tool is still a ... and therefore there are lots of examples out there where the design and implementation of the UI leaves &#34;room for improvement&#34;.&#xA;At the same there are also examples of very clever and thought-through UI design/implementation. One example in this category is the website for the movie &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass-customization delivered - Back to the roots ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</guid>
      <description>20 years ago I started my career as a Technical Project Manager/Lead Architect for EDS and was working on Bill-of-Material solutions for the Automotive Industry (e.g. Opel).&#xA;During my self-declared summer-sabbatical, I was musing over what I want to do next and felt that (if possible) I would like to work again in a business domain and (if possible) maybe (again) in manufacturing.&#xA;I am happy to report that it worked out just fine!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Android - Using Apache CXF to access SOAP services</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/09/21/effective-android-using-apache-cxf-to-access-soap-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/09/21/effective-android-using-apache-cxf-to-access-soap-services/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I developed a small set of demos to show how to access SOAP services from the iPhone. To do this I used a very interesting feature of Apache CXF: The ability to generate a complete JavaScript client-side SOAP-stack on the fly.&#xA;I just finished an update/upgrade of this demo to show that it also works with the Android Phone. I also ported it to maven, means installing, building and running the demo is much easier now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Networking - Updating your status: all or nothing?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/09/17/social-networking-updating-your-status-all-or-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/09/17/social-networking-updating-your-status-all-or-nothing/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was stumbling over a Facebook status update from Oisin Hurley ...&#xA;Oisin Hurley is starting to get a bit irritated with people that unselectively duplicate their twitter stream to their Facebook status. They&#39;re different interactions, people.&#xA;This is an interesting observation and creates a bigger question: where do we go with this social-networking, micro-blogging, status-update thingy? Initially it was easy: there was just/only twitter and this was the place to do micro-blogging and status-updates, but by now all social-networking sites (Facebook, Linked-In, XING, Plaxo, Bebo, .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Using TimeMachine Part II or Why Restore was greyed out?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/09/12/effective-mac-using-timemachine-part-ii-or-why-restore-was-greyed-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/09/12/effective-mac-using-timemachine-part-ii-or-why-restore-was-greyed-out/</guid>
      <description>It happened again!!! Another HD crash. A year ago I lost my original 160GB drive and replaced it with a 250GB drive. Now this one failed only 12 month later. I am not sure what is happening here, but I do not feel that I &#34;mishandle&#34; my MacBook in a way that would explain this rate of failure. Let me know, what your experience is. Are MacBooks DiskEaters? Anyway .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACCU 2009 - Slides are available</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/20/accu-2009-slides-are-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/20/accu-2009-slides-are-available/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I attended ACCU 2009 to deliver a talk on &#34;RESTful Services and Distributed OSGi - Friends or Foes&#34; and &#34;AJAX for Mobile Devices - Using Apache Projects to get the job done&#34;. The conference was very well organized (thanks Giovanni) and took place in the beautiful city of Oxford. The format (keynote presentations and smaller breakout sessions) allowed for a good mix of thought-provoking presentations and good discussions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Street Performance World Championship - a non-technical blog post</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/19/street-performance-world-championship-a-non-technical-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/19/street-performance-world-championship-a-non-technical-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Sorry - this is a non-technical blog post. If you are not interested in having a good time, stop reading now. Otherwise ...&#xA;I am on the LUAS on the way home from the Street Performance World Championship in Dublin.&#xA;All of the performances are good/funny, but my personal favorite are Alakazam and Mr. Toons.&#xA;Go and check it out. It is worth-while the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading books - Steve Jobs, Raising Boys and The Complete Robot</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/18/reading-books-steve-jobs-raising-boys-and-the-complete-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/18/reading-books-steve-jobs-raising-boys-and-the-complete-robot/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I decided to use some of my time during the summer and work my way through the pile of books that I always wanted to read and never really got to. The first four weeks proofed to be interesting, very interesting.&#xA;I started with &#34;ICon: The Greatest Second Act in the History of Business&#34;. It is obviously a biography about Steve Jobs, but it is also a good book on the history of Apple, the Silicon Valley, Next, Disney and Pixar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Energy - let&#39;s bring Smart Meters, Smart Grid, Micro Grid and the software behind it together</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/18/smart-energy-lets-bring-smart-meters-smart-grid-micro-grid-and-the-software-behind-it-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/18/smart-energy-lets-bring-smart-meters-smart-grid-micro-grid-and-the-software-behind-it-together/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I had a couple of pints with Dan Salt (Chief Software Architect at GE Energy) and we discussed the current state of affairs with respect to IT and Software Architectures/Solutions in the Energy/Utility sector. As a result I started to develop an interest in Smart Meter (just watch the first 5 min), Smart Grid, Micro Grid and Grid 2.0 concepts/solutions.&#xA;Here is a summary of the problems as I see them .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEDx Dublin - Reviewing a very nice friday evening</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/18/tedx-dublin-reviewing-a-very-nice-friday-evening/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/18/tedx-dublin-reviewing-a-very-nice-friday-evening/</guid>
      <description>Last friday (means already almost a week ago) I had the chance to attend the first TEDx event in Dublin at the Science Gallery. To make a long story short ... it was a GREAT event. Great people, great presentations, great location. If you ever get the chance to attend a TEDx event or maybe even to attend a TED conference ... DO IT!!!&#xA;Just in case you have never heard about TED I suggest you check out the website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSEforge Lightsaber/Lightsabre - Research on Asynchronous Distributed OSGi (for Jedi&#39;s :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/09/fuseforge-lightsaber/lightsabre-research-on-asynchronous-distributed-osgi-for-jedis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/09/fuseforge-lightsaber/lightsabre-research-on-asynchronous-distributed-osgi-for-jedis/</guid>
      <description>The Distributed OSGi spec (RFC 119) is coming along nicely, means now might be a good time to raise the head and start to think about what might come next. A couple of month ago David, Roman and myself got together and concluded to set up a research project on the alternatives available to potentially extend the Distributed OSGi spec with some asynchronous messaging concepts/capabilities.&#xA;The research is still ongoing, but the intermediate results (including a first demo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skills, Innovation and the future of Ireland - Bermuda Triangle or Trinity</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Ireland (like any other country in the world right now) needs to reinvent itself. The Celtic Tiger (1.0) is over. Question is: What&#39;s next? Do we want a Celtic Tiger 2.0? If so, how should it look like? And how do we make it happen?&#xA;Chris Horn has published a couple of interesting blog entries and articles on the topic.&#xA;For me the key is skills and innovation. Skill comes in two flavors: expertise and experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Android - Getting Started Guide for the Android Dev Phone 1</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/05/28/effective-android-getting-started-guide-for-the-android-dev-phone-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/05/28/effective-android-getting-started-guide-for-the-android-dev-phone-1/</guid>
      <description>This week I spend a day to get my new Android Phone up and running.&#xA;At the end I figured it might make sense to write up a cookbook on what to do when you finally get your hands on the box and unwrap your new toy. Here we go ...&#xA;The (ultimate :)) Android Getting Started Guide (for Mac Users :)) First things first: This guide assumes that you got yourself an Android Dev Phone 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Andriod - a new category</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/05/27/effective-andriod-a-new-category/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/05/27/effective-andriod-a-new-category/</guid>
      <description>Last year I introduced categories like &#34;Link of the Month&#34; and &#34;Effective Mac&#34; to my blogging&#34;. Heads up ... there is a new category coming: Effective Android will talk about my adventures with my new Android phone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Make the Mac listen ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/05/18/effective-mac-make-the-mac-listen-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/05/18/effective-mac-make-the-mac-listen-.../</guid>
      <description>This morning I was using my new JawBone Bluetooth headset to make a Skype call. The quality was bad and therefore I decided to switch to my headset. The result was better, but still not what I was looking for. At the end I took the time to really understand, where the sound is coming from and to my big surprise I found out that the line-in jack is not working with normal headsets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Need a new phone - iPhone vs. Blackberry vs. Android</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/05/18/need-a-new-phone-iphone-vs.-blackberry-vs.-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/05/18/need-a-new-phone-iphone-vs.-blackberry-vs.-android/</guid>
      <description>Last year I went hill-walking with Andrew and Adrian in Kerry. By now everybody knows the story: I drowned my iPhone in Adrian&#39;s backpack. The backpack was 100% water-proof, means it did not let any water out and at the end of a 4 1/2 hour (irish) survival tour with heavy, &#34;horizontal&#34; rain the iPhone did not pass the &#34;can-your-iPhone-also-work-under-water&#34; test.&#xA;I decided to look at it as an opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrating the orchestration - EIP vs. BPEL vs. BPML</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/23/orchestrating-the-orchestration-eip-vs.-bpel-vs.-bpml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/23/orchestrating-the-orchestration-eip-vs.-bpel-vs.-bpml/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally (and in any case not often enough) I am having diner or lunch (or any another excuse) to meet my dear friend Klaus Grieger. He is a Principal Architect with CIMT AG. Klaus is what I would call a &#34;deep thinker&#34;. Discussions with him are in between interesting, challenging, invigorating and exhausting :).&#xA;The topic of the Christmas Lunch (we had the choice between &#34;The best Worscht in Town&#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Open Source for Apache Projects - Survival of the fittest</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/22/commercial-open-source-for-apache-projects-survival-of-the-fittest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/22/commercial-open-source-for-apache-projects-survival-of-the-fittest/</guid>
      <description>Just found another company offering commercial support for Apache ServiceMix and Apache ActiveMQ (like we do :)). For me this is good news. It shows that more and more people use Apache integration projects in mission-critical deployment scenarios. And that these deployments generate enough value for customers to warrant an &#34;insurance&#34; against worst-case scenarios. For me it was never the goal to be the only company to offer consulting, training and support for Apache integration projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Sleeping on the plane</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/10/effective-mac-sleeping-on-the-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/10/effective-mac-sleeping-on-the-plane/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, I &#34;borrowed&#34; the battery from Christina&#39;s MacBook to extend my &#34;life&#34;, while I am on the plane. The Mac (being the Mac) has a nice feature, which will hibernate the machine when the battery gets low. This allows you to change the battery without rebooting.&#xA;I was looking for a way to hibernate the machine on demand. This is also useful if you want to conserve battery power (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Update - Apache Con, Java Days and ACCU</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/04/conference-update-apache-con-java-days-and-accu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/04/conference-update-apache-con-java-days-and-accu/</guid>
      <description>It seems over Christmas a lot of people did what I did: Clean up the Todos, catch up on EMail and get ready for 2009. As a side effect my colleagues and I (the Open Source Center of Competence in Progress) got notifications from various conference committees that our speaking proposals got accepted.&#xA;* Andreas and Adrian will talk/present at ApacheCon 2009 in Amsterdam (NL)* David will talk/present at the Italian JavaDays 2009 in Rome (IT)* And myself will talk/present at ACCU 2009 in Oxford (UK)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Using OpenOffice, NeoOffice and/or iWorks08</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/04/effective-mac-using-openoffice-neooffice-and/or-iworks08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/04/effective-mac-using-openoffice-neooffice-and/or-iworks08/</guid>
      <description>Finally! OpenOffice is now available for the Mac. In the last two month I used OpenOffice 3.0, NeoOffice 2.2.5 and iWorks08 in parallel (with a special focus on the presentation functionality).&#xA;The result is surprising (and maybe not :)). If you use the &#34;native&#34; formats (e.g. ODF, .key/.page) everything works fine. Obviously things get more interesting, if you want to use these tools to read and write MS-Office files (.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link of the Month - TwitterFeed</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/12/28/link-of-the-month-twitterfeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/12/28/link-of-the-month-twitterfeed/</guid>
      <description>In the last two month I have put some work into my online presence (website, blog, twitter, linked-in, ...). Obviously I try to minimize the maintenance effort for me, but maximize the user experience for the &#34;customers&#34; of my online presence (I am talking about you, dear reader :)). One great tool in this regard is TwitterFeed. It allows you to create &#34;feeds&#34;, which will &#34;listen&#34; on RSS feeds and will then turn them into tweets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache CXF vs. Axis 2 - The current state of affairs or The missing book</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/12/07/apache-cxf-vs.-axis-2-the-current-state-of-affairs-or-the-missing-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/12/07/apache-cxf-vs.-axis-2-the-current-state-of-affairs-or-the-missing-book/</guid>
      <description>(Blogging from the plane again. This time on my way to the Progress Sales Kickoff in Miami.)The other day I stumbled over a good presentation&#xA;from Falko Riemenschneider. The high-level summary is ...&#xA;* Axis 2 is not as easy to use as CXF, but is more ubiquitous in the marketplace (and got better documentation, including a book in german)&#xA;* CXF is a very well developed piece of software, but needs more people using it (and needs more/better documentation, including a book in any language, but preferably in english)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSE on the german autobahn - listing to a CAOS podcast</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/11/25/fuse-on-the-german-autobahn-listing-to-a-caos-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/11/25/fuse-on-the-german-autobahn-listing-to-a-caos-podcast/</guid>
      <description>For private reasons I had/have to spend some time in Germany these days. The house of my parents is about 45 mins away from the office, means I get to listen to some podcasts while I am doing 160 miles/hour on the german autobahn. One of my favorite podcasts is the CAOS Theory podcast from the 451 Group.&#xA;Yesterday I was listening to one that discussed the current state of affairs with respect to the Open Source Middleware space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSE Quickstart - a sneak preview</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/11/14/fuse-quickstart-a-sneak-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/11/14/fuse-quickstart-a-sneak-preview/</guid>
      <description>Yes, we are busy to add new content to FUSEsource :). First we published a/the first set of FUSE TV videos and next we are going to publish a set of &#34;FUSE Quickstart&#34; screen casts. Take a look at the sneak preview and/or wait for the high-res versions to become available on FUSEsource later on this month.&#xA;Tip/Hint: The best way to get the sneak preview is to subscribe to the podcast and download all videos into iTunes :).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Core Licensing - moving from &#34;bait-and-switch&#34; to &#34;suggest-and-complement&#34;</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/11/11/open-core-licensing-moving-from-bait-and-switch-to-suggest-and-complement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/11/11/open-core-licensing-moving-from-bait-and-switch-to-suggest-and-complement/</guid>
      <description>The Open Core Licensing discussion is really refreshing! Lots of good ideas and lots of good energy. Obviously the &#34;earlier&#34; versions of the model were more oriented towards a &#34;bait-and-switch&#34; approach (get a good stack for free, but then if you want to do real/serious enterprise computing, you have to to buy the real thing :)). Right now the models have evolved into more mature &#34;suggest-and-complement&#34; models (aka. Open Core Licensing).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Marketing - and what it got to do with the Michelin brothers</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/11/11/open-source-marketing-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-the-michelin-brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/11/11/open-source-marketing-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-the-michelin-brothers/</guid>
      <description>Open Core Licensing and the business model behind it is not (really) new. When you look at it from a history/marketing point of view there are lots of examples, where money is/was made with a &#34;handle-blade&#34; model.&#xA;From a marketing point of view the most famous example is probably Gillette. They give away the handles and make a lot of money with the blades. This works because they have a very strong brand and because they &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMQP for dummies - A guide for managers</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/28/amqp-for-dummies-a-guide-for-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/28/amqp-for-dummies-a-guide-for-managers/</guid>
      <description>(I start to like this &#34;plane blogging&#34; thing :))Adrian blogged about Microsoft embracing AMQP.&#xA;Just from a technical point of view this is good news (assuming it will help the adoption of the Advanced Message Queueing Protocol (AMQP)), because AMQP is a very cool (and extremely well thought through) standard.&#xA;Given that there might be a renewed interest in the standard, let me just try to explain (again) what it is good for: The main benefit of AMQP (besides a couple of very cool features in the standard itself) is that it will (finally and for the first time) allow messaging stacks to interoperate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Networking - Del.icio.us rediscovered! or Do we need the Open Social API?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/28/social-networking-del.icio.us-rediscovered-or-do-we-need-the-open-social-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/28/social-networking-del.icio.us-rediscovered-or-do-we-need-the-open-social-api/</guid>
      <description>(Blogging from a plane en-route from DUB to BOS using the email interface of blogger.com :))The other day I updated my website with the details of my new employer and decided to give a second live to my del.icio.us account by using one of the widgets to include my reading list on my blog. I also had to decide, which of my social networks I reference on my site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link of the Month - FUSE TV</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/22/link-of-the-month-fuse-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/22/link-of-the-month-fuse-tv/</guid>
      <description> Great new content. Check out FUSEsource.com! 4 weeks ago we huddled in our &#34;new&#34; HQ in Bedford for Managment Meetings (and other fun :)). Debbie had the great idea to take advantage of our presence there and record a first set of FUSE TV sessions. Great fun! Check out the result.&#xA;And yes mea culpa, &#34;aaaeeeehhhhhhmmmm&#34; is not a german word. No Oscar for me (this time :)). </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link of the Month - FUSE is moving on ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/18/link-of-the-month-fuse-is-moving-on-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/18/link-of-the-month-fuse-is-moving-on-.../</guid>
      <description>... to FUSEsource.com. As part of the Progress acquisition we decided to change the host/domain name of the FUSE community website from open.iona.com to FUSEsource.com.&#xA;I like the new name better, because what we do here is not about a company (be it IONA or Progress). It is about a project. In our case FUSE.&#xA;The renaming will also allow us to role out more interesting stuff in the near future on a new, consistent family of good host/domain names.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone screen - Is it a problem or a solution?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/05/the-iphone-screen-is-it-a-problem-or-a-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/05/the-iphone-screen-is-it-a-problem-or-a-solution/</guid>
      <description>Lot&#39;s of interesting exciting stuff is going to happen with FUSE over the next couple of month. Especially on the tooling side. The other day I was riding in the car with Oisin Hurley (Head of Tool Development for FUSE) and we discussed the value of having NOT a lot of screen real-estate, because it really makes you think about what the problem is the user wants/needs to solve and how you can guide the user through that process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complex Event Processing - An exiting (new) frontier</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/05/complex-event-processing-an-exiting-new-frontier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/05/complex-event-processing-an-exiting-new-frontier/</guid>
      <description>Through the merger (:)) with Progress, I got exposed to the new exciting field of (Real-Time) Complex Event Processing (CEP). There are a couple of obvious use cases in finance (e.g. algorithmic stock trading) and manufacturing (e.g. detecting possible problems in the assembly line, which might effect your just-in-time service-level-agreements).&#xA;Complex Event Processing or Intelligent Event Correlation is not what excites me. That was/is also possible using large data-warehouses and suitable data-mining solutions, but then you learn about it after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Using Time Maschine</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/30/effective-mac-using-time-maschine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/30/effective-mac-using-time-maschine/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday at 08:00am it happend to me. I move/dragged an email into a folder on my Mac and the machine froze. Diagnosis: Catastrophic harddisk failure. But hey ... look at the bright side: I got to replace my 160GB disk with a bigger 250GB disk and got to test, if my Time Machine backup really works.&#xA;And there is where the problem starts. In an ill-conceived effort to minimize the disk space and the time I need for my backup, I excluded all directories besides my &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Open-Source Mac</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/10/effective-mac-open-source-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/10/effective-mac-open-source-mac/</guid>
      <description> Was looking for an opensource search engine for the Mac and found this interesting website. I am already using half of the apps, but will take a look at the other half too :). </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - Growl back to work</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/07/effective-mac-growl-back-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/07/effective-mac-growl-back-to-work/</guid>
      <description>Stumbled over James&#39;s blog entry about useful software for the Mac and added Growl to my list of software that you need have/use to be effective, but was not able to make it work with X-Chat (AquaChat). Confronted with the option to figure out what is wrong or to try something new, I took the easy way out: I tried Colloquy. This worked out of the box. I know need to find out how to make my Twitter tweeds show up in Growl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Business Models - Open-Core Licensing</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/02/open-source-business-models-open-core-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/02/open-source-business-models-open-core-licensing/</guid>
      <description>OH NO, please!!! YABOOSBM!!! Yet another blog entry on open-source business models :).&#xA;Ok, let&#39;s make it as short and as sweet as possible :).&#xA;This morning I was reading Matt Aslett&#39;s comment on Andrew Lampitt&#39;s blog entry on &#34;Open-Core&#34; licensing (which actually contains a link to a good presentation by MySQL chief Marten Mickos).&#xA;What I like about the approach is that it tries to take the emotion out of the discussion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Innovation - Fact or Fiction</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/open-source-innovation-fact-or-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/open-source-innovation-fact-or-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Is Open Source Innovation an oxymoron? Is Open-source fostering innovation or killing it?&#xA;There are two school of thoughts out there: First, there are lots of people, who say that open-source is not fostering innovation or even killing it, because it is just about the reimplementation of already solved problems and that it actually kills innovation, because it keeps people from implementing solutions that can not be protected from being reimplemented as an open-source solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solid State Disks - Level 5 cache</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/solid-state-disks-level-5-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/solid-state-disks-level-5-cache/</guid>
      <description>Last month I had the pleasure to spend 2 hours in the car with Klaus Grieger. Klaus and myself know each other from ObjectDesign and Versant. Right now he is a partner with CIMT AG in Germany. As always talking to him was invigorating. He is one of the most innovative people I know.&#xA;The topic of the drive was the future of Solid State Disks (SSDs). His thought was/is that with the arrival of in-expensive, fast SSDs we can potentially rethink the way we structure memory and storage in general.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Software Engineering - Can we avoid another software crisis</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/12/embedded-software-engineering-can-we-avoid-another-software-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/12/embedded-software-engineering-can-we-avoid-another-software-crisis/</guid>
      <description>The term &#34;software crisis&#34; was coined 1968 by F.L. Bauer during the first NATO Software Engineering Conference in Garmisch, Germany and was used by Dijkstra in his very famous lecture on &#34;The humble programmer&#34;:&#xA;[The major cause of the software crisis is] that the machines have become several orders of magnitude more powerful! To put it quite bluntly: as long as there were no machines, programming was no problem at all; when we had a few weak computers, programming became a mild problem, and now we have gigantic computers, programming has become an equally gigantic problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randy Pausch - about elephants, walls, rooms and TVs</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/04/randy-pausch-about-elephants-walls-rooms-and-tvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/04/randy-pausch-about-elephants-walls-rooms-and-tvs/</guid>
      <description>Last week Randy Pausch died. With all the hype around his cancer and &#34;the last lecture&#34;, it was/is kind of hard to see who he was or what he was. Yesterday I tried to find out a little bit more and watched his presentation on time management. Good presentation, but not something that we haven&#39;t heard before. In the end I have to agree with him: He is a smart professor, but there are lots of smart professors out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESTful Services - Dana Gardner, Adrian Trenaman, Roland Tritsch - wrapping it up</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/16/restful-services-dana-gardner-adrian-trenaman-roland-tritsch-wrapping-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/16/restful-services-dana-gardner-adrian-trenaman-roland-tritsch-wrapping-it-up/</guid>
      <description> The Webinar went very well. I think we had over 50 poeple that showed up. The archived webinar and the source code will be available on open.iona.com.&#xA;Check it out. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - call me slow</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/12/effective-mac-call-me-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/12/effective-mac-call-me-slow/</guid>
      <description> You can call me slow, but it took me only a year to find the RSS reader that everybody else is using. David Greco finally pointed me to NetNewsWire. This seems to be it :). </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link of the month - Google Twitter (GTwit)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/07/link-of-the-month-google-twitter-gtwit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/07/link-of-the-month-google-twitter-gtwit/</guid>
      <description>Micro-blogging (Twitter, Pounce, Facebook, ...) just go a little bit easier. Check out GTwit. It is a light-weight Google App, that allows you to access your Twitter account from any browser you might have access to. It is based on the Twitter API. It stores all tweets that you send/receive in a private &#34;Google-Cloud&#34; and allows you to search on them by whatever you like (word, person, tag).&#xA;Check it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone - and what you can learn from thinking about it</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/05/the-iphone-and-what-you-can-learn-from-thinking-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/05/the-iphone-and-what-you-can-learn-from-thinking-about-it/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the driving range and while Alexandros was working on my early retirement plan (aka. he making lots of money with golf and I am managing his career), I was reading an article on Businessweek about the new iPhone 3G contracts. The article made me think again. It made me think about two presentations that I saw recently: One by Michael Crossey from Aepona at the Mobile Monday in Belfast and the other one by Peter Moeckel from T-Labs (the R&amp;amp;D think-tank of Deutsche Telekom) at the OSGi community event in Berlin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Mac - the beginning of a journey</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/effective-mac-the-beginning-of-a-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/effective-mac-the-beginning-of-a-journey/</guid>
      <description>yesterday i finally finished my upgrade to Mac OS X 10.5 (Leopard).&#xA;overall it went well. i did an erase and install (as a 20 year windows user i feel much more comfortable with clean installs. maybe next time if will try it the mac-way :)) and also used the exercise to clean up my disk and the way i work. the biggest problem was that leopard does not come with iLife, means you need to find your old tiger CDs and reinstall iLife from there (or buy (!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Payment - what is needed</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/mobile-payment-what-is-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/mobile-payment-what-is-needed/</guid>
      <description>in the last 4 weeks, i was talking to sailesh panchal (Enterprise Architect - Payments at Lloyds TSB) and hermann sauer (EDS - Integration Engineering Lead EMEA North/Central) about the future of mobile payment.&#xA;there is clearly a need and a benefit to find a solution, but implementations are not available yet (leaving aside lots of POCs that are out there). one obvious driver is the need to find a replacement for cheque payments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2008 OSGi Community Event - talking about trains</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/23/2008-osgi-community-event-talking-about-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/23/2008-osgi-community-event-talking-about-trains/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I attended the OSGi Community Event in Berlin.&#xA;One of the presentations was from Deutsche Bahn about their new Mobile Integration Platform (MIP). It was not only in this presentation that I felt that OSGi has become the ICE of deployment platforms. A 300 km/h high-speed trend/train with a lot of momentum. Think about it: Do you want to be on the train or in front of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering Radio - talking about OSGi, Rest, Opensource, ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/23/software-engineering-radio-talking-about-osgi-rest-opensource-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/23/software-engineering-radio-talking-about-osgi-rest-opensource-.../</guid>
      <description>In the last four weeks a lot of people asked me about this &#34;show&#34; I am listening to on my way to work. It is called Software Engineering Radio and talks about trends and technologies in Software Engineering (OSGi, Rest, Opensource, ...). I was told that one of the next issues will be an interview with Peter Kriens on the current state of affairs with respect to OSGi.&#xA;Check it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESTful Services - Dana Gardner, Adrian Trenaman, Roland Tritsch</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/17/restful-services-dana-gardner-adrian-trenaman-roland-tritsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/17/restful-services-dana-gardner-adrian-trenaman-roland-tritsch/</guid>
      <description> Everybody is talking about REST. We do too :).&#xA;Join us on July, 15th for this existing Webinar on REST and RESTful Services. Will include a live demo of a RESTful iPhone integration.&#xA;CU there. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation on Innovation - How to make elephants dance</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went out and had a pint with Sailesh Panchal. He is an Enterprise Architect with the payments division of Lloyds TSB in London. Part of his responsibility is to foster innovation in Lloyds. Obviously innovation needs to be directed towards a measurable goal/target/impact for the customer and/or the company. To judge, if an/the idea was just a good idea or a real innovation, you must be able to show some measurable ROI in a defined timeframe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSE Master Class Series - Hidden Gem</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/23/fuse-master-class-series-hidden-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/23/fuse-master-class-series-hidden-gem/</guid>
      <description> A couple of weeks ago, I published the first 3 videos of the FUSE Master Class Series on the open.iona.com wiki. Sooner or later we might link to it from the top page, but for the time being they are hidden gems :). The videos are also available from my homepage. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link of the month - TwitterFone</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/link-of-the-month-twitterfone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/link-of-the-month-twitterfone/</guid>
      <description> Just updated the Link of the Month. It now points to TwitterFone (by Dial2Do). Cool stuff. Traffic in Dublin is a nightmare. Means I am walking a lot. This is the way to Twitter, while you walk (or drive).&#xA;Very innovative. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Monday in Belfast - WebServices to foster innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to-foster-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to-foster-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Monday evening I spent in Belfast at the Mobile Monday, presenting on &#34;How to access WebServices from the iPhone&#34; (pictures are available upon request :)).&#xA;Good event. We had 30 people in the room. Good format. Four short presentations with good networking before and after the talks. My favorite presentation was Michael Crossey from Aepona, talking about &#34;Exploiting Telco Asserts through Telecom WebServices&#34;. One interesting point that he raised is that Mobile Telecom Operators are currently challenged (or even threatend) by &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sensoric revolution - iPhone/Chumby integration</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/the-sensoric-revolution-iphone/chumby-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/the-sensoric-revolution-iphone/chumby-integration/</guid>
      <description>The embedded/mobile software market is growing faster than the rest of the industry. From my point of view this just the tip of the iceberg, because we are at the beginning of the sensoric revolution. Historically all data got created in the &#34;middle&#34; and we used integration technologies to distribute the data. Web 1.0 turned out to become the preferred mechanism to get this done and we changed the content/data in the middle through the web (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complexity explained simple - Ciaran McHale talks about security</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/20/complexity-explained-simple-ciaran-mchale-talks-about-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/20/complexity-explained-simple-ciaran-mchale-talks-about-security/</guid>
      <description>Just finished a/the review of a great presentation on security and security concepts published by Ciaran McHale on www.ciaranmchale.com.&#xA;His claim is that 80% of the the perceived complexity of any given subject is not in the concept, but in the way it is explained to people. His quest is to fix this. Therefore he has started to publish a series of very well written presentations to introduce technical concepts in the most simple way possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Leap</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/18/quantum-leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/18/quantum-leap/</guid>
      <description>Today we went to a local art (flee) market. We were looking for some paintings for our new house. At the end we could not agree on anything, but I was in the right mindset to find something that will focus the mind, when I am at my desk.&#xA;I like innovation and I like to innovate. Sometimes this requires to take a leap of faith to produce a quantum leap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Monday</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/13/mobile-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/13/mobile-monday/</guid>
      <description>Got invited to talk at the Mobile Monday Series in Belfast.Looks interesting/promising. Will publish a post lateronnext week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Colossus of Rhodes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</guid>
      <description>Now. Lets get things started. Lets talk about innovation. for a well-known reason (at least) once a year i am in greece. this year we also went to rhodos to see the colossus. question is: was this innovation? i mean, is it innovative to come up with the idea to build something like the colossus?&#xA;what is the nature of innovation? how is it for instance different from creativity?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache-CXF generates client-side SOAP stack for the iPhone</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/04/13/apache-cxf-generates-client-side-soap-stack-for-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/04/13/apache-cxf-generates-client-side-soap-stack-for-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Yep. It was inevitable. Sooner or later we need to talk about the iPhone.&#xA;And there is a lot to talk about ... the innovative hardwarethe business model behind itthe market this device might be able to createand a lot of other disruptive changes that come with itBut today I just want to talk about a neat feature that I discovered in Apache-CXF.&#xA;In January I was looking for ways to make the mobile device a first-class citizen in a distributed SOA.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
