<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mass-Customization on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/mass-customization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mass-Customization on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 16:11:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/mass-customization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Conference on Mass Customization and Personalization in Central Europe (MCP-CE 2010)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/07/international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe-mcp-ce-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/07/international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe-mcp-ce-2010/</guid>
      <description>Good news :). My talk on ...&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the importance of templates and platforms for &#34;managed customization&#34; in the garment industry&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;The garment industry is not only looking for a solution to address the increasing demand for customized product solutions for end-customers. As with other industries the solution/approach must take a more hollistic view to also cater for a wider variety of legal (certification) and manufacturing (small batches, short leadtime) requirements (&#34;managed customization&#34;).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;The proposed paper will suggest a software-based approach and will discuss the experience with respect to the relevance of templates and platforms for the given solution.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;... was accepted. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://mass-customization.blogs.com/mass_customization_open_i/2010/01/call-for-papers-international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe.html&#34;&gt;conference&lt;/a&gt; will happen on Sep., 22nd-24th 2010 in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Novi_Sad&#34;&gt;Novi Sad, Serbia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;CU there :).&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass-customization delivered - Back to the roots ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;20 years ago I started my career as a Technical Project Manager/Lead Architect for EDS and was working on Bill-of-Material solutions for the Automotive Industry (e.g. Opel).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;During my self-declared summer-sabbatical, I was musing over what I want to do next and felt that (if possible) I would like to work again in a business domain and (if possible) maybe (again) in manufacturing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I am happy to report that it worked out just fine!&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A couple of month ago I was approached by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brandvis.com/&#34;&gt;Brandvis Ltd&lt;/a&gt; and they were looking for a Chief Architect with manufacturing background to help them with the implementation of their next-generation mass-customization platform. For the time being the platform is targeted at the garment industry (or to be precise at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-visibility_clothing&#34;&gt;high-visible, high-performance, technical workwear&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_protective_equipment&#34;&gt;Personal Protective Equipment (PPE)&lt;/a&gt;). The Brandvis Software Solution allows you to customize these garments and (if necessary) certify the garments (in real-time) against the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-visibility_clothing#BS_EN_471:2003&#34;&gt;relevant standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The software that is behind the solution needs to be tightly integrated with underlying Bill-of-Material information and also with the Supply-Chain that is driving the manufacturing process. What we (Brandvis) have right now is a good start, but lots remains to be done. I am really looking forward to the adventure of building this.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Ultimately/Potentially the Brandvis Solution might evolve into a general-purpose solution to deliver on the promises of the holy-grail of manufacturing: the implementation of a general-purpose &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mass_customization&#34;&gt;mass-customization&lt;/a&gt; solution.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mass-customization is a very interesting and exciting concept and you can expect that I will start to talk about it more on this blog.  &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
