<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:37:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Augmented Software Engineer - What is it?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>Updated &amp;hellip;&#xA;2024-11-08: Added section at the end on published and planned episodes 2024-11-19: Added episode 3-5 2024-11-25: Added episode 6 I can hear you loud and clear &amp;hellip;&#xA;Ooohhh my god: Not another blog post about AI!!!&#xA;Bear with me. I will try to make reading it (or watching it) worth while your time. I promise.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s set the stage. My opinion is &amp;hellip;&#xA;The planet has problems (over-population, climate-change, poverty and economic inequality, cancer and alzheimer, &amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IOM TT 2024 - History was made</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/06/01/iom-tt-2024-history-was-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/06/01/iom-tt-2024-history-was-made/</guid>
      <description>Ok, here comes an odd one &amp;hellip;&#xA;This one is not about software-technologies or software-engineering or software-craftmanship or management or leadership.&#xA;This is about another passion of mine: Motorbikes and motorbike racing. Specifically road-racing.&#xA;For those of you who know nothing about road-racing and want to learn and understand more I recommend to watch Road.&#xA;The exec summary is that all racing started on open, public roads. Later purpose build tracks started to emerge and are obviously the much safer option to conduct a race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Software Gardening Manifesto - A copy</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/07/01/the-software-gardening-manifesto-a-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/07/01/the-software-gardening-manifesto-a-copy/</guid>
      <description>In case the Software Gardening Manifesto is down or otherwise not available, here is a copy of it &amp;hellip;&#xA;SOFTWARE GARDENING MANIFESTO Software Gardeners are professionals who perceive software development in a different way. Our goal is to spread the word of our core values, be mentors for the new developers and create software that it is developed at the highest quality bar.&#xA;Every software gardener believes and embraces the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Blogging - The Art of Prompting</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/augmented-blogging-the-art-of-prompting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/augmented-blogging-the-art-of-prompting/</guid>
      <description>This is a landmark blog post. I just introduced a tag called Augmented-by-AI. And this post is tagged with it.&#xA;This is going to be the new normal. Let me explain &amp;hellip;&#xA;First things first: This blog post is not written by chatGPT.&#xA;It is Sunday morning, 6am and I am sitting here in my living room in my PJ with a cup of coffee and I am typing this. Believe me &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pillars of a sustainable energy future - A fireside chat</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is interesting in more than one way, because &amp;hellip;&#xA;I am going to discuss a topic that is deer to my heart: What do we need to do to get to a better place with respect to a sustainable energy future? And I am going to use a new approach: Where I am first going to articulate my thoughts and then I am going to complement it with a fireside chat that I had with chatGPT about the topics at hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal Team Player - HHS vs. DAC</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/02/10/the-ideal-team-player-hhs-vs.-dac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/02/10/the-ideal-team-player-hhs-vs.-dac/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Lencioni (obviously) wrote The Five Dysfunctions of a Team.&#xA;In that book we learn that the five dysfunctions you need to avoid are &amp;hellip;&#xA;Absence of trust — unwilling to be vulnerable within the group Fear of conflict — seeking artificial harmony over constructive passionate debate Lack of commitment — feigning buy-in for group decisions creates ambiguity throughout the organization Avoidance of accountability — ducking the responsibility to call peers, superiors on counterproductive behavior which sets low standards Inattention to team results — focusing on personal success, status and ego before team success I always try to frame these in positive/actionable terms by asking people to help me to build teams that show/exhibit the following characteristics &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can we afford to be surprised? - &#34;Hot, hot, hot&#34;</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/01/14/can-we-afford-to-be-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/01/14/can-we-afford-to-be-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</guid>
      <description>6 years ago I wrote a blog post to express that my wife loves me for a lot of different reasons and that there is no reason to be surprised about the climate change that we are experiencing.&#xA;Note: If you do not know, why there is a picture of a microwave here, you need to read the first blog post.&#xA;I am compelled to write about it again.&#xA;Mainly because it did not get better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy new year - I am tooting now ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/01/01/happy-new-year-i-am-tooting-now-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/01/01/happy-new-year-i-am-tooting-now-.../</guid>
      <description>Happy new year to ya all!!!&#xA;What a year it has been. Some of the highlights are &amp;hellip;&#xA;In February I spend a week with the European Community Engineers in Lisbon/Portugal for the first (actually the second) EMEA tribe meeting after the pandemic In June I spend a week with Christina in London to deliver a talk on Micros-Services &amp;amp; Event-Based Systems In August I spend 3 weeks on the Isle Of Man to attend the Manx GP and (finally) got my TT Race Course Marshall certification In May I Went do the US for 3 weeks to attend the US east/west coast tribe meetings &amp;hellip; and had to isolate for 10 days because I got Covid (but got a good sunrise out of it) We continue to do Innovation-Weeks at Community :) &amp;hellip; I really enjoyed working as a Staff-Director here at Community (I get to do all (or at least a lot of) the good/interesting stuff) Installed a stove at home and bought one(solo) for the mobile office Spend a week in county Donegal (working remote) Spend a week in county Clare (working remote) using the most remote co-working space in Ireland Had two weeks of outstanding boating again (no remote working; just vacation :)) Doing (another) 100 day walking challenge Got a full-body check-up done (first after 6 years).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is better than Remote-First 1.0? Remote-First 2.0!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/07/04/what-is-better-than-remote-first-1.0-remote-first-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/07/04/what-is-better-than-remote-first-1.0-remote-first-2.0/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I got my second jab. I am fully vaccinated now. I am now in Germany to see my parents for the first time in 12 month.&#xA;Yes: It is finally happening! The pandemic (slowly, but surely) comes to an end.&#xA;Which creates (for some of us and for some companies) a big question: What&amp;rsquo;s the next step? What&amp;rsquo;s the path forward (e.g. from a organisational structure/development point of view)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of the pandemic - Social Media Edition</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/10/the-end-of-the-pandemic-social-media-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/10/the-end-of-the-pandemic-social-media-edition/</guid>
      <description>Now it is (almost) official: The pandemic is over (or is coming to an end fast/soon). In the next couple of days I am going to get my second shoot. Last week I was staying for 5 days in River Valley Holiday Park (first time in 12 month that I was able to do a multi-day_trip with the TEDN van). And next week I am going to Germany (and I am going to stay there for a month).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distances - Know them. Manage them.</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</guid>
      <description>Building and managing remote-first organizations means that you also need to understand (and manage) distances!&#xA;To develop your ability to understand and manage distances is very important because human beings naturally need closeness (to other people and/or the purpose of the endeavor) to feel a sense of belonging.&#xA;But &amp;hellip; wait a sec: What do you mean by distances (plural)? Is there more than one?&#xA;Big surprise: Yes! When I build and run remote-first organizations I worry about and manage at least the following distances &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(The Extreme) 100 Day Walking Challenge</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/the-extreme-100-day-walking-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/the-extreme-100-day-walking-challenge/</guid>
      <description>In January I had a good call with my friend Braggy in Sydney. The insight was, that 2020 was different to what I/we expected, but with 20/20 hint-sight it was not necessarily a bad a year (at least not for me).&#xA;The pandemic forced me to question what I am doing and why I am doing it and how I am doing it in a lot of interesting ways. I will always remember 2020 as a year where I grew a lot, albeit in unexpected ways/directions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s a Staff Director?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</guid>
      <description>Community is growing fast.&#xA;More business. More customers. More people. More money. More (necessary) complexity (software and people).&#xA;The demand for this kind of growth can create a lot of interesting strains, problems and challenges.&#xA;In situations like this it is easy to end up between a rock and a hard place: Grow fast and run a/the risk that the growing pains will kill you or end up being too slow to fully capitalize on the magnitude of the opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland ... what&#39;s in a name</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/13/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/13/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>Updated: On Oct., 11th, 2020 Updated: On Apr., 12th, 2020 Updated: On Oct., 29th, 2016&#xA;A couple of years ago a colleague of mine pointed me to the new website/book from Jim Carrey &amp;ldquo;How Roland rolls&amp;rdquo; and while looking at it I started to think about my name: What does it mean? What is the origin? What are other well-known usages?&#xA;Here is what I found out &amp;hellip; Roland was a knight who fought for Charles the Great (also called the father of Europe).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The American election ... 1 year after</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</guid>
      <description>The dust has settled. All opinions have been voiced. All articles have been written. Not quite &amp;hellip; here is another one :).&#xA;I am struggling with Donald Trump and his character and his personality and his opinions. A lot!&#xA;And what do to next depend first of all on, if you believe that there is a problem or not and what that problem is. It then comes down to what to do to fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am a lucky guy :) ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it takes a while to get to it &amp;hellip;&#xA;Last year I was opening Data-by-the-Bay and was welcoming/addressing the attendees. Wanted to turn it into a blog post and never got around to do it. Finally &amp;hellip; here we go &amp;hellip;&#xA;Good morning everybody. On behalf of Nitro: Welcome to Data by the Bay.&#xA;My name is Roland Tritsch and I am German and I am the VP Engineering at Nitro.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting GTD done - Thoughts and Tools</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>We all have a lot to do. Effective time/task management is essential. I’ve been using GTD (Getting Things Done) for a while now (a long while :)) and for me it comes down to the question, “How do you pick the next, best, most valuable thing to work on?”—basically answering the question of how to make the best use of the time you have.&#xA;Picking something from your list of urgent things to do is kind of easy, but how can you make sure you are not missing the opportunity/chance to work on something important, if you get the chance to do so?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About broken windows and software gardening ... - Thoughts from The Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/02/16/about-broken-windows-and-software-gardening-...-thoughts-from-the-pragmatic-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/02/16/about-broken-windows-and-software-gardening-...-thoughts-from-the-pragmatic-programmer/</guid>
      <description>These days I am writing more source code again (mostly Scala) and decided to (re)read a couple of books to refresh some thoughts and ideas and believes that I always had when it comes to writing source code.&#xA;One of the books I was (re)reading was Clean Code and there are lots of good ideas in it, e.g. after reading the book 15 years ago I got into the habit of refactoring, whenever I feel the urge to put a comment in the code, which is an indication that the code is not clear/self-documenting enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing - A practical guide for the common user</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/05/01/cloud-computing-a-practical-guide-for-the-common-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/05/01/cloud-computing-a-practical-guide-for-the-common-user/</guid>
      <description>These days (and especially after the Amazon EC2 outage :)) everybody is talking about cloud computing. It seems you cannot be sexy, if you do not &#34;live&#34; in the cloud. But most of the more &#34;common&#34; users (and for the sake of the discussion, I am including myself in that group) probably think that cloud computing and using &#34;the cloud&#34; is something that enterprises use to (potentially) safe cost and also to (potentially) gain flexibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing complexity with OSGi - In bundles and between bundles</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/22/managing-complexity-with-osgi-in-bundles-and-between-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/22/managing-complexity-with-osgi-in-bundles-and-between-bundles/</guid>
      <description>Right now the Brandvis SelectPortal system is based on Microsoft .NET and we constantly improve it and add features. While we do this we also constantly refactor the system to eliminate complexity to make it easier to maintain/extend.&#xA;Triggered by this work and triggered by a talk on reuse of OSGi bundles that I attended a couple of years ago, I started to think about complexity again. The main conclusion of that thought process is that there is probably an optimal (means minimal) complexity for any given system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bierdeckel Economics vs. Armchair Economics - ... and what it got to do with Greece and Ireland</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</guid>
      <description>As most of you know, I am married to a greek woman and life in Ireland. Therefore the current economic crisis is omnipresent in my life.&#xA;A couple of weeks ago Chris Horn posted an interesting article about certain economical key indicators and what they mean for Ireland. I also saw a good article in the NYT about why and how the US and Ireland and Greece are different (from a financial crises/debt point of view).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
