<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The end of the pandemic - Social Media Edition</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/10/the-end-of-the-pandemic-social-media-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/10/the-end-of-the-pandemic-social-media-edition/</guid>
      <description>Now it is (almost) official: The pandemic is over (or is coming to an end fast/soon). In the next couple of days I am going to get my second shoot. Last week I was staying for 5 days in River Valley Holiday Park (first time in 12 month that I was able to do a multi-day_trip with the TEDN van). And next week I am going to Germany (and I am going to stay there for a month).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distances - Know them. Manage them.</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</guid>
      <description>Building and managing remote-first organizations means that you also need to understand (and manage) distances!
To develop your ability to understand and manage distances is very important because human beings naturally need closeness (to other people and/or the purpose of the endeavor) to feel a sense of belonging.
But &amp;hellip; wait a sec: What do you mean by distances (plural)? Is there more than one?
Big surprise: Yes! When I build and run remote-first organizations I worry about and manage at least the following distances &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(The Extreme) 100 Day Walking Challenge</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/the-extreme-100-day-walking-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/the-extreme-100-day-walking-challenge/</guid>
      <description>In January I had a good call with my friend Braggy in Sydney. The insight was, that 2020 was different to what I/we expected, but with 20/20 hint-sight it was not necessarily a bad a year (at least not for me).
The pandemic forced me to question what I am doing and why I am doing it and how I am doing it in a lot of interesting ways. I will always remember 2020 as a year where I grew a lot, albeit in unexpected ways/directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s a Staff Director?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</guid>
      <description>Community is growing fast.
More business. More customers. More people. More money. More (necessary) complexity (software and people).
The demand for this kind of growth can create a lot of interesting strains, problems and challenges.
In situations like this it is easy to end up between a rock and a hard place: Grow fast and run a/the risk that the growing pains will kill you or end up being too slow to fully capitalize on the magnitude of the opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roland ... what&#39;s in a name</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/13/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/13/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>Updated: On Oct., 11th, 2020 Updated: On Apr., 12th, 2020 Updated: On Oct., 29th, 2016
A couple of years ago a colleague of mine pointed me to the new website/book from Jim Carrey &amp;ldquo;How Roland rolls&amp;rdquo; and while looking at it I started to think about my name: What does it mean? What is the origin? What are other well-known usages?
Here is what I found out &amp;hellip;  Roland was a knight who fought for Charles the Great (also called the father of Europe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American election ... 1 year after</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</guid>
      <description>The dust has settled. All opinions have been voiced. All articles have been written. Not quite &amp;hellip; here is another one :).
I am struggling with Donald Trump and his character and his personality and his opinions. A lot!
And what do to next depend first of all on, if you believe that there is a problem or not and what that problem is. It then comes down to what to do to fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a lucky guy :) ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it takes a while to get to it &amp;hellip;
 Last year I was opening Data-by-the-Bay and was welcoming/addressing the attendees. Wanted to turn it into a blog post and never got around to do it. Finally &amp;hellip; here we go &amp;hellip;

Good morning everybody. On behalf of Nitro: Welcome to Data by the Bay.
My name is Roland Tritsch and I am German and I am the VP Engineering at Nitro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting GTD done - Thoughts and Tools</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>We all have a lot to do. Effective time/task management is essential. I’ve been using GTD (Getting Things Done) for a while now (a long while :)) and for me it comes down to the question, “How do you pick the next, best, most valuable thing to work on?”—basically answering the question of how to make the best use of the time you have.
Picking something from your list of urgent things to do is kind of easy, but how can you make sure you are not missing the opportunity/chance to work on something important, if you get the chance to do so?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About broken windows and software gardening ... - Thoughts from The Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/02/16/about-broken-windows-and-software-gardening-...-thoughts-from-the-pragmatic-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/02/16/about-broken-windows-and-software-gardening-...-thoughts-from-the-pragmatic-programmer/</guid>
      <description>These days I am writing more source code again (mostly Scala) and decided to (re)read a couple of books to refresh some thoughts and ideas and believes that I always had when it comes to writing source code.
One of the books I was (re)reading was Clean Code and there are lots of good ideas in it, e.g. after reading the book 15 years ago I got into the habit of refactoring, whenever I feel the urge to put a comment in the code, which is an indication that the code is not clear/self-documenting enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing - A practical guide for the common user</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/05/01/cloud-computing-a-practical-guide-for-the-common-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/05/01/cloud-computing-a-practical-guide-for-the-common-user/</guid>
      <description>These days (and especially after the Amazon EC2 outage :)) everybody is talking about cloud computing. It seems you cannot be sexy, if you do not &#34;live&#34; in the cloud. But most of the more &#34;common&#34; users (and for the sake of the discussion, I am including myself in that group) probably think that cloud computing and using &#34;the cloud&#34; is something that enterprises use to (potentially) safe cost and also to (potentially) gain flexibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing complexity with OSGi - In bundles and between bundles</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/22/managing-complexity-with-osgi-in-bundles-and-between-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/22/managing-complexity-with-osgi-in-bundles-and-between-bundles/</guid>
      <description>Right now the Brandvis SelectPortal system is based on Microsoft .NET and we constantly improve it and add features. While we do this we also constantly refactor the system to eliminate complexity to make it easier to maintain/extend.Triggered by this work and triggered by a talk on reuse of OSGi bundles that I attended a couple of years ago, I started to think about complexity again. The main conclusion of that thought process is that there is probably an optimal (means minimal) complexity for any given system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bierdeckel Economics vs. Armchair Economics - ... and what it got to do with Greece and Ireland</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</guid>
      <description>As most of you know, I am married to a greek woman and life in Ireland. Therefore the current economic crisis is omnipresent in my life.
A couple of weeks ago Chris Horn posted an interesting article about certain economical key indicators and what they mean for Ireland. I also saw a good article in the NYT about why and how the US and Ireland and Greece are different (from a financial crises/debt point of view).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
