<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/categories/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tedn.life/categories/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a lucky guy :) ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/18/i-am-a-lucky-guy-.../</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it takes a while to get to it &amp;hellip;
 Last year I was opening Data-by-the-Bay and was welcoming/addressing the attendees. Wanted to turn it into a blog post and never got around to do it. Finally &amp;hellip; here we go &amp;hellip;

Good morning everybody. On behalf of Nitro: Welcome to Data by the Bay.
My name is Roland Tritsch and I am German and I am the VP Engineering at Nitro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning ... and beyond - RRRs from the Deep Learning Summit 2016 in London</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/09/23/deep-learning-...-and-beyond-rrrs-from-the-deep-learning-summit-2016-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/09/23/deep-learning-...-and-beyond-rrrs-from-the-deep-learning-summit-2016-in-london/</guid>
      <description>I am just back from the Deep Learning (DL) Summit in London, where I had very interesting 2 days with a lot of good presentations and a lot of time to think about the future.
I am working with Nitro for a year now and have learned a lot about Machine Learning (ML) and Natural Language Processing (NLP), but as always: the more you learn, the more you understand that you know nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Conference on Mass Customization and Personalization in Central Europe (MCP-CE 2010)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/07/international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe-mcp-ce-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/07/international-conference-on-mass-customization-and-personalization-in-central-europe-mcp-ce-2010/</guid>
      <description>Good news :). My talk on ...

About the importance of templates and platforms for &#34;managed customization&#34; in the garment industry

The garment industry is not only looking for a solution to address the increasing demand for customized product solutions for end-customers. As with other industries the solution/approach must take a more hollistic view to also cater for a wider variety of legal (certification) and manufacturing (small batches, short leadtime) requirements (&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>