<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:42:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The pillars of a sustainable energy future - A fireside chat</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is interesting in more than one way, because &amp;hellip;&#xA;I am going to discuss a topic that is deer to my heart: What do we need to do to get to a better place with respect to a sustainable energy future? And I am going to use a new approach: Where I am first going to articulate my thoughts and then I am going to complement it with a fireside chat that I had with chatGPT about the topics at hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can we afford to be surprised? - &#34;Hot, hot, hot&#34;</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/01/14/can-we-afford-to-be-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/01/14/can-we-afford-to-be-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</guid>
      <description>6 years ago I wrote a blog post to express that my wife loves me for a lot of different reasons and that there is no reason to be surprised about the climate change that we are experiencing.&#xA;Note: If you do not know, why there is a picture of a microwave here, you need to read the first blog post.&#xA;I am compelled to write about it again.&#xA;Mainly because it did not get better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy new year - I am tooting now ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/01/01/happy-new-year-i-am-tooting-now-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/01/01/happy-new-year-i-am-tooting-now-.../</guid>
      <description>Happy new year to ya all!!!&#xA;What a year it has been. Some of the highlights are &amp;hellip;&#xA;In February I spend a week with the European Community Engineers in Lisbon/Portugal for the first (actually the second) EMEA tribe meeting after the pandemic In June I spend a week with Christina in London to deliver a talk on Micros-Services &amp;amp; Event-Based Systems In August I spend 3 weeks on the Isle Of Man to attend the Manx GP and (finally) got my TT Race Course Marshall certification In May I Went do the US for 3 weeks to attend the US east/west coast tribe meetings &amp;hellip; and had to isolate for 10 days because I got Covid (but got a good sunrise out of it) We continue to do Innovation-Weeks at Community :) &amp;hellip; I really enjoyed working as a Staff-Director here at Community (I get to do all (or at least a lot of) the good/interesting stuff) Installed a stove at home and bought one(solo) for the mobile office Spend a week in county Donegal (working remote) Spend a week in county Clare (working remote) using the most remote co-working space in Ireland Had two weeks of outstanding boating again (no remote working; just vacation :)) Doing (another) 100 day walking challenge Got a full-body check-up done (first after 6 years).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The American election ... 1 year after</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</guid>
      <description>The dust has settled. All opinions have been voiced. All articles have been written. Not quite &amp;hellip; here is another one :).&#xA;I am struggling with Donald Trump and his character and his personality and his opinions. A lot!&#xA;And what do to next depend first of all on, if you believe that there is a problem or not and what that problem is. It then comes down to what to do to fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bierdeckel Economics vs. Armchair Economics - ... and what it got to do with Greece and Ireland</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/04/04/bierdeckel-economics-vs.-armchair-economics-...-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-greece-and-ireland/</guid>
      <description>As most of you know, I am married to a greek woman and life in Ireland. Therefore the current economic crisis is omnipresent in my life.&#xA;A couple of weeks ago Chris Horn posted an interesting article about certain economical key indicators and what they mean for Ireland. I also saw a good article in the NYT about why and how the US and Ireland and Greece are different (from a financial crises/debt point of view).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
