<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDN - The most important tool ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; is the laptop? No (but more on this later)!
&amp;hellip; is the mobile phone (with good 4G coverage)? No (and again &amp;hellip; more on this later)!
&amp;hellip; is a foldable coffee mug!!!
 When you start to work remote (from home, from any place, &amp;hellip;) you will discover that you will end up in coffee shops (either because you want to (because you want/need to fight the cabin fever) or because you have to (because you want/need to find/have a WLAN connection)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the right thing ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/03/19/do-the-right-thing-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/03/19/do-the-right-thing-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>I am driving an electric car. It is a great experience. Not to a small part, because the Irish government is trying very hard to make it a good experience. Government grants, good infrastructure, friendly people.
The other day, I noticed something that leaves room for improvement. On a Sunday afternoon, I was charging my car at the quick charger at the LUAS station in Stillorgan. The parking lot is operated by NCPS and has signs on the ground and on sign-posts to indicate that the spaces are reserved for electric vehicle (EV) charging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Range anxiety? What range anxiety! (My first road trip with the BADMobile :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/05/20/range-anxiety-what-range-anxiety-my-first-road-trip-with-the-badmobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/05/20/range-anxiety-what-range-anxiety-my-first-road-trip-with-the-badmobile/</guid>
      <description>In case you are wondering ... this is the BADMobile ... (ask me, if you want :)) ...

My friend Klaus and myself have spend more time and more miles (on motorbike(s)) together than we care to count. And the pattern is that once in a while we need to do something crazy. This time around we decided that in the next 5 years we will visit all of the major road races in the UK &amp;amp; Ireland (at least) once.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>