<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMQP on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/amqp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AMQP on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/amqp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting to RabbitMQ with AMQP in Elixir</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/10/26/reconnecting-to-rabbitmq-with-amqp-in-elixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/10/26/reconnecting-to-rabbitmq-with-amqp-in-elixir/</guid>
      <description>Updated (2022-01-01): Added stage.
At Community we are building a platform that will allow you to have meaningful conversations with large audiences &amp;hellip; at scale!!!
The architectural backbone is a shared-nothing micro-services architecture, that uses an event-bus for state propagation.
To avoid any kind of 2-phase-commit shenanigans we are publishing events at-least-once (not exactly-once). That means our services need to be able to and are able to deal with dublicated events gracefully (by ignoring them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMQP for dummies - A guide for managers</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/10/28/amqp-for-dummies-a-guide-for-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/10/28/amqp-for-dummies-a-guide-for-managers/</guid>
      <description>(I start to like this &#34;plane blogging&#34; thing :))Adrian blogged about Microsoft embracing AMQP.
Just from a technical point of view this is good news (assuming it will help the adoption of the Advanced Message Queueing Protocol (AMQP)), because AMQP is a very cool (and extremely well thought through) standard.
Given that there might be a renewed interest in the standard, let me just try to explain (again) what it is good for: The main benefit of AMQP (besides a couple of very cool features in the standard itself) is that it will (finally and for the first time) allow messaging stacks to interoperate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
