<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 04:25:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Augmented Software Engineer - What is it?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Updated &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-11-08: Added section at the end on published and planned episodes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-11-19: Added episode 3-5&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-11-25: Added episode 6&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-11-28: Added episode 7-10&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-12-23: Added episode 11-13&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-01-26: Added episode 14&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024-02-27: Added episode 15-17&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can hear you loud and clear &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ooohhh my god: Not another blog post about AI!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bear with me. I will try to make reading it (or watching it) worth&#xA;while your time. I promise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Blogging - The Art of Prompting</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/augmented-blogging-the-art-of-prompting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/04/09/augmented-blogging-the-art-of-prompting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a landmark blog post. I just introduced a tag called&#xA;&lt;code&gt;Augmented-by-AI&lt;/code&gt;. And this post is tagged with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tedn.life/images/2023-04-09-augmented-blogging/roland.jpg&#34;&#xA;style=&#34;float:right; margin:auto&#34; width=&#34;20%&#34; hspace=&#34;5%&#34; vspace=&#34;1%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is going to be the new normal. Let me explain &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first: This blog post is not written by &lt;code&gt;chatGPT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is Sunday morning, 6am and I am sitting here in my living room in&#xA;my PJ with a cup of coffee and I am typing this. Believe me &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pillars of a sustainable energy future - A fireside chat</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/03/12/the-pillars-of-a-sustainable-energy-future-a-fireside-chat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is interesting in more than one way, because &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am going to discuss a topic that is deer to my heart: What do we&#xA;need to do to get to a better place with respect to a sustainable&#xA;energy future?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And I am going to use a new approach: Where I am first going to&#xA;articulate my thoughts and then I am going to complement it with a&#xA;fireside chat that I had with &lt;code&gt;chatGPT&lt;/code&gt; about the topics at hand.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here we go &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Pair Programming - Innovation-Week Q2/2022</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2022/05/01/emacs-pair-programming-innovation-week-q2/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2022/05/01/emacs-pair-programming-innovation-week-q2/2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We (at Community) just had another &lt;a href=&#34;https://tedn.life/2021/02/12/the-first-summit/hack-a-thon-community/&#34;&gt;Innovation-Week&lt;/a&gt;. I was actually working on generating &lt;a href=&#34;https://pactflow.io&#34;&gt;pact-files&lt;/a&gt; from frontend code and then generating &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/open-api-spex/open_api_spex&#34;&gt;openapi spec files from elxir backend code&lt;/a&gt; and then automatically check that the frontend pact is compatible with the backend openapi spec while running the build pipeline for the frontend(s)/backend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But this is not what this blog post is all about :).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While working on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/geoff-smith-46739188&#34;&gt;Geoff&lt;/a&gt; and myself also decided that it is a good opportunity to sharpen the tools and take remote-first pair-programming to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gilt CIO talks ... about innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</guid>
      <description>From an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.logicworks.net/blog/2013/09/cloud-player-steve-jacobs-cio-gilt-groupe-part-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gilt.com/company/bio/steve-jacobs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Steve&lt;/a&gt;. Too good not to turn it into a blog post ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#34;When people talk about innovation they are often talking about the solution to some problem. But the real source of innovation is figuring out what the right problem is to solve. Take Gilt for example: Gilt took the invite only friends &amp;amp; family sample sale invite that existed for coveted brands in cities like New York and moved that model online. &amp;nbsp;This allowed consumers all over the US to have access to designer apparel and accessories for a short period of time, similar to a two day offline sample sale, and it allowed the brands to have another outlet to sell end of season merchandise. &amp;nbsp;Gilt was perfectly positioned to meet both the brand’s needs and the customer’s needs. The identification of the problem is the hardest part. The solution, once you’ve identified the problem, tends to be pretty easy. If you give any set of engineers a problem, they’ll figure out a solution with confidence. But really, picking which problems to go after in a world of limited resources is where the magic of innovation happens. I think often times people focus on a solution or cool technology that’s really innovative, but it’s only innovative if it solves a substantial problem.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;True, true, true, ... let&#39;s continue to find and pick the right problems!!!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dublin Innovation Festival - Talking about Innovation, Gilt and Ireland ... and Evolution and Darwinism</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-SKu1QBbZHOw/Ts5wRNhbAPI/AAAAAAAAAUQ/n0NNY_QoLzE/s1600/Diversity_Matters_photo_without_wording_.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;A couple of weeks ago I had the chance to talk about three things I care about: Innovation, Gilt and Ireland. The occasion was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.innovationdublin.ie/festival/2011/view_event/ID259/&#34;&gt;Dublin Chamber of Commerce Smart Series Event on Innovation&lt;/a&gt; (that was the day after Dundrum Shopping Center and half of Dublin got &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_OWG_XjmLNQ&#34;&gt;flooded&lt;/a&gt;). The objective was to share a couple of thoughts on what innovation is (or is not), what Gilt is doing to foster innovation and what Ireland has to offer to companies like Gilt.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;To start ... Innovation is probably on all our minds. If you get it right as an individual or as a company or as a country, you create a differentiator for yourself. Everybody wants to be innovative. The main point of the talk was to point out the &lt;b&gt;similarities between innovation and evolution.&lt;/b&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 133px; height: 200px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8gs1e4uZGog/TrhNBkJH6cI/AAAAAAAAAR0/U9s3UzZ1fp8/s200/sally-gap-wicklow-county-ireland-r115-21222196.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5672368419950291394&#34; /&gt;There are lots of definitions available, but one way to think about innovation is in terms of the hard and the brain. The hard tells us that innovation is this wonderful thing that happens in the shower or in my case on the bike on the way up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mapmyride.com/s/routes/view/bike-ride-map/ireland/kildare/885363&#34;&gt;Sally Gap&lt;/a&gt;, when you have this moment of brilliance for the next best, bigger business idea that will actually change the world. And then we look at individuals like Steve Jobs, who are obviously either showering a lot or who know the way up to Sally Gap like the back of their hands, because it seems they innovate everyday and we start to wonder what is wrong with us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The short answer is actually: nothing. Nothing, because in my opinion it does not work this way. Even in the case of the iPod you could argue that the real innovation was the Sony Walkman and the iPod was a refinement on the original idea.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 156px; height: 200px;&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NIH8w4fcdYs/TrhN7Hxmd_I/AAAAAAAAASA/Y2-ppMip7Cs/s200/charles_darwin_01.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5672369408767850482&#34; /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The more rational definition behind innovation is that innovation is not a thing or an event that &#34;happens&#34;. It is the result of a process. I am personally a big fan of evolution and Darwinism. There is only so much you can plan and/or foresee. For the rest you have to try (a lot) and see what works. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;That sounds easy, but it isn&#39;t, because it is counterintuitive. You have to embrace mutation and selection. You first have to create a &#34;creative&#34; environment that produces a lot of (hopefully) good, new ideas and then you have to filter them and needs to happen early, because being innovative does not mean to be just creative. It means to be successful and that means it is not about creating a lot of good, new ideas, it is also about finding the ones that make a difference for your business and for your customers and if your are lucky for your industry.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Not to a small extend it is this “bi-polar” nature of innovation that makes it difficult for us to implement innovation. Just think about it: On one hand you ask people to mutate (means to come up with a lot of good, new ideas) and to be passionate about these ideas and then you need to have strong selection in place to kill most of them. If you do it wrong it will frustrate people, because they might get the impression that nobody is listening and innovation will just stop to happen.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;In a lot cases we fail to get good innovation because we either mutate too much and do not select enough or the other way around. Good innovative environments show both characteristics: A lot of mutation and strong selection. &lt;b&gt;Innovation is the evolution of ideas. It is Darwinism of ideas. It is the survival of the fittest idea.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;To create such an environment and to maybe avoid the frustration mentioned above, you should reward people equally for coming up with an idea and also for giving up on an idea. Failure must become an option and maybe even something that you should or could celebrate.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Let&#39;s talk about Gilt. Gilt is innovative. Let me talk about two examples that will illustrate how innovation based on strong selective pressure  (means a well-defined niche that you need to adapt to) and/or strong mutation (means a good idea) can look like.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zhsSpr5dwtw/TrhPSKiDnyI/AAAAAAAAASM/9jrn5zHvyo0/s200/Hackathon.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5672370904156577570&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 146px; &#34; /&gt;The first example I want to talk about is inventory management. Normal retail business models allow you to do inventory management based on thresholds, means as soon as your inventory goes beyond a certain threshold you reorder. When you reorder has something to do with your lead times and also with the quality of your inventory management, means you actually do not care, if there is a little bit more or little bit less in stock, as long as you never run out of stock.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Gilt business model requires a totally different approach. Because in most cases we are selling excess stock, 80% of all products we have ever sold we have sold only once, means we never really can reorder and that &lt;b&gt;means we are in the business of selling down to the very last unit. Always!!!&lt;/b&gt; And we need to do that while we maintain highest possible availability and scalability. To deliver on these business requirements we had to question conventional wisdom and build a very innovative inventory management runtime platform, based on highly available and highly scalable NoSQL databases that actually relax some of the transactional ACID properties, but still allows us to sell down to the very last unit. And we succeeded. That’s an example for innovation out of necessity to adapt to a niche.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The second example for an innovation at Gilt is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xna2YVgXY7c&#34;&gt;360 degree &#34;look-around&#34; Jetsetter iPad app.&lt;/a&gt; The application allows you to take a 360 degree view of a room and explore literally every ankle of it. This is an example for a strong mutation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Gilt is still a very young company, means we are still learning how to institutionalize innovation in the company, but so far I believe that the 3 pillars of innovation in Gilt are &lt;b&gt;people, process and culture. &lt;/b&gt;You need people that are creative and intelligent. You need a process that is open and transparent. And you need a culture that equally celebrates success and failure.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;In that context we are experimenting with &#34;Unstructured Time&#34; where we bring people together without an agenda. We also believe that a lot of good ideas will not come from us, but from outside the company and in that context we are currently building a public API that we will expose to partners and other interested parties, so that they can innovate independently from us. Earlier this year we did a &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/2011/03/09/technology/hackathons/index.htm&#34;&gt;hackathon&lt;/a&gt; and had the entire SW development organization on the hunt for the next better idea and also prove it (within 24 hours). Our &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gilt-on-the-go/id331804452?mt=8&#34;&gt;color search feature&lt;/a&gt; (which allows you to take a picture of a color and search for similar products) and the public API were actually incubated in the hackthon. We are also doing a lot of A/B testing to measure the &#34;goodness&#34; of our ideas. This allows us to rationalize the conversation about the value of certain ideas. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;But there is always more to do. Right now, we are thinking about a &#34;follow-the-sun&#34; hackathon were global teams will implement something over a period of three days, because we are suspicious that some good ideas, will get conceived, when people from different cultural backgrounds work together, means it is not only about creativity and intelligence, but also about heterogeneity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 200px; height: 165px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-SKu1QBbZHOw/Ts5wRNhbAPI/AAAAAAAAAUQ/n0NNY_QoLzE/s200/Diversity_Matters_photo_without_wording_.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5678599621150703858&#34; /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Let me wrap up, by exploring that thought more. &lt;b&gt;It is my believe that culturally diverse, cultur&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;ally heterogeneous environments are more likely to be innovative than homogeneous environments.&lt;/b&gt; If you also believe in the value of heterogeneity than there is good news, because the Irish software engineering population is among the most heterogeneous and diverse in Europe, maybe even in the world, means Ireland allows you to build teams that will look at problems and possible solutions in different/unique ways. They all went to different schools and had different experiences before they came to Ireland. This creates an environment for innovation to happen.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Ireland is the only English speaking country in the Eurozone. This makes it easy for talent to relocate to Ireland and to work here. Building an innovation hub will probably to a certain extend rely on our ability to take advantage of the talent in the rest of Europe and to use the heterogeneity and diversity that comes with it as a driver to build creative, innovative teams here in Ireland.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Gilt is very excited to be in Ireland. We are looking to use our presence here to build a stronger, more scalable, even more innovative Gilt Technologie Organisation.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventure 2.0 - Building the Gilt Software Development Center in Dublin</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/04/19/adventure-2.0-building-the-gilt-software-development-center-in-dublin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/04/19/adventure-2.0-building-the-gilt-software-development-center-in-dublin/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I got a call from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bx9WjvNGHPE&#34;&gt;Gilt Groupe in NYC&lt;/a&gt; and they asked, if I would be interested in joining Gilt Groupe to build a software development center in Dublin. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rolandtritsch/5508724707/in/set-72157626372178226&#34;&gt;I went to NY&lt;/a&gt; and met some of &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/video/technology/2011/03/08/t_tt_gilt_groupe_hackathon.cnnmoney/&#34;&gt;the brightest engineers in the industry&lt;/a&gt; and was totally blown away by the enthusiasm and the commitment to build and run the best e-commerce shopping experience on the web.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And here I am today sitting in a room with the Irish Finance Minister Michael Noonan &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.delicious.com/rolandtritsch/Gilt+Announcement&#34;&gt;announcing&lt;/a&gt; that Gilt is establishing its International HQ and a software development center in Dublin. And I can&#39;t tell you how exited I am about being part of that adventure.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gilt is the number one flash sales site in the US. Within 3 years they went from 0 to more than USD 400M in revenue. Flash sales is outlet shopping over the internet and allows large designer brands to get the best possible deal on their excess stock. And it is frantic. Gilt has close to 5M members and sends 3M emails every day (within 15 mins) to notify its members about upcoming sales events. The next day at noon(est) the sale goes live and it is first-come first-served on all kinds of goods from a wide variety of designer brands. The discounts are from 20 to (sometimes) over 70 percent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That presents a &#34;small&#34; technical challenge, because at noon within seconds the traffic on the website goes from decent to 5000 pages/sec. At peak time the site processes over USD 1M in revenue within 30 mins (every day). And it serves 99.7% of all pages, fully dynamic and personalized, within 100 ms at all times. And it cannot go down, meaning scalability, performance and availability are at the top of the requirements list. Fortunately Gilt employs only the brightest and the best.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let me know, if you are interest to join us. I am &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gilt.com/careers/tech/2011/04/14/dublin/?cat=dup&#34;&gt;hiring&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greek Vacation - Food for thought</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/02/17/greek-vacation-food-for-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/02/17/greek-vacation-food-for-thought/</guid>
      <description>It is happening again :). I am in Greece ... on vacation. My wife has this unbelievable ability to find wonderful places for us to explore and experience the best of Greece. The (non-complete) list of breaks encompasses ...&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visit the home of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zeus&#34;&gt;Zeus&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Olympus_(Mountain)&#34;&gt;Mount Olympus&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.semeliresort.gr/data/home.php?sl=US&#34;&gt;Mountain Resort Semeli&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find out how colosal &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colossus_of_Rhodes&#34;&gt;Colossus of Rhodes&lt;/a&gt; really&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; was (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikostakishotel.com/&#34;&gt;Fashion Hotel Nikos&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take a 6 hour hike through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/Vikos_Gorge&#34;&gt;Vikos Canyon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Explore the beauty of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pelion&#34;&gt;Piliou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Follow the footsteps of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonard_Cohen&#34;&gt;Leonard Cohen&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydra,_Saronic_Islands&#34;&gt;Hydra&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fourseasonshydra.gr/default.aspx?sector_id=187&amp;amp;lang_id=2&#34;&gt;Four Seasons Hotel&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Right now I am in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;ll=37.436158,21.948538&amp;amp;spn=0.019253,0.03798&amp;amp;z=15&amp;amp;msid=110664402557387540287.00047f9fba5998de94a20&#34;&gt;middle of nowhere&lt;/a&gt; in a place called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epohes.gr/default.asp?la=2&#34;&gt;Epohes&lt;/a&gt;  and again ... I am loving it. These trips are and the nature around me, put me into a very good, peaceful, thoughful frame of mind. Will send &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rolandtritsch/&#34;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; later this week.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Also assuming that the (deep) thinking will result in one (or two) blog entries :). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass-customization delivered - Back to the roots ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;20 years ago I started my career as a Technical Project Manager/Lead Architect for EDS and was working on Bill-of-Material solutions for the Automotive Industry (e.g. Opel).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;During my self-declared summer-sabbatical, I was musing over what I want to do next and felt that (if possible) I would like to work again in a business domain and (if possible) maybe (again) in manufacturing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I am happy to report that it worked out just fine!&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A couple of month ago I was approached by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brandvis.com/&#34;&gt;Brandvis Ltd&lt;/a&gt; and they were looking for a Chief Architect with manufacturing background to help them with the implementation of their next-generation mass-customization platform. For the time being the platform is targeted at the garment industry (or to be precise at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-visibility_clothing&#34;&gt;high-visible, high-performance, technical workwear&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_protective_equipment&#34;&gt;Personal Protective Equipment (PPE)&lt;/a&gt;). The Brandvis Software Solution allows you to customize these garments and (if necessary) certify the garments (in real-time) against the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-visibility_clothing#BS_EN_471:2003&#34;&gt;relevant standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The software that is behind the solution needs to be tightly integrated with underlying Bill-of-Material information and also with the Supply-Chain that is driving the manufacturing process. What we (Brandvis) have right now is a good start, but lots remains to be done. I am really looking forward to the adventure of building this.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Ultimately/Potentially the Brandvis Solution might evolve into a general-purpose solution to deliver on the promises of the holy-grail of manufacturing: the implementation of a general-purpose &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mass_customization&#34;&gt;mass-customization&lt;/a&gt; solution.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mass-customization is a very interesting and exciting concept and you can expect that I will start to talk about it more on this blog.  &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSEforge Lightsaber/Lightsabre - Research on Asynchronous Distributed OSGi (for Jedi&#39;s :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/09/fuseforge-lightsaber/lightsabre-research-on-asynchronous-distributed-osgi-for-jedis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/09/fuseforge-lightsaber/lightsabre-research-on-asynchronous-distributed-osgi-for-jedis/</guid>
      <description>The &lt;a href=&#34;http://cxf.apache.org/distributed-osgi.html&#34;&gt;Distributed OSGi spec (RFC 119)&lt;/a&gt; is coming along nicely, means now might be a good time to raise the head and start to think about what might come next. A couple of month ago &lt;a href=&#34;http://coderthoughts.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://romanroe.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;Roman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/&#34;&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt; got together and concluded to set up a research project on the alternatives available to potentially extend the Distributed OSGi spec with some asynchronous messaging concepts/capabilities.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The research is still ongoing, but the intermediate results (including a first demo!!!) are now available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://fusesource.com/forge/&#34;&gt;FUSEforge&lt;/a&gt; (Project &lt;a href=&#34;http://fusesource.com/forge/projects/LIGHTSABRE&#34;&gt;Lightsabre&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The demo will also be presented at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osgi.org/DevConEurope2009/HomePage&#34;&gt;OSGi DevCon Europe&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe (another) reason to attend. Enjoy and stay tuned.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skills, Innovation and the future of Ireland - Bermuda Triangle or Trinity</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Ireland (like any other country in the world right now) needs to reinvent itself. The Celtic Tiger (1.0) is over. Question is: What&#39;s next? Do we want a Celtic Tiger 2.0? If so, how should it look like? And how do we make it happen?&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chrishornat.blogspot.com/2009/01/innovation.html&#34;&gt;Chris Horn&lt;/a&gt; has published a couple of interesting blog entries and articles on the topic.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For me the key is skills and innovation. Skill comes in two flavors: expertise and experience. The Celtic Tiger 1.0 was based on expertise. At the time Ireland was building a very well educated workforce (Trinity College, UCD, University of Limerick, ... ) and was also enjoying (or creating) other (monetary) benefits (like low corporate taxes, low wages, lots of EU aids, ...).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celtic_Tiger&#34;&gt;These times are clearly over&lt;/a&gt; and Ireland has to find a new (the next) niche to compete in the global economy. My hope and my belief is that Ireland can reinvent itself around a different set of skills, namely the experience the workforce has gained in the last 10 years. Right now is the (a good) time to reinvent Ireland as a place, where small startups can flourish and succeed: A European (Software) Business Incubator.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lets make it happen.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Innovation - Fact or Fiction</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/open-source-innovation-fact-or-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/open-source-innovation-fact-or-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Is Open Source Innovation an oxymoron? Is Open-source fostering innovation or killing it?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are two school of thoughts out there: First, there are lots of people, who say that open-source is not fostering innovation or even killing it, because it is just about the reimplementation of already solved problems and that it actually kills innovation, because it keeps people from implementing solutions that can not be protected from being reimplemented as an open-source solution. Second there are at least as many people, who say that open-source is actually creating/fostering innovation, because a company can not hide behind a bad implementation and will always be forced to look for ways to make its solution better, faster and more affordable.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let&#39;s first contemplate on the nature of innovation. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/Blog/2008/04/colossus-of-rhodes.html&#34;&gt;previously discussed&lt;/a&gt; there is a difference between innovation and creativity: You can ask people to be creative, but you can&#39;t really ask them to be innovative, because innovation is something that get&#39;s established after the fact, means it get&#39;s established by the traction you get with your ideas in a give business context and the impact they have on the business and the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I personally believe that you cannot orchestrate or manage or create innovation. It just happens. It happens in a more darwinistic way: Through diversity/competition/mutation and selection. What you can do is to create an environment, which cherishes  diversity/creativity and competition. This will increase the likelyhood that some of your ideas turn into real innovation. In that context you probably want to set up a number of small units to shoot at the same target and want to make them compete for the best implementation. This is why open-source is innovative and/or creates innovation. It is not the a/the project that is innovative. It is the competition between the projects that creates the innovation. One good discussion on this can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreamsongs.com/IHE/IHE.html&#34;&gt;&#34;Innovation Happens Elsewhere, by Ron Goldman and Richard P. Gabriel&#34;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One other way to put more structure into the discussion is to segment innovation into ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Business Model Innovation - a new creative way to make money with something (might be closed-source or open-source)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Solution Innovation - a new creative way to solve a given (old or new) problem&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implementation Innovation - a new creative way to implement a given solution&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Open-source is clearly a good fit to drive implementation innovation. If you do not like a given implementation, you can always take the source code and make it better or even reimplement a given solution (e.g. a customer relationship management solution) or a given standard (e.g. JBI) with a new implementation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question is, if open-source and/or open-source concepts are also suitable to drive solution- and/or business-model-innovation? This leads to the next bigger question: In the past the value of a company was determined by the solutions they own. This is why pharmaceutical companies try to protect their products with patents and other means. I am not sure that will stay this way going forward. Instead we might see a world in which your solutions matter less, but your ability to detect problems and develop solutions will determine the value of your company to a much larger extend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In such a world, open-source concepts might actually be very suitable to foster innovation on the solution level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solid State Disks - Level 5 cache</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/solid-state-disks-level-5-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/solid-state-disks-level-5-cache/</guid>
      <description>Last month I had the pleasure to spend 2 hours in the car with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/pub/0/236/A97&#34;&gt;Klaus Grieger&lt;/a&gt;. Klaus and myself know each other from ObjectDesign and Versant. Right now he is a partner with CIMT AG in Germany. As always talking to him was invigorating. He is one of the most innovative people I know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The topic of the drive was the future of Solid State Disks (SSDs). His thought was/is that with the arrival of in-expensive, fast SSDs we can potentially rethink the way we structure memory and storage in general. Right now, we &#34;load&#34; executables from a &#34;disk&#34; into &#34;main memory&#34;. What if, we turn the disk into a level 5 CPU cache, means  programs never get loaded and/or started. They get installed into &#34;memory&#34; and will stay there all the time. Instructions get fetched into lower-level CPU caches on as needed basis. This would/could probably work for instructions, but not for data. Means for data you would still needs a disk with a file-system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hhhhmmmmmm, ... can somebody help me to think this through?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone - and what you can learn from thinking about it</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/05/the-iphone-and-what-you-can-learn-from-thinking-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/05/the-iphone-and-what-you-can-learn-from-thinking-about-it/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the driving range and while Alexandros was working on my early retirement plan (aka. he making lots of money with golf and I am managing his career), I was reading an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/techbeat/archives/2008/07/where_the_iphon.html&#34;&gt;article on Businessweek&lt;/a&gt; about the new iPhone 3G contracts. The article made me think again.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It made me think about two presentations that I saw recently: One by Michael Crossey from Aepona at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/Blog/2008/05/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to.html&#34;&gt;Mobile Monday in Belfast&lt;/a&gt; and the other one by Peter Moeckel from T-Labs (the R&amp;amp;D think-tank of Deutsche Telekom) at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/Blog/2008/06/2008-osgi-community-event-talking-about.html&#34;&gt;OSGi community event in Berlin&lt;/a&gt;. Both are saying the same thing: Mobile Phone Operators are struggling to maintain their value proposition in the food/value chain. More and more applications are totally provider-independent and just use the network as a bit-pipe. Even worse, customers actually have either no or a bad perception of the underlying network operator.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lets take a look at the current situation. I have a mobile phone and I am willing to spend EUR 100,-/month for that luxury (e.g. like I am willing to pay a certain amount of money for the luxury to have a dish washer). Right now and in general, there are three parties I am spending this money with:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the device/platform provider&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the network operator&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;(and to a much lesser extend) 3rd party application/service/content providers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Going to a Vodafone, O2 or T-Mobile shop is actually the wrong way around and is just a desperate attempt by the mobile phone operators to make sure that existing customers stay with them. People do not buy a &#34;contract&#34;. They buy a and/or feel loyalty for a device (e.g. the iPhone) or a platform (e.g. Palm OS, Windows Mobile). Means normally you should go to an Apple-, Nokia- or HTC-Store. Most customers have an emotional relationship with the hardware and/or the operating system that runs on it, but not with the network operator (or at least not a positive one).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When the network operators realized that people do not buy contracts, but hardware, they approached the device manufactures and said &#34;Hey Mr. Device-Manufacturer, give me 1M of your phones, make me a good price and I sell it for you&#34;. They then give away the device for a fraction of the prize to make people sign up for their contracts. The result is, that people buy devices and pay for these devices through contracts. Means today most of the money flows through the network operator,  but a certain fraction of this money (my EUR 100,-/month) ends up in the pockets of the device manufacturer. Interesting enough, right now I am spending close to nothing on 3rd party (value-add) applications/services.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the next 5 years all of this is going to change. The Mobile Phone Operators will get a lot of pressure from customers, politicians and competing technologies (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WiMAX&#34;&gt;WiMax&lt;/a&gt;) to drop their prices for voice and data services. At the same time the Mobile Phone Operators have created an acceptance in the market to spend a certain amount of money on/with the mobile phone (e.g. in my case EUR 100,-/month). In the end some customers will just to be happy to save money, but others will be willing to spend the saved money on something else.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The companies who have a good answer for the question, what this something else is, will win. Means the future of the mobile market is not in the network and/or the device. Instead the future is in mobile applications, services, solutions and content. And to enable such a market you need to provide a platform to connect the customers/consumers/users with the application/solution/content-providers. And this is what Apple is doing right now. They (and a lot of other poeple) realized that the future is in applications and content. Means they will create some applications themselves and will also provide a platform (aka. AppStore) to allow others to sell applications and content (against a fee).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I am spending a 100% of my monthly budget, buy paying my mobile phone bill. My prediction is that in 5 years from now this will drop to below 50% and that I will spend the remaining +50% on monthly subscriptions for applications, services and content. Becoming a platform- and/or application/content-provider in such a world will make you a winner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Payment - what is needed</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/mobile-payment-what-is-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/mobile-payment-what-is-needed/</guid>
      <description>in the last 4 weeks, i was talking to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/in/saileshpanchal&#34;&gt;sailesh panchal&lt;/a&gt; (Enterprise Architect - Payments at Lloyds TSB) and &lt;a href=&#34;Integration%20Engineering%20Lead%20EMEA%20North/Central&#34;&gt;hermann sauer&lt;/a&gt; (EDS - &lt;strong style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;Integration Engineering Lead EMEA North/Central&lt;/strong&gt;) about the future of mobile payment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;there is clearly a need and a benefit to find a solution, but implementations are not available yet (leaving aside lots of POCs that are out there).&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;one obvious driver is the need to find a replacement for cheque payments. cheque payments are expensive and slow, means neither banks nor customers/retailers like them, but they are still a popular means of settling bills in the UK, Ireland and other countries. in the UK the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paymentscouncil.org.uk/&#34;&gt;national payments council&lt;/a&gt; has just released the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paymentscouncil.org.uk/national_payments_plan&#34;&gt;national payments plan&lt;/a&gt;, which states that one the ambitions is to find a suitable replacement for cheque payments by 2013. a first step into that direction is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Faster_Payments_Service&#34;&gt;Faster Payment Service&lt;/a&gt; that got launched in May 2008.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;today (in Ireland) i am using cheques to pay my utility bills and my dentist. in germany i haven&#39;t used cheques in a long time. in general i am getting an invoice (e.g. from my doctor) and just pay by electronic funds transfer (EFT). in some cases (e.g. utility bills) i allow direct debit on my account and last but not least for some i have a standing order (e.g. rent). for everything else i am using cash and/or a credit card. i know that this is maybe a simplistic way to look at it, but it allows us to focus on the real nature of a cheque. what can a cheque do, that i cannot do otherwise?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a cheque allows me to give money to somebody with no bank account, means i can write a cheque and the person can go the next bank and can get cash for it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the payment can be anonymous, means even if the person has a bank account the decision might be not to use any means of EFT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;a good summary what a cheque is all about can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheque&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. the question for me is, what problem mobile payment solutions will solve. currently i cannot see, how they can possibly address the two capabilities that i described above and everything else makes them just another way to transfer money besides EFT and plastic cards. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;where is the value in mobile payment? what problems will mobile payments solutions solve? replacing cheques (probably no)? competing with ETF and plastic (probably yes, but then the question is what makes mobile payment solutions superior to EFT and plastic)?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;flockcredit&#34; style=&#34;text-align: right; color: #CCC; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;Blogged with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flock.com/blogged-with-flock&#34; style=&#34;color: #999; font-weight: bold;&#34; target=&#34;_new&#34; title=&#34;Flock Browser&#34;&gt;Flock Browser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation on Innovation - How to make elephants dance</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went out and had a pint with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/in/saileshpanchal&#34;&gt;Sailesh Panchal&lt;/a&gt;. He is an Enterprise Architect with the payments division of Lloyds TSB in London. Part of his responsibility is to foster innovation in Lloyds.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Obviously innovation needs to be directed towards a measurable goal/target/impact for the customer and/or the company. To judge, if an/the idea was just a good idea or a real innovation, you must be able to show some measurable ROI in a defined timeframe. Depending on the &#34;size&#34; of the innovation and the size of the organizations these timeframes can be easily 6 month or more. That&#39;s a long way down the road.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Question is: What kind of signposts can you create to judge ideas earlier?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We are looking for innovative ideas to foster, measure and rank (by value and relevance) innovative ideas in large enterprises. Sailesh is currently contemplating about implementing a system/culture, where the value of ideas gets rated by the number of citations that are made, means if you and your idea gets cited a lot the likelyhood that it is a good idea is high(er).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Just wondering ... communities.iona.com is implemented with Jive. We have a ranking for the number of posts a given individual creates. But there are markups that you can use to reference other docs and threads. Just wondering, if it would be possible to have a ranking for the docs and threads that get referenced the most?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Just wondering ... &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Monday in Belfast - WebServices to foster innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to-foster-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to-foster-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Monday evening I spent in &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobilemondaybelfast.org/&#34;&gt;Belfast&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilemonday.net/&#34;&gt;Mobile Monday&lt;/a&gt;, presenting on &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobilemondaybelfast.org/files/folders/may_2008/entry48.aspx&#34;&gt;&#34;How to access WebServices from the iPhone&#34;&lt;/a&gt; (pictures are available upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobilemondaybelfast.org/photos/may_2008_mobile_web_services/slideshowpro.aspx&#34;&gt;request&lt;/a&gt; :)).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Good event. We had 30 people in the room. Good format. Four short presentations with good networking before and after the talks.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My favorite presentation was &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:michael.crossey@aepona.com&#34;&gt;Michael Crossey&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aepona.com&#34;&gt;Aepona&lt;/a&gt;, talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobilemondaybelfast.org/files/folders/may_2008/entry50.aspx&#34;&gt;&#34;Exploiting Telco Asserts through Telecom WebServices&#34;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;One interesting point that he raised is that Mobile Telecom Operators are currently challenged (or even threatend) by &#34;Over the top&#34; applications (applications that use the network as a bit-pipe), which will over time marginalize the value of the operators in the value chain.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Therefore the operators have to find new innovative ways to stay relevant. And they also know, that time is of essence. And they know, that if you are in a business for a while, you develop a certain amount of a tunnel-vision. Therefore they need help. The suggested approach is to expose network capabilities as WebServices (maybe comparable to the Amazon Elastic Computing Cloud - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/browse.html?node=201590011&#34;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt;) and let other people innovate based on this set of capabilities.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;WebServices as a way to make asserts digestible for a large group of people to foster innovation. Here is a new business value for WebServices.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sensoric revolution - iPhone/Chumby integration</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/the-sensoric-revolution-iphone/chumby-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/the-sensoric-revolution-iphone/chumby-integration/</guid>
      <description>The embedded/mobile software market is growing faster than the rest of the industry. From my point of view this just the tip of the iceberg, because we are at the beginning of the &lt;b&gt;sensoric revolution&lt;/b&gt;.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Historically all data got created in the &#34;middle&#34; and we used integration technologies to distribute the data. Web 1.0 turned out to become the preferred mechanism to get this done and we changed the content/data in the middle through the web (e.g. online banking). With Web 2.0 something new is happening, because the data/content does not get created anymore in the middle. It gets created at the edges of the web and flows into the &#34;middle&#34; (e.g. mobile phones with cameras).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The next wave is going to be &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;the sensoric revolution&lt;/span&gt;, where lots of data/content will become available, but it is not going to be produced by human beings anymore. Instead devices like homes, cars, phones, toasters will produce data/content. Because they can. Because by now all of these devices contain a million (not quite) sensors to measure, what the h... is going on around them. A car is driving over a bridge and the sensors in the car detect that there is wheel-spin and that the temperature is below zero. The car will then make this data/content available and other cars going into this direction can be warned that this bridge is probably slippery. The VP Engineering at IONA Technologies is on his mountain bike going downhill and flips over. The accelerometer in his iPhone detects the stunt (and waits for one minute, if there is anymore movement :)) and notifies a selected group of people (not me) to check on him.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The sensoric revolution is coming. How do we integrate with these &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;sensoric devices&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Check out this cool &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.pepperdust.org/2008/5/19/high-performance-integration-between-iphone-and-the-chumby/&#34;&gt;iPhone/Chumby integration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Leap</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/18/quantum-leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/18/quantum-leap/</guid>
      <description>Today we went to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goireland.com/dublin/merrion-square-outdoor-art-sale-and-exhibition-attraction-exhibitions-id43220.htm&#34;&gt;local art (flee) market&lt;/a&gt;. We were looking for some paintings for our new house.  At the end we could not agree on anything, but I was in the right mindset to find something that will focus the mind, when I am at my desk.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I like innovation and I like to innovate. Sometimes this requires to take a leap of faith to produce a quantum leap. Just bought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annanielsen.com/catalogue/prints/limitededition/shortstories/quantumleap.htm&#34;&gt;Quantum Leap from Anne Nielsen&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Colossus of Rhodes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</guid>
      <description>Now. Lets get things started. Lets talk about innovation.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;for a well-known reason (at least) once a year i am in greece. this year we also went to rhodos to see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colossus_of_Rhodes&#34;&gt;colossus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;question is: was this innovation? i mean, is it innovative to come up with the idea to build something like the colossus?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;what is the nature of innovation? how is it for instance different from creativity?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;there are obviously lots of websites that offer a definition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creativity&#34;&gt;creativity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Innovation&#34;&gt;innovation. &lt;/a&gt;there are also attempts to define the &lt;a href=&#34;http://innovateonpurpose.blogspot.com/2006/05/creativity-versus-innovation.html&#34;&gt;difference between creativity and innovation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;fortunately i had one of my most trusted advisors with me and the conclusion of the discussion is, that creativity is about ideas and innovation is about results. Creativity is the at the core of innovation, but not every creative idea is also actually innovative, because innovation always serves a purpose. Innovation is directed towards a goal. It strives to improve a situation in a given context.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&#34;Creativity is thinking up new things. Innovation is doing new things.&#34; Theodore Levitt (Havard Buisness School)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;i think the colussus was a creative idea, but have him hold up the fire to find the harbour was innovative.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;next: is the iphone creative or innovative?&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
