<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gilt CIO talks ... about innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</guid>
      <description>From an interview with Steve. Too good not to turn it into a blog post ...
&#34;When people talk about innovation they are often talking about the solution to some problem. But the real source of innovation is figuring out what the right problem is to solve. Take Gilt for example: Gilt took the invite only friends &amp;amp; family sample sale invite that existed for coveted brands in cities like New York and moved that model online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dublin Innovation Festival - Talking about Innovation, Gilt and Ireland ... and Evolution and Darwinism</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I had the chance to talk about three things I care about: Innovation, Gilt and Ireland. The occasion was the Dublin Chamber of Commerce Smart Series Event on Innovation (that was the day after Dundrum Shopping Center and half of Dublin got flooded). The objective was to share a couple of thoughts on what innovation is (or is not), what Gilt is doing to foster innovation and what Ireland has to offer to companies like Gilt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure 2.0 - Building the Gilt Software Development Center in Dublin</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/04/19/adventure-2.0-building-the-gilt-software-development-center-in-dublin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/04/19/adventure-2.0-building-the-gilt-software-development-center-in-dublin/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I got a call from the Gilt Groupe in NYC and they asked, if I would be interested in joining Gilt Groupe to build a software development center in Dublin. I went to NY and met some of the brightest engineers in the industry and was totally blown away by the enthusiasm and the commitment to build and run the best e-commerce shopping experience on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Vacation - Food for thought</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/02/17/greek-vacation-food-for-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/02/17/greek-vacation-food-for-thought/</guid>
      <description>It is happening again :). I am in Greece ... on vacation. My wife has this unbelievable ability to find wonderful places for us to explore and experience the best of Greece. The (non-complete) list of breaks encompasses ... Visit the home of Zeus (Mount Olympus) (Mountain Resort Semeli)Find out how colosal the Colossus of Rhodes really was (Fashion Hotel Nikos)Take a 6 hour hike through Vikos Canyon Explore the beauty of PiliouFollow the footsteps of Leonard Cohen on Hydra (Four Seasons Hotel)Right now I am in the middle of nowhere in a place called Epohes and again .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass-customization delivered - Back to the roots ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/12/15/mass-customization-delivered-back-to-the-roots-.../</guid>
      <description>20 years ago I started my career as a Technical Project Manager/Lead Architect for EDS and was working on Bill-of-Material solutions for the Automotive Industry (e.g. Opel).
During my self-declared summer-sabbatical, I was musing over what I want to do next and felt that (if possible) I would like to work again in a business domain and (if possible) maybe (again) in manufacturing.
I am happy to report that it worked out just fine!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUSEforge Lightsaber/Lightsabre - Research on Asynchronous Distributed OSGi (for Jedi&#39;s :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/09/fuseforge-lightsaber/lightsabre-research-on-asynchronous-distributed-osgi-for-jedis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/09/fuseforge-lightsaber/lightsabre-research-on-asynchronous-distributed-osgi-for-jedis/</guid>
      <description>The Distributed OSGi spec (RFC 119) is coming along nicely, means now might be a good time to raise the head and start to think about what might come next. A couple of month ago David, Roman and myself got together and concluded to set up a research project on the alternatives available to potentially extend the Distributed OSGi spec with some asynchronous messaging concepts/capabilities.
The research is still ongoing, but the intermediate results (including a first demo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills, Innovation and the future of Ireland - Bermuda Triangle or Trinity</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Ireland (like any other country in the world right now) needs to reinvent itself. The Celtic Tiger (1.0) is over. Question is: What&#39;s next? Do we want a Celtic Tiger 2.0? If so, how should it look like? And how do we make it happen?
Chris Horn has published a couple of interesting blog entries and articles on the topic.
For me the key is skills and innovation. Skill comes in two flavors: expertise and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Innovation - Fact or Fiction</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/open-source-innovation-fact-or-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/open-source-innovation-fact-or-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Is Open Source Innovation an oxymoron? Is Open-source fostering innovation or killing it?
There are two school of thoughts out there: First, there are lots of people, who say that open-source is not fostering innovation or even killing it, because it is just about the reimplementation of already solved problems and that it actually kills innovation, because it keeps people from implementing solutions that can not be protected from being reimplemented as an open-source solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid State Disks - Level 5 cache</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/solid-state-disks-level-5-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/25/solid-state-disks-level-5-cache/</guid>
      <description>Last month I had the pleasure to spend 2 hours in the car with Klaus Grieger. Klaus and myself know each other from ObjectDesign and Versant. Right now he is a partner with CIMT AG in Germany. As always talking to him was invigorating. He is one of the most innovative people I know.
The topic of the drive was the future of Solid State Disks (SSDs). His thought was/is that with the arrival of in-expensive, fast SSDs we can potentially rethink the way we structure memory and storage in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone - and what you can learn from thinking about it</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/05/the-iphone-and-what-you-can-learn-from-thinking-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/05/the-iphone-and-what-you-can-learn-from-thinking-about-it/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the driving range and while Alexandros was working on my early retirement plan (aka. he making lots of money with golf and I am managing his career), I was reading an article on Businessweek about the new iPhone 3G contracts. The article made me think again. It made me think about two presentations that I saw recently: One by Michael Crossey from Aepona at the Mobile Monday in Belfast and the other one by Peter Moeckel from T-Labs (the R&amp;amp;D think-tank of Deutsche Telekom) at the OSGi community event in Berlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Payment - what is needed</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/mobile-payment-what-is-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/07/04/mobile-payment-what-is-needed/</guid>
      <description>in the last 4 weeks, i was talking to sailesh panchal (Enterprise Architect - Payments at Lloyds TSB) and hermann sauer (EDS - Integration Engineering Lead EMEA North/Central) about the future of mobile payment.
there is clearly a need and a benefit to find a solution, but implementations are not available yet (leaving aside lots of POCs that are out there). one obvious driver is the need to find a replacement for cheque payments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation on Innovation - How to make elephants dance</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went out and had a pint with Sailesh Panchal. He is an Enterprise Architect with the payments division of Lloyds TSB in London. Part of his responsibility is to foster innovation in Lloyds. 
Obviously innovation needs to be directed towards a measurable goal/target/impact for the customer and/or the company. To judge, if an/the idea was just a good idea or a real innovation, you must be able to show some measurable ROI in a defined timeframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Monday in Belfast - WebServices to foster innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to-foster-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/mobile-monday-in-belfast-webservices-to-foster-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Monday evening I spent in Belfast at the Mobile Monday, presenting on &#34;How to access WebServices from the iPhone&#34; (pictures are available upon request :)).
Good event. We had 30 people in the room. Good format. Four short presentations with good networking before and after the talks. 
My favorite presentation was Michael Crossey from Aepona, talking about &#34;Exploiting Telco Asserts through Telecom WebServices&#34;. 
One interesting point that he raised is that Mobile Telecom Operators are currently challenged (or even threatend) by &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sensoric revolution - iPhone/Chumby integration</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/the-sensoric-revolution-iphone/chumby-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/21/the-sensoric-revolution-iphone/chumby-integration/</guid>
      <description>The embedded/mobile software market is growing faster than the rest of the industry. From my point of view this just the tip of the iceberg, because we are at the beginning of the sensoric revolution. 
Historically all data got created in the &#34;middle&#34; and we used integration technologies to distribute the data. Web 1.0 turned out to become the preferred mechanism to get this done and we changed the content/data in the middle through the web (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Leap</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/18/quantum-leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/18/quantum-leap/</guid>
      <description>Today we went to a local art (flee) market. We were looking for some paintings for our new house. At the end we could not agree on anything, but I was in the right mindset to find something that will focus the mind, when I am at my desk.
I like innovation and I like to innovate. Sometimes this requires to take a leap of faith to produce a quantum leap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Colossus of Rhodes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</guid>
      <description>Now. Lets get things started. Lets talk about innovation. 
for a well-known reason (at least) once a year i am in greece. this year we also went to rhodos to see the colossus. 
question is: was this innovation? i mean, is it innovative to come up with the idea to build something like the colossus?
what is the nature of innovation? how is it for instance different from creativity?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>