<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/categories/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tedn.life/categories/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal Team Player - HHS vs. DAC</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/02/10/the-ideal-team-player-hhs-vs.-dac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/02/10/the-ideal-team-player-hhs-vs.-dac/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Lencioni (obviously) wrote The Five Dysfunctions of a Team.
In that book we learn that the five dysfunctions you need to avoid are &amp;hellip;
 Absence of trust — unwilling to be vulnerable within the group Fear of conflict — seeking artificial harmony over constructive passionate debate Lack of commitment — feigning buy-in for group decisions creates ambiguity throughout the organisation Avoidance of accountability — ducking the responsibility to call peers, superiors on counterproductive behaviour which sets low standards Inattention to team results — focusing on personal success, status and ego before team success  I always try to frame these in positive/actionable terms by asking people to help me to build teams that show/exhibit the following characteristics &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is better than Remote-First 1.0? Remote-First 2.0!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/07/04/what-is-better-than-remote-first-1.0-remote-first-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/07/04/what-is-better-than-remote-first-1.0-remote-first-2.0/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I got my second jab. I am fully vaccinated now. I am now in Germany to see my parents for the first time in 12 month.
Yes: It is finally happening! The pandemic (slowly, but surely) comes to an end.
Which creates (for some of us and for some companies) a big question: What&amp;rsquo;s the next step? What&amp;rsquo;s the path forward (e.g. from a organisational structure/development point of view)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distances - Know them. Manage them.</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/01/distances-know-them.-manage-them./</guid>
      <description>Building and managing remote-first organizations means that you also need to understand (and manage) distances!
To develop your ability to understand and manage distances is very important because human beings naturally need closeness (to other people and/or the purpose of the endeavor) to feel a sense of belonging.
But &amp;hellip; wait a sec: What do you mean by distances (plural)? Is there more than one?
Big surprise: Yes! When I build and run remote-first organizations I worry about and manage at least the following distances &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Summit/Hack-a-thon @ Community</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/12/the-first-summit/hack-a-thon-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/12/the-first-summit/hack-a-thon-community/</guid>
      <description>As people know &amp;hellip; I am big fan of building and maintain this balance between Product and Engineering where &amp;hellip;
Product makes sure we build the right thing and Engineering makes sure we built it right (and we help each other to do so :)) But that is only the start. The real magic happens when we get to a point where we are not building faster horses. If the conversation goes wrong it goes like this &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s a Staff Director?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/08/31/whats-a-staff-director/</guid>
      <description>Community is growing fast.
More business. More customers. More people. More money. More (necessary) complexity (software and people).
The demand for this kind of growth can create a lot of interesting strains, problems and challenges.
In situations like this it is easy to end up between a rock and a hard place: Grow fast and run a/the risk that the growing pains will kill you or end up being too slow to fully capitalize on the magnitude of the opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing Remote ... the book!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/07/discussing-remote-...-the-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/07/discussing-remote-...-the-book/</guid>
      <description>These days people look for advice and insight into how to build and run a remote-first engineering organization. And want/need to learn fast!!!
One good resource is (obviously) Remote (kind of the bible on working remote).
The book was published in 2013 (and was probably written in the 12 month before that).
Obviously the key messages/statements from the book are still true (or truer than ever), but I think that since then things have also changed and evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extreme Digital Nomad (TEDN)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/03/31/the-extreme-digital-nomad-tedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/03/31/the-extreme-digital-nomad-tedn/</guid>
      <description>In the last 25 years I have build and run multiple distributed software engineering organisations.
My management style/philosophy is based on a couple of core believes &amp;hellip;
 The Power of Why - I like to lead with Why (to make sure Talent and Passion can meet a Purpose) People first - I always think and feel that people are the solution (not the problem) Heterogenerity for the win - You have to be different to complement each other (and to create innovation) No surprises - Everybody (at all times) should be clear on what is happening and why it is happening, which leads to &amp;hellip; Building and maintain trust (and respect) (between the people) at all cost!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hub-First vs. Remote-First vs. Pod-First ... Skating to where the puck is going to be</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2019/03/01/hub-first-vs.-remote-first-vs.-pod-first-...-skating-to-where-the-puck-is-going-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2019/03/01/hub-first-vs.-remote-first-vs.-pod-first-...-skating-to-where-the-puck-is-going-to-be/</guid>
      <description>Fig 1: Skating to where the puck ...  Finding good and the right talent for an engineering organisation is as challenging as ever.
And then you need to keep engagement high and attrition low and you need to build/deliver something (with good/high velocity/efficiency/quality).
One key component to get this right is a good/the right structure for your engineering organisation.
And you probably want to structure it in a way so that it not only works today, but also in 2-3 years from now, because otherwise by the time you are done building the org it will not work (anymore)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDSE @ edx.org (with TU Delft)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/24/gdse-edx.org-with-tu-delft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/24/gdse-edx.org-with-tu-delft/</guid>
      <description>MOOCs (Massive Open Online Courses) are massive!!!
I did my first one 7 years ago (on Cousera; Martin Odersky&amp;rsquo;s course on Functional Programming with Scala).
Since then there has been an explosion of sites and offerings. By now it is clear that, if you do not know, how to use these sites to your own advantage you are putting yourself at a competitive disadvantage (from a skills development point of view).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About being a (software development) manager ... and managing energy!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/20/about-being-a-software-development-manager-...-and-managing-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/20/about-being-a-software-development-manager-...-and-managing-energy/</guid>
      <description>A lot has been written and said about what you need to do as a manager or more specifically as a manager of a software development team/group/organisation.
You need to understand people and the business and technology (software engineering processes and practices, tools and frameworks, programming languages, &amp;hellip;).
You need to be a manager and a leader. You need to be a friend and a dad (or mother) and a boss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackweeks @ Nitro ... The Why, The What, The How</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/07/29/hackweeks-nitro-...-the-why-the-what-the-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/07/29/hackweeks-nitro-...-the-why-the-what-the-how/</guid>
      <description>As already discussed: I am obsessed with building cars!!!
Not in the sense that I want/need to build cars, but in the sense that Henry Ford famously once upon a time (apparently not) said, that if he would have build what customers wanted, he would have build faster horses.
Luckily he was able to complement the input from the customers (we want faster horses) with a view of what is possible (cars).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership at Amazon ... Productive Friction 2.0</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/leadership-at-amazon-...-productive-friction-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/leadership-at-amazon-...-productive-friction-2.0/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was reading the letter that Jeff Bezo&amp;rsquo;s is writing to shareholders every year.
The obsession with fast, good decision making was and is resonating with me.
I like fast decision making processes that produce good decisions. And I like cultures and behaviors that foster environments that produce these fast, good decisions.
In the case of Amazon they have developed a set of leadership principles and behaviors (like the famous 2 pizza rule) to protect their agility and velocity, while they are scaling (and to make sure they stay a Day 1 company).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive Friction and Diversity ... the pillars of innovation ... or: How to NOT build faster horses!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/productive-friction-and-diversity-...-the-pillars-of-innovation-...-or-how-to-not-build-faster-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/12/productive-friction-and-diversity-...-the-pillars-of-innovation-...-or-how-to-not-build-faster-horses/</guid>
      <description>In the week of Jul., 10th we are going to do our next Hackweek.
The concept is not new. A lot of companies do it.
The question is: Why is it valuable?
For me the answer is: Because you want to make sure you are not building faster horses!
Henry Ford once famously said (or not said :)): &amp;ldquo;If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Operational Excellence</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/04/30/thoughts-on-operational-excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/04/30/thoughts-on-operational-excellence/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes for me discussions about Operational Excellence sound like discussions about teenager sex: Everybody is talking about it, nobody &amp;hellip;
The other day I was wondering again: What is Operational Excellence and why should you have it?
For me Operational Excellence is the ability of an organization to make (initially small and then over time bigger and bigger) promises and keep them consistently and reliably within budget (time and money).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOL ... printers suck!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/01/19/lol-...-printers-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/01/19/lol-...-printers-suck/</guid>
      <description>Last year we visited some of our customers in EMEA to get some video footage about their Nitro Experience.
 While we had our Creative Director in town (in Dublin), we also decided to shoot some material for some internal videos. Ooohhh &amp;hellip; the fun we had &amp;hellip;
 Life at Nitro: The Nitro Family Life Nitro: Our Dedication to Development Life at Nitro: Our Diversity Nitro: Our Vision for PDF Life at Nitro: Our Leaders Nitro: Our Thoughts on Printers  My favorite quote is &amp;hellip; obviously &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;Printers suck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Light ... Nitro Engineering 2017</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/12/09/spotify-light-...-nitro-engineering-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/12/09/spotify-light-...-nitro-engineering-2017/</guid>
      <description>Finding a good and maybe even the right org structure for an engineering organization is something of a dark art.
Initially everything is so easy. 5-10 engineers are in one location, have one boss, work on the one thing and have one common skill.
But then you are successful. And you hire more engineers and then you realize that to derisk the hiring and the growth you probably want to hire in more than one location and then a couple of engineers will leave, because the people management aspect of the being an engineering manager is not something that comes naturally to most of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I work for Nitro ... connecting the dots!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/11/11/why-do-i-work-for-nitro-...-connecting-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/11/11/why-do-i-work-for-nitro-...-connecting-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>We are redoing our engineering website and our blog (stay tuned).
In parallel we have worked on the Nitro Mission Statement (for 2017 and beyond) and have condensed it down to &amp;hellip;
Our VP Product has also articulated a comprehensive, 2-step, &amp;ldquo;Elon Musk&amp;rdquo;-style master plan how to get there &amp;hellip;
 Make edit, collaborate, share, sign &amp;hellip; work!!! - for everybody (personal and business (wall-to-wall)), everywhere (desktop, browser, mobile) and anytime (always-on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit the Powerscourt Gardens ... the Home of Software Gardening</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/28/visit-the-powerscourt-gardens-...-the-home-of-software-gardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/28/visit-the-powerscourt-gardens-...-the-home-of-software-gardening/</guid>
      <description>Clearly &amp;hellip; and obviously &amp;hellip; the idea of Software Gardening is not mine. But as I have already mentioned once or twice &amp;hellip; I like it a lot.
And it is also something that we have adopted here at Nitro Engineering as a guiding principle for our daily actions and daily habits.
In general software architecture is something that you cannot see or touch, but in October I had the engineering managers in Dublin and that chance was just too good to not use it, means we all hoped on a bus and went to see the real thing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero-to-Hero ... in a day</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/22/zero-to-hero-...-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/22/zero-to-hero-...-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had a good day in the office!
Nitro (like a lot of other startups) is going through growing pains. In the last 2 years we have hired a lot of people (and have not been able to retain all of them). We have build a lot of systems, platforms, features and products (and some of it turned into technical debt faster than we wanted). We implemented processes and practices (and not all of them made us more productive or faster).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about the value of immutability ... for deployment platforms and innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/11/12/talking-about-the-value-of-immutability-...-for-deployment-platforms-and-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/11/12/talking-about-the-value-of-immutability-...-for-deployment-platforms-and-innovation/</guid>
      <description>I am just back from presenting a talk at FutureStack in SFO.

Very interesting trip. Got very positive feedback on what we are doing. Did meet a lot of people with very interesting ideas (e.g. my friend Klaus (see below)). Lew&#39;s keynote on Rubicon was insightful and inspiring. Kate was talking on the art of self-management and Peter talked about how to run hundreds of Postgres databases for Heroku.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gilt CIO talks ... about innovation</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/09/24/gilt-cio-talks-...-about-innovation/</guid>
      <description>From an interview with Steve. Too good not to turn it into a blog post ...
&#34;When people talk about innovation they are often talking about the solution to some problem. But the real source of innovation is figuring out what the right problem is to solve. Take Gilt for example: Gilt took the invite only friends &amp;amp; family sample sale invite that existed for coveted brands in cities like New York and moved that model online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting GTD done - Thoughts and Tools</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/08/19/getting-gtd-done-thoughts-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>We all have a lot to do. Effective time/task management is essential. I’ve been using GTD (Getting Things Done) for a while now (a long while :)) and for me it comes down to the question, “How do you pick the next, best, most valuable thing to work on?”—basically answering the question of how to make the best use of the time you have.
Picking something from your list of urgent things to do is kind of easy, but how can you make sure you are not missing the opportunity/chance to work on something important, if you get the chance to do so?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting some KPIs ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/05/10/charting-some-kpis-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/05/10/charting-some-kpis-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of weeks I was working on an initiative to make all the Gilt Tech KPIs available in one place. There are lots of dashboard solutions available, but nothing really did what we wanted it to do or it was clumsy to use. At the end we decided to build a small Scala Play app to get what we want.
As part of that exercise we had to find a way to visualise the history of the KPI values (timestamp, value pairs) and I started to play around with charting frameworks and figured it makes sense to write up what I have found out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dublin Innovation Festival - Talking about Innovation, Gilt and Ireland ... and Evolution and Darwinism</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2011/11/24/dublin-innovation-festival-talking-about-innovation-gilt-and-ireland-...-and-evolution-and-darwinism/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I had the chance to talk about three things I care about: Innovation, Gilt and Ireland. The occasion was the Dublin Chamber of Commerce Smart Series Event on Innovation (that was the day after Dundrum Shopping Center and half of Dublin got flooded). The objective was to share a couple of thoughts on what innovation is (or is not), what Gilt is doing to foster innovation and what Ireland has to offer to companies like Gilt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy, Mastery, Purpose - ... or ... how to unleash creativity.</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2010/06/08/autonomy-mastery-purpose-...-or-...-how-to-unleash-creativity./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2010/06/08/autonomy-mastery-purpose-...-or-...-how-to-unleash-creativity./</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a short blog post. A Facebook post by Brian Kelly made me revisit the stuff that Dan Pink did and is doing.
The main idea behind Drive (RSA, TED) is that Autonomy, Mastery and Purpose unleash the creative power of individuals and teams, not material/monetary incentives. Opensource and Wikipedia and ... are obviously the classic/legendary examples for this FACT (and yes, it is a fact :)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills, Innovation and the future of Ireland - Bermuda Triangle or Trinity</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/06/07/skills-innovation-and-the-future-of-ireland-bermuda-triangle-or-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Ireland (like any other country in the world right now) needs to reinvent itself. The Celtic Tiger (1.0) is over. Question is: What&#39;s next? Do we want a Celtic Tiger 2.0? If so, how should it look like? And how do we make it happen?
Chris Horn has published a couple of interesting blog entries and articles on the topic.
For me the key is skills and innovation. Skill comes in two flavors: expertise and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Open Source for Apache Projects - Survival of the fittest</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/01/22/commercial-open-source-for-apache-projects-survival-of-the-fittest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/01/22/commercial-open-source-for-apache-projects-survival-of-the-fittest/</guid>
      <description>Just found another company offering commercial support for Apache ServiceMix and Apache ActiveMQ (like we do :)). For me this is good news. It shows that more and more people use Apache integration projects in mission-critical deployment scenarios. And that these deployments generate enough value for customers to warrant an &#34;insurance&#34; against worst-case scenarios. 
For me it was never the goal to be the only company to offer consulting, training and support for Apache integration projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Marketing - and what it got to do with the Michelin brothers</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/11/11/open-source-marketing-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-the-michelin-brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/11/11/open-source-marketing-and-what-it-got-to-do-with-the-michelin-brothers/</guid>
      <description>Open Core Licensing and the business model behind it is not (really) new. When you look at it from a history/marketing point of view there are lots of examples, where money is/was made with a &#34;handle-blade&#34; model.
From a marketing point of view the most famous example is probably Gillette. They give away the handles and make a lot of money with the blades. This works because they have a very strong brand and because they &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Business Models - Open-Core Licensing</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/09/02/open-source-business-models-open-core-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/09/02/open-source-business-models-open-core-licensing/</guid>
      <description>OH NO, please!!! YABOOSBM!!! Yet another blog entry on open-source business models :).
Ok, let&#39;s make it as short and as sweet as possible :).
This morning I was reading Matt Aslett&#39;s comment on Andrew Lampitt&#39;s blog entry on &#34;Open-Core&#34; licensing (which actually contains a link to a good presentation by MySQL chief Marten Mickos).
What I like about the approach is that it tries to take the emotion out of the discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randy Pausch - about elephants, walls, rooms and TVs</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/08/04/randy-pausch-about-elephants-walls-rooms-and-tvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/08/04/randy-pausch-about-elephants-walls-rooms-and-tvs/</guid>
      <description>Last week Randy Pausch died. With all the hype around his cancer and &#34;the last lecture&#34;, it was/is kind of hard to see who he was or what he was. Yesterday I tried to find out a little bit more and watched his presentation on time management. Good presentation, but not something that we haven&#39;t heard before. In the end I have to agree with him: He is a smart professor, but there are lots of smart professors out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation on Innovation - How to make elephants dance</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/06/05/innovation-on-innovation-how-to-make-elephants-dance/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went out and had a pint with Sailesh Panchal. He is an Enterprise Architect with the payments division of Lloyds TSB in London. Part of his responsibility is to foster innovation in Lloyds. 
Obviously innovation needs to be directed towards a measurable goal/target/impact for the customer and/or the company. To judge, if an/the idea was just a good idea or a real innovation, you must be able to show some measurable ROI in a defined timeframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Colossus of Rhodes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/04/20/the-colossus-of-rhodes/</guid>
      <description>Now. Lets get things started. Lets talk about innovation. 
for a well-known reason (at least) once a year i am in greece. this year we also went to rhodos to see the colossus. 
question is: was this innovation? i mean, is it innovative to come up with the idea to build something like the colossus?
what is the nature of innovation? how is it for instance different from creativity?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
