<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tedn.life/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDN - The most important tool ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/04/06/tedn-the-most-important-tool-.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; is the laptop? No (but more on this later)!
&amp;hellip; is the mobile phone (with good 4G coverage)? No (and again &amp;hellip; more on this later)!
&amp;hellip; is a foldable coffee mug!!!
 When you start to work remote (from home, from any place, &amp;hellip;) you will discover that you will end up in coffee shops (either because you want to (because you want/need to fight the cabin fever) or because you have to (because you want/need to find/have a WLAN connection)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The corona virus ... and it&#39;s consequences</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2020/03/30/the-corona-virus-...-and-its-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 21:36:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2020/03/30/the-corona-virus-...-and-its-consequences/</guid>
      <description>The corona virus has a lot of weird side effects.
You suddenly find time to do things that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t do (or wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do) for month!!!
In my case I just updated/refreshed my blogging infrastructure &amp;hellip;
 switching from jekyll to hugo (more capable framework; good support for Emacs org-mode) adding support for tags and categories retiring www.tritsch.org and www.innolocity.org (replacing it with tedn.life (more on that in due course))  The result is aesthetically pleasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Cookbook ... Insights into Digital Transformation and how to go about it!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/25/the-digital-cookbook-...-insights-into-digital-transformation-and-how-to-go-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/25/the-digital-cookbook-...-insights-into-digital-transformation-and-how-to-go-about-it/</guid>
      <description>Nitro&amp;rsquo;s mission statement is &amp;hellip;

And right now &amp;hellip; Digital Transformation is a very hot topic. For most of the Fortune 500 companies! And it is also a very complex topic (e.g. How to make sure that (PDF) documents can become a first class citizen in the Digital Transformation initiative).
Companies obviously want it. Either to gain a competitive advantage or at least to not put themselves at a competitive disadvantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American election ... 1 year after</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/01/21/the-american-election-...-1-year-after/</guid>
      <description>The dust has settled. All opinions have been voiced. All articles have been written. Not quite &amp;hellip; here is another one :).
I am struggling with Donald Trump and his character and his personality and his opinions. A lot!
And what do to next depend first of all on, if you believe that there is a problem or not and what that problem is. It then comes down to what to do to fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the right thing ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/03/19/do-the-right-thing-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/03/19/do-the-right-thing-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>I am driving an electric car. It is a great experience. Not to a small part, because the Irish government is trying very hard to make it a good experience. Government grants, good infrastructure, friendly people.
The other day, I noticed something that leaves room for improvement. On a Sunday afternoon, I was charging my car at the quick charger at the LUAS station in Stillorgan. The parking lot is operated by NCPS and has signs on the ground and on sign-posts to indicate that the spaces are reserved for electric vehicle (EV) charging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roland ... what&#39;s in a name</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/10/29/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/10/29/roland-...-whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>Updated: On Oct., 29th, 2016
The other day a colleague of mine pointed me to the new website/book from Jim Carrey &amp;ldquo;How Roland rolls&amp;rdquo; and while looking at it I started to think about my name: What does it mean? What is the origin? What are other well-known usages?
Here is what I found out &amp;hellip;
 Roland was a knight who fought for Charles the Great (also called the father of Europe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 4th of July!!! Or ... how to take advantage of an opportuunity!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/07/10/happy-4th-of-july-or-...-how-to-take-advantage-of-an-opportuunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/07/10/happy-4th-of-july-or-...-how-to-take-advantage-of-an-opportuunity/</guid>
      <description>A long weekend in San Francisco (Jul., 4th - Independence Day), great weather and nothing to do?
I smell opportunity! Opportunity to do something that I always wanted to do: Explore the bay area on a motor bike.
The Nitro CEO was kind enough to introduce me to Wolfgang and Wolfgang and his team helped me to get my hands on a BMW R1200 RT and off we go.
Motorcycling in San Francisco (SF) can be tricky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are we surprised? - &#34;Hot, hot, hot&#34;</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2016/02/08/why-are-we-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2016/02/08/why-are-we-surprised-hot-hot-hot/</guid>
      <description>Christina loves me. For a lot of reasons. One of them is that I have this habit of putting stuff into the microwave, heat it for 10 mins (I am exhaturating) and then try to take it out with my bare hands, while shouting (with this expression of total surprise on my face) &amp;ldquo;hot, hot, hot&amp;rdquo;.
Why am I surprised? If you put stuff into the microwave (longer than 30 secs) it is probably going to be (very) hot, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Job, New Site, ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/08/14/new-job-new-site-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/08/14/new-job-new-site-.../</guid>
      <description>Yep &amp;hellip; I got a new job and yep &amp;hellip; I got a new website.
In reverse order, first: (Given that I am a VP Infrastructure Engineering) I am currently in the process to refactor my personal infrastructure and I am consolidate most of it on GitHub and Amazon. The result is the wonderful new website you are looking at. The pages are on GitHub (pages based on Jekyll) and the domains and the DNS are hosted on Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Range anxiety? What range anxiety! (My first road trip with the BADMobile :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/05/20/range-anxiety-what-range-anxiety-my-first-road-trip-with-the-badmobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/05/20/range-anxiety-what-range-anxiety-my-first-road-trip-with-the-badmobile/</guid>
      <description>In case you are wondering ... this is the BADMobile ... (ask me, if you want :)) ...

My friend Klaus and myself have spend more time and more miles (on motorbike(s)) together than we care to count. And the pattern is that once in a while we need to do something crazy. This time around we decided that in the next 5 years we will visit all of the major road races in the UK &amp;amp; Ireland (at least) once.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>