<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SOAP on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/soap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SOAP on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 16:11:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/soap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effective Android - Using Apache CXF to access SOAP services</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2009/09/21/effective-android-using-apache-cxf-to-access-soap-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2009/09/21/effective-android-using-apache-cxf-to-access-soap-services/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I developed a small set of demos to show how to&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.tritsch.org/2008/04/apache-cxf-generates-client-side-soap.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; access SOAP services from the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;. To do this I used a very interesting feature of Apache CXF: The ability to generate a complete &lt;a href=&#34;http://cwiki.apache.org/CXF20DOC/javascript-clients.html&#34;&gt;JavaScript client-side SOAP-stack&lt;/a&gt; on the fly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I just finished an update/upgrade of this demo to show &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rolandtritsch/3601394870/&#34;&gt;that it also works with the Android Phone&lt;/a&gt;. I also ported it to maven, means installing, building and running the demo is much easier now. The source code and the maven build environment is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rolandtritsch/iPhone-Android-Apache-CXF-Soap-Services&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Enjoy :). &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache CXF vs. Axis 2 - The current state of affairs or The missing book</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/12/07/apache-cxf-vs.-axis-2-the-current-state-of-affairs-or-the-missing-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/12/07/apache-cxf-vs.-axis-2-the-current-state-of-affairs-or-the-missing-book/</guid>
      <description>(Blogging from the plane again. This time on my way to the Progress &lt;br /&gt;Sales Kickoff in Miami.)&lt;p&gt;The other day I stumbled over a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/itemis/axis2-vs-cxf-high-noon-apache-presentation/&#34;&gt;good presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.falkoriemenschneider.de/index.html&#34;&gt;Falko Riemenschneider&lt;/a&gt;. The high-level summary is ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;* Axis 2 is not as easy to use as CXF, but is more ubiquitous in the &lt;br /&gt;marketplace (and got better documentation, including a book in german)&lt;br /&gt;* CXF is a very well developed piece of software, but needs more &lt;br /&gt;people using it (and needs more/better documentation, including a book &lt;br /&gt;in any language, but preferably in english)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSE Master Class Series - Hidden Gem</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/05/23/fuse-master-class-series-hidden-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/05/23/fuse-master-class-series-hidden-gem/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I published the first 3 videos of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://open.iona.com/wiki/display/ProdInfo/FUSE+Master+Class+Series&#34;&gt;FUSE Master Class Series&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://open.iona.com&#34;&gt;open.iona.com&lt;/a&gt; wiki. Sooner or later we might link to it from the top page, but for the time being they are hidden gems :). The videos are also available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/Podcast/Podcast.html&#34;&gt;my homepage&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache-CXF generates client-side SOAP stack for the iPhone</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2008/04/13/apache-cxf-generates-client-side-soap-stack-for-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2008/04/13/apache-cxf-generates-client-side-soap-stack-for-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Yep. It was inevitable. Sooner or later we need to talk about the iPhone.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And there is a lot to talk about ...&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the innovative hardware&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the business model behind it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the market this device might be able to create&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;and a lot of other disruptive changes that come with it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;But today I just want to talk about a neat feature that I discovered in &lt;a href=&#34;http://cwiki.apache.org/CXF/&#34;&gt;Apache-CXF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In January I was looking for ways to &lt;marketing&gt;make the mobile device a first-class citizen in a distributed SOA&lt;/marketing&gt;. Right now, there are probably three platforms types that you can consider when it comes to mobile devices and the integration of mobile devices with (SOA) backend systems:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Native - means you are using a platform SDK (e.g. .Net, Symbian, iPhone SDK) and write applications directly for a given platform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;JAVA - means you are using the JAVA ME platform. Potentially/Hopefully in combination with an OSGi container.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Browser - means you are using a browser and implement your application as (AJAX-based) WebApplications (XHTML, CSS, JavaScript (with XmlHttpRequest objects).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Right now, you can develop applications for the iPhone using option 1 and 3. Option 2 is not an option, because there is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javalobby.org/java/forums/t88464.html&#34;&gt;no JVM&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone (but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoworld.com/article/08/03/07/sun-iphone-java_1.html&#34;&gt;SUN&lt;/a&gt; recently announce that this will change later in the year :)).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Option 3 got a lot of merits, but leaves you with the daunting task to write all of the JavaScript marshaling code yourself :(.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And here is where the miracle happens: The next version of Apache-CXF (2.1) has a feature that allows you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cwiki.apache.org/CXF20DOC/javascript-clients.html&#34;&gt;generate JavaScript client-side code for WebServices&lt;/a&gt;. Either from an WSDL file or from annotated JAVA source code or dynamically at runtime.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;It makes writing WebApplications for the iPhone so much easier.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I have ported some of the CXF demos to the iPhone. The podcast, the presentation and the source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://open.iona.com/wiki/display/ProdInfo/FUSE+Master+Class+Series&#34;&gt;open.iona.com&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tritsch.org/Podcast/044D9C8C-29A6-4C38-96F8-933A3F9E3335.html&#34;&gt;www.tritsch.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Check it out. Feedback welcome.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
