<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scala on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/tags/scala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scala on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:35:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/tags/scala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The AOC 2024 Retro - Finally!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2025/04/09/the-aoc-2024-retro-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2025/04/09/the-aoc-2024-retro-finally/</guid>
      <description>I am calling it! I declare my Advent of Code (AOC) for 2024 done! Finally!&#xA;Clarification: This does not mean that I did all of it, but I did what I wanted to do and was able to do to make the tree look like this &amp;hellip;&#xA;The last star that was missing was part1 of Day21 (more on this later).&#xA;This year my main focus was on refreshing my scala3 skills and to learn a lot about how AI-enabled IDEs can support a scala-engineer to write better code and to solve problems faster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About AOC, VSCode, Scala, Mill and NO_COLOR</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/12/22/about-aoc-vscode-scala-mill-and-no_color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/12/22/about-aoc-vscode-scala-mill-and-no_color/</guid>
      <description>It is this time of the year again: We are all doing the Advent of Code (AOC), right?&#xA;For me the AOC has never been about speed and solving the problems fast and the leaderboard.&#xA;For me it has always been about learning something new or getting better at something (sharpening the saw) or developing a new, better way to solve problems (also known as becoming a better sofware craftsman).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huffman Trees/Codes - Why are they different?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/11/19/huffman-trees/codes-why-are-they-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/11/19/huffman-trees/codes-why-are-they-different/</guid>
      <description>Right now I am solving the 99-scala-problems. Again!!!&#xA;This time around I am using them to learn more about what it means to be an Augmented Software Engineer (ASE). Just subscribe to the podcast to follow along.&#xA;P50 is to build a Huffman tree and to return the set of Huffman codes for the given string.&#xA;codeium found a good implementation, but struggled to find tests that worked.&#xA;I then tried various websites ([1], [2], [3], [4]) to test various strings and noticed that the trees and the resulting set of codes are different between the implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programming with Scala(3)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/02/effective-programming-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/02/effective-programming-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Just finished the brand new Effective Programming with Scala course on Coursera.&#xA;It is a beginners course and it is excellent for beginners. Good introduction to Scala and also into the basics of functional programming.&#xA;But &amp;hellip; for me the main attraction was that the course is based on (and is using) Scala3, means even if you are a seasoned Scala2 software engineer (and/or have not written Scala code in a while), this course is an excellent refresher that will allow you to grasp the essence of why/how Scala3 is different from Scala2 in the shortest possible time (I was playing the videos on 2x and was able to do all 6 weeks in 6x3=18 hours; and used the exercices to make my IDE (emacs/metals) work with Scala3).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some more fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Scala3 is here.&#xA;In my earlier post I saw some weird performance differences between Scala2 and Scala3 (RC3) and felt (obviously) compelled to run the benchmark again against 3.0.0.&#xA;And &amp;hellip; big surprise: Everything is back to normal. Scala3 is as fast as Scala2.&#xA;The big differences come from very small numbers (e.g. Day13). The biggest (reproducible) differences is on Day3(part1): 112 msecs vs. 255 msecs. If I am getting really bored one day I might take a look at it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Note: Look here for 3.0 benchmark numbers&#xA;The release of Scala3 is imminent.&#xA;In April I ported/migrated nmesos from Scala2 to Scala3 and I just did a quick benchmark to see what Scala3 is doing to my Advent-of-Code implementation from 2017.&#xA;Initially I was wondering (and maybe a little bit afraid) how difficult migrating to Scala3 will be (and what problems I will be running into).&#xA;The good news is that migrating to Scala3 is not difficult at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala 3 is ... gluten-free!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/21/scala-3-is-...-gluten-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/21/scala-3-is-...-gluten-free/</guid>
      <description>A couple of month ago I started to have stomach cramps. First it was only once week, but then it was more or less constant.&#xA;Funny enough I had to find out that (even) late(r) in life you can &amp;ldquo;become&amp;rdquo; gluten-sensitive/-intolerant. Means &amp;hellip; a couple of weeks ago I got myself tested and changed my diet (to (mostly) gluten-free) and (big surprise !!!) &amp;hellip; after 3 days I was pain free!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Elixir LDN 2019 - 3 languages in 3 minutes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2019/08/01/code-elixir-ldn-2019-3-languages-in-3-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2019/08/01/code-elixir-ldn-2019-3-languages-in-3-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was in London attending Code Elixir LDN 2019 delivering a lightening talk on 3 languages in 3 minutes &amp;hellip;&#xA;This was my first Elixir conference. We had about 100 people there. The conference was very well organized. From what I can see London is one the Elixir hotspots in Europe.&#xA;All of the talks where good, but a couple of them where of even better value to me personally (because I am the newbie) &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code ... Final cut (... and First cut :))</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/11/30/advent-of-code-...-final-cut-...-and-first-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/11/30/advent-of-code-...-final-cut-...-and-first-cut/</guid>
      <description>Today Advent of Code 2018 started again (at 05:00am (GMT))!!!&#xA;And &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; just in time &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; today I am also wrapping up Advent of Code 2017!!!&#xA;My first implementation was (obviously) in Scala.&#xA;And that one alone was interesting, because I also used ScalaCheck for property-based testing and ScalaMeter to implement performance tests for all solutions.&#xA;I then made the Scala code cross-compile with ScalaNative.&#xA;At the time I was also learning Kotlin and spend some cycles to port the code to Kotlin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2017 ... Revolutions!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/advent-of-code-2017-...-revolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/08/11/advent-of-code-2017-...-revolutions/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the Advent of Code &amp;hellip; again!!!&#xA;Last time we talked about a/the Scala implementation.&#xA;This time around I figured that I need to understand what the hype about Kotlin is all about and decided to port my Scala solutions to Kotlin.&#xA;There is a separate blog post on what I think about Kotlin, but overall it was a positive experience. I like Kotlin (but would not suggest/recommend it as a replacement for Scala).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2017 ... Reloaded!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/05/24/advent-of-code-2017-...-reloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/05/24/advent-of-code-2017-...-reloaded/</guid>
      <description>OK &amp;hellip; it took me a while, but &amp;hellip; hopefully it was worth it!!!&#xA;Last year at christmas I did the Advent of Code and &amp;hellip; really liked it!!!&#xA;If you do not know it, it is a series (25 of them) of code puzzles that need to be solved to unlock a/the christmas tree (every day (between Dec. 1st and Dec. 25th) a new/the next puzzle becomes available).&#xA;The puzzles do a lot of different things and will test your ability to come up with good/clever datastructures/algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable new hire training ... and integrating sbt-release with sbt-github-release</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/05/04/tenable-new-hire-training-...-and-integrating-sbt-release-with-sbt-github-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/05/04/tenable-new-hire-training-...-and-integrating-sbt-release-with-sbt-github-release/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was flying to the Tenable new hire training in Columbia/MD and that means &amp;hellip; 8 hours of uninterrupted coding time!!!&#xA;At the same time, I saw/found the sbt-guthub-release plugin and started to wonder, if it would be possible to combine it with the sbt-release plugin.&#xA;And while I was thinking about this I figured &amp;ldquo;what the hell&amp;rdquo;, why not creating another opinionated giter8 template to bootstrap my scala projects, means at the end I decided to spend the 8 hours on bringing a couple of things together &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assembling a Gatling (gun) ... how hard can it be?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2018/03/07/assembling-a-gatling-gun-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2018/03/07/assembling-a-gatling-gun-...-how-hard-can-it-be/</guid>
      <description>Back to the roots!!!&#xA;I am writing Gatling tests (again :)). (Obviously) I used to do this (a lot :)), when I was with Gilt (for an obvious reason :)).&#xA;To get going again, I had to make the basics work &amp;hellip; again.&#xA;The basics are: Make the sbt-gatling plugin work to build (end-to-end integration) tests/simulations and then create a &amp;ldquo;deployable&amp;rdquo; (fat) jar (using sbt-assembly).&#xA;This proved to be more difficult than I thought (because this used to work).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make your options in the future suck less!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2017/06/26/how-to-make-your-options-in-the-future-suck-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2017/06/26/how-to-make-your-options-in-the-future-suck-less/</guid>
      <description>If you are here for some advise on how to invest your money (using options), you are in the wrong place.&#xA;This is about how to use Scala Options in Scala Futures!!!&#xA;Erik Bakker delivered an excellent talk on this topic in 2015 at the ScalaDays in Amsterdam.&#xA;On Sunday morning I was on Dad-duty driving Alexandros to a paint-ball battle and ended up in coffee shop with three hours of zone time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on Android - Gradle, Ensime and the Android UI samples</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2015/01/27/scala-on-android-gradle-ensime-and-the-android-ui-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2015/01/27/scala-on-android-gradle-ensime-and-the-android-ui-samples/</guid>
      <description>Besides getting my first companion app done for my Pebble, I also spend some time on X-Mas to start porting the Android UI samples to Scala. The samples obviously use gradle. I normally use sbt to build my apps, but this time I decided to stick with gradle, because I wanted to make it easy for people to consume the code (and embracing a new build system might be too big of a step as a first step).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Mas Project 1: Pebble Hello World 2.0 - The companion edition (with Android, Scala, Macroid)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-1-pebble-hello-world-2.0-the-companion-edition-with-android-scala-macroid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/12/29/x-mas-project-1-pebble-hello-world-2.0-the-companion-edition-with-android-scala-macroid/</guid>
      <description>I love Christmas!!!&#xA;My wife turns the house into the home of all homes, I get to see my all (or at least most of) my friends and ... I get to work on special projects :).&#xA;My first special project was to extend the standard Pebble Tutorial a little bit and show how to build a simple companion app that exchanges data with the watch.&#xA;As a first step I added some text to the standard Pebble Tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala, Android and BLE, because ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/07/27/scala-android-and-ble-because-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/07/27/scala-android-and-ble-because-.../</guid>
      <description>... everything is better with bluetooth :).&#xA;Originally I was thinking to do a presentation, but Martin convinced me to turn my talk for the Scala Meetup in Dublin into a hands-on tutorial.&#xA;The main objective was to talk people through a couple of demos that can serve as starting points, so that they can start to do their own development.&#xA;We talked about, how to write, compile and run .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on the Pebble - Exploring SDK 2.0 ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/02/06/scala-on-the-pebble-exploring-sdk-2.0-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/02/06/scala-on-the-pebble-exploring-sdk-2.0-.../</guid>
      <description>... just kidding :).&#xA;Reality is ... triggered by the release of the Pebble SDK 2.0 on Feb., 3rd (iOS only, more on this later) and after more than 20 years of JVM based software development I willingful decided to write some C code again!!!&#xA;And I liked it. Mainly because of CloudPebble. As pointed out here, setting up a software development environment can be a daunting task. Not so with CloudPebble.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on Android - A start ...</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/01/28/scala-on-android-a-start-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/01/28/scala-on-android-a-start-.../</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t know what your experience is, but ...&#xA;... in my case, when I look at a new technology, one of the main (or first) hurdles is, that it takes some time to get the initial development environment up and running.&#xA;This is why I figured it probably makes sense to polish and publish something that I did a couple of month ago: Porting the basic Android tutorial to Scala.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala on a Chromebook? Yes, we can!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2014/01/22/scala-on-a-chromebook-yes-we-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2014/01/22/scala-on-a-chromebook-yes-we-can/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I got myself an Acer Chromebook and so far I am very happy with it. I use it as a tablet with a keyboard and carry it around with me a lot, but ...&#xA;... sometimes I have an hour to kill in a coffee shop and would like to do some software development (in my case and these days mainly Scala) and started to wonder, if and how this is possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To become or not to become ... a Sunday with Scala and Actors</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2013/10/07/to-become-or-not-to-become-...-a-sunday-with-scala-and-actors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2013/10/07/to-become-or-not-to-become-...-a-sunday-with-scala-and-actors/</guid>
      <description>It is Sunday, the sun is shining ... in Ireland!!! What do you do? Right: You get your laptop and finally start to get your head around the actor model in Scala.&#xA;In my case I tried to come up with a simulation for the Dining Philosophers Problem (DPP). There are implementations available, but I consolidated them and renamed the states and transitions to make it more obvious what is going on and used plantUML to come up with State Transition Diagrams (STDs) that show what is going on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Scala @ TCD ... back to the roots</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2012/11/10/teaching-scala-@-tcd-...-back-to-the-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2012/11/10/teaching-scala-@-tcd-...-back-to-the-roots/</guid>
      <description>20 years ago I used to teach object-oriented programming (based on Eiffel) at my old university in Germany.&#xA;This week I got the chance to experience a deja-vu, because earlier this year I did run into Glenn Strong who is teaching Functional Programming in TCD in Dublin and we started to develop the idea that it would be useful to add a Scala module to his Haskell based lecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A starting point for ... Apache Felix, OSGi, Scala, Sbt</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2012/09/16/a-starting-point-for-...-apache-felix-osgi-scala-sbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2012/09/16/a-starting-point-for-...-apache-felix-osgi-scala-sbt/</guid>
      <description>It is not a secret ...&#xA;I like OSGi and Scala ... and therefore it was only a question of time until I started to wonder, if there is anything that would prevent me from using OSGi from/with Scala. The short answer and the good news is ... nothing.&#xA;I just checked in my port of the original Apache Felix Tutorial to Scala. As mentioned in the README I do not want to claim that this boilerplate code, but it is a working development environment that you can use as a starting point for your own experiments.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
