<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software-Craftmanship on tedn.life</title>
    <link>http://tedn.life/categories/software-craftmanship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software-Craftmanship on tedn.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:29:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tedn.life/categories/software-craftmanship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The AOC 2024 Retro - Finally!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2025/04/09/the-aoc-2024-retro-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2025/04/09/the-aoc-2024-retro-finally/</guid>
      <description>I am calling it! I declare my Advent of Code (AOC) for 2024 done! Finally!&#xA;Clarification: This does not mean that I did all of it, but I did what I wanted to do and was able to do to make the tree look like this &amp;hellip;&#xA;The last star that was missing was part1 of Day21 (more on this later).&#xA;This year my main focus was on refreshing my scala3 skills and to learn a lot about how AI-enabled IDEs can support a scala-engineer to write better code and to solve problems faster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu, Wayland, Sway - Just mirror the screen!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2025/03/09/ubuntu-wayland-sway-just-mirror-the-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2025/03/09/ubuntu-wayland-sway-just-mirror-the-screen/</guid>
      <description>This is a good one. Let me go back to the beginning &amp;hellip;&#xA;Once upon a time there was a pandemic and during this pandemic we forgot how to do meetups.&#xA;We also (after the pandemic) updated and upgraded ourselves from Ubuntu/X11/i3 to Ubuntu/Wayland/Sway.&#xA;And the world was good. Until &amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip; I tried to do a live demo at the latest Augmented Software Engineering Meetup.&#xA;Imaging my surprise when I found out that with Ubuntu/Wayland/Sway there is no good/easy way to mirror your screen to a projector.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About AOC, VSCode, Scala, Mill and NO_COLOR</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/12/22/about-aoc-vscode-scala-mill-and-no_color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/12/22/about-aoc-vscode-scala-mill-and-no_color/</guid>
      <description>It is this time of the year again: We are all doing the Advent of Code (AOC), right?&#xA;For me the AOC has never been about speed and solving the problems fast and the leaderboard.&#xA;For me it has always been about learning something new or getting better at something (sharpening the saw) or developing a new, better way to solve problems (also known as becoming a better sofware craftsman).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huffman Trees/Codes - Why are they different?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/11/19/huffman-trees/codes-why-are-they-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/11/19/huffman-trees/codes-why-are-they-different/</guid>
      <description>Right now I am solving the 99-scala-problems. Again!!!&#xA;This time around I am using them to learn more about what it means to be an Augmented Software Engineer (ASE). Just subscribe to the podcast to follow along.&#xA;P50 is to build a Huffman tree and to return the set of Huffman codes for the given string.&#xA;codeium found a good implementation, but struggled to find tests that worked.&#xA;I then tried various websites ([1], [2], [3], [4]) to test various strings and noticed that the trees and the resulting set of codes are different between the implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Augmented Software Engineer - What is it?</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2024/10/24/the-augmented-software-engineer-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>Updated &amp;hellip;&#xA;2024-11-08: Added section at the end on published and planned episodes 2024-11-19: Added episode 3-5 2024-11-25: Added episode 6 2024-11-28: Added episode 7-10 2024-12-23: Added episode 11-13 2024-01-26: Added episode 14 2024-02-27: Added episode 15-17 I can hear you loud and clear &amp;hellip;&#xA;Ooohhh my god: Not another blog post about AI!!!&#xA;Bear with me. I will try to make reading it (or watching it) worth while your time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Software Gardening Manifesto - A copy</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2023/07/01/the-software-gardening-manifesto-a-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2023/07/01/the-software-gardening-manifesto-a-copy/</guid>
      <description>In case the Software Gardening Manifesto is down or otherwise not available, here is a copy of it &amp;hellip;&#xA;SOFTWARE GARDENING MANIFESTO Software Gardeners are professionals who perceive software development in a different way. Our goal is to spread the word of our core values, be mentors for the new developers and create software that it is developed at the highest quality bar.&#xA;Every software gardener believes and embraces the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Pair Programming - Innovation-Week Q2/2022</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2022/05/01/emacs-pair-programming-innovation-week-q2/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2022/05/01/emacs-pair-programming-innovation-week-q2/2022/</guid>
      <description>We (at Community) just had another Innovation-Week. I was actually working on generating pact-files from frontend code and then generating openapi spec files from elxir backend code and then automatically check that the frontend pact is compatible with the backend openapi spec while running the build pipeline for the frontend(s)/backend.&#xA;But this is not what this blog post is all about :).&#xA;While working on this Geoff and myself also decided that it is a good opportunity to sharpen the tools and take remote-first pair-programming to the next level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting to RabbitMQ with AMQP in Elixir</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/10/26/reconnecting-to-rabbitmq-with-amqp-in-elixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/10/26/reconnecting-to-rabbitmq-with-amqp-in-elixir/</guid>
      <description>Updated (2022-01-01): Added stage.&#xA;At Community we are building a platform that will allow you to have meaningful conversations with large audiences &amp;hellip; at scale!!!&#xA;The architectural backbone is a shared-nothing micro-services architecture, that uses an event-bus for state propagation.&#xA;To avoid any kind of 2-phase-commit shenanigans we are publishing events at-least-once (not exactly-once). That means our services need to be able to and are able to deal with dublicated events gracefully (by ignoring them).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programming with Scala(3)</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/06/02/effective-programming-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/06/02/effective-programming-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Just finished the brand new Effective Programming with Scala course on Coursera.&#xA;It is a beginners course and it is excellent for beginners. Good introduction to Scala and also into the basics of functional programming.&#xA;But &amp;hellip; for me the main attraction was that the course is based on (and is using) Scala3, means even if you are a seasoned Scala2 software engineer (and/or have not written Scala code in a while), this course is an excellent refresher that will allow you to grasp the essence of why/how Scala3 is different from Scala2 in the shortest possible time (I was playing the videos on 2x and was able to do all 6 weeks in 6x3=18 hours; and used the exercices to make my IDE (emacs/metals) work with Scala3).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some more fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/15/some-more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Scala3 is here.&#xA;In my earlier post I saw some weird performance differences between Scala2 and Scala3 (RC3) and felt (obviously) compelled to run the benchmark again against 3.0.0.&#xA;And &amp;hellip; big surprise: Everything is back to normal. Scala3 is as fast as Scala2.&#xA;The big differences come from very small numbers (e.g. Day13). The biggest (reproducible) differences is on Day3(part1): 112 msecs vs. 255 msecs. If I am getting really bored one day I might take a look at it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More fun with Scala3</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/05/01/more-fun-with-scala3/</guid>
      <description>Note: Look here for 3.0 benchmark numbers&#xA;The release of Scala3 is imminent.&#xA;In April I ported/migrated nmesos from Scala2 to Scala3 and I just did a quick benchmark to see what Scala3 is doing to my Advent-of-Code implementation from 2017.&#xA;Initially I was wondering (and maybe a little bit afraid) how difficult migrating to Scala3 will be (and what problems I will be running into).&#xA;The good news is that migrating to Scala3 is not difficult at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala 3 is ... gluten-free!!!</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2021/02/21/scala-3-is-...-gluten-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2021/02/21/scala-3-is-...-gluten-free/</guid>
      <description>A couple of month ago I started to have stomach cramps. First it was only once week, but then it was more or less constant.&#xA;Funny enough I had to find out that (even) late(r) in life you can &amp;ldquo;become&amp;rdquo; gluten-sensitive/-intolerant. Means &amp;hellip; a couple of weeks ago I got myself tested and changed my diet (to (mostly) gluten-free) and (big surprise !!!) &amp;hellip; after 3 days I was pain free!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Elixir LDN 2019 - 3 languages in 3 minutes</title>
      <link>http://tedn.life/2019/08/01/code-elixir-ldn-2019-3-languages-in-3-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://tedn.life/2019/08/01/code-elixir-ldn-2019-3-languages-in-3-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was in London attending Code Elixir LDN 2019 delivering a lightening talk on 3 languages in 3 minutes &amp;hellip;&#xA;This was my first Elixir conference. We had about 100 people there. The conference was very well organized. From what I can see London is one the Elixir hotspots in Europe.&#xA;All of the talks where good, but a couple of them where of even better value to me personally (because I am the newbie) &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
